Chapter 225: Iron Essence, Spiritual Medicines

Seeing that the situation was about to get out of hand, the skinny tall male had quickly retrieved the pair of puppet beasts into his storage pouch!

Now, seeing that the burly man had pulled out a black, junk-metal-like object in order to force him to bring out the auction items that had soared in price, he couldn’t help but roll his eyes and say impolitely:

“Everybody, please calm down! You there, we will appraise the item’s worth ourselves, but for now it is more appropriate for you to return to your seat and sit down! Otherwise, this store will assume that you are purposefully creating trouble, and we won’t be polite to you anymore!”

Upon hearing the thin, tall man’s threatening words, the burly man grew very angry at first.

In his own sect, he was a person with a great identity. When faced with this kind of annoyance, tens of thousands of people would respond to his call! He immediately raised his fists and was about to break out in anger!

However, when that person glanced at the strange figure wearing a hood on his head, he discovered that the other person was watching him like a statue; a trace of gloating flitted across his eyes, causing the burly man’s heart to quiver! After thinking better of it, he actually forcefully restrained the anger in his heart, suddenly turning around and returning to his seat.

Some cultivators who had thought that they would see an entertaining scene play out couldn’t help but feel somewhat disappointed.

The auction of the puppet beasts was going to continue! However, that black item had already been handed to the trio sitting on the sandalwood chairs. At that time, they were discussing the item in low tones. Although their exact expressions were unclear because they were wearing masks, their solemn attitude was clearly seen by all of the cultivators!

That palm-sized, black piece of foundry iron was examined thoroughly multiple times by the three figures before they finally reached a unanimous decision. Then, a black-clothed person stood up in their midst and loudly declared:

“One piece of high-quality iron essence, worth two thousand spirit stones!”

Then, that person returned to his seat without saying another word.

“Iron essence?”

The cultivators who heard these two words couldn’t help but feel shock in their hearts! The person who had wanted to call out another price immediately shut his mouth tight, unwilling to say another word!

Everybody thought with consternation, could this fellow actually be a Core Formation expert? Otherwise, where did he obtain the iron essence!

This was a magic treasure material that could only be refined by a Core Formation expert’s Dan fire. Under normal circumstances, cultivators who finished refining this ingredient would immediately assimilate it into their own magic treasures to raise its strength! They would not allow this kind of material to be easily spread out.

If even a tiny bit of this iron essence magic treasure ingredient were to be mixed into a regular magic tool, its strength would greatly increase; even raising a grade was not an impossibility! Thus, the value of this ingredient was outrageous!

The burly man from earlier, could he be a Core Formation cultivator who had purposefully suppressed his aura and pretended to be at the Foundation Establishment stage?! Low-level cultivators could not tell the depth of a Core Formation cultivator!

Just when all of the cultivators were frightened in their hearts and had many suspicions...

The skinny, tall man, under the prompting of the three people behind him, finally opened his mouth again and shouted:

“Is there anyone else who is willing to place a bid above two thousand nine hundred? If not, this pair of puppet beasts will all belong to to this brother!”

The skinny, tall man seemingly still wanted to pull the price slightly higher; thus, he purposefully uttered these words leisurely, obviously intending to stall for time.

But which cultivator in the large room still dared to randomly call out prices!

Since these people were able to attend this time’s auction, they naturally were not common characters. Either they were important figures from a cultivator clan or they had reached the Foundation Establishment stage; however, when faced with a suspected Core Formation expert, which one of them dared to ask for trouble?

In addition, even if this person was not a Core Formation cultivator, this person at least had a Core Formation expert backing him. Thus, even if one coveted the puppet beast’s secrets, there was no one who was willing to signal themselves out, so they could only stare at the treasure.

The strange person who had gone tit for tat with him from the beginning similarly sat without saying a word. Nobody knew if he had been frightened by that piece of iron essence or if he was embarrassingly short of money and simply couldn’t pull out that many spirit stones.

Upon hearing about the iron essence, Han Li also felt very shocked. That cheap master of his had lost two pieces of iron essence to Senior Eccentric Qiong. At that time, seeing his master’s depressed expression, he knew that this item was extremely precious and valuable.

Just like that, this pair of puppet beasts fell into the burly man’s hands without any further contest. When he received the puppet beasts, he was so excited that his hands shook slightly!

However, this provoked the cultivators’ recklessness even more. A large portion of them even wished that they could just seize it in order to precisely research the secrets hidden within!

After receiving the puppet beasts, the burly man wearing a cloak immediately left his seat and walked towards the stone doors, but when he reached them, he discovered that the stone doors had actually been tightly shut from the outside! He forcefully pushed on the door twice, but it did not budge an inch!

“What is the meaning of this!”

“Could it be that even though I bought an item, I’m still not allowed to leave?” The man’s tone of voice became somber; his accent, which was already somewhat strange, became even more pronounced and uncomfortable to hear.

“Of course not! When the trades finish, we will immediately open the doors and allow you to leave. However, we cannot do so right now.” The person who spoke directly at this moment was not the skinny, tall man running the auction, but rather the black-clothed person sitting on the left.

“What? What kind of reasoning is this? I want to leave this place immediately!” The man began to rage, and his voice grew increasingly loud.

“Regretfully, this truly is this store’s rule. We use some of these methods to prevent any kinds of unfortunate accidents from occurring! Sir, surely it can’t be that you can’t even wait this small amount of time!” With a low, hoarse voice, the black-clothed person on the right exclaimed in a very gloomy manner.

“Humph! Of course I can continue to wait. Do you think that I’m afraid of you? I've changed my mind. I want to see if any good items will come out next!” It was unknown what this man had thought, but he suddenly changed his attitude and swaggered back to his seat.

This caused the others to stare blankly and feel greatly shocked. What was this person thinking? Could it be that the longer this person stayed here, the more in danger he would be?

At this time, the majority of the cultivators present had already seen that this person truly was in the Foundation Establishment realm. Otherwise, how could he be content with being put into his place? However, the secret store’s representatives had seemingly known the actual situation of the burly man from the beginning and didn’t seem to have any intentions of backing down!

Since the burly man did not leave, the auction in the room continued! However, the hearts of the majority of the people did not return to the auction; there was actually the cold scene of two items in a row being auctioned without a single person calling out a bid. This caused that skinny, tall man to begin feeling incredibly awkward.

However, this auction had also neared its end. The really precious items and the climax of the auction had finally begun!

“Top-grade spiritual medicine, one thousand year-old Yellow Essence Mushrooms. I will not say any more superfluous words. Everyone here is most likely even clearer than I am about this medicinal herb’s value!”

The skinny, tall man had just finished saying this when a green jade box appeared in his hand.

Then, he put on an act and glanced at all of the cultivators; seeing that everyone’s attention had been attracted by the thousand-year-old herbal medicine, he said, secretly happy:

“This thousand year-old spirit medicine has only appeared a few times in the past hundred years; buying it to refine spiritual pills will definitely result in realm-shattering creations. It is the optimal opportunity to greatly increase one’s magic power. Thus, the base price starts from five hundred spirit stones!”

Having said this, the skinny, tall man pulled off the lid to the jade box, then picked it up and showed the medicinal herb to the cultivators.

In an instant, a thick, medicinal fragrance filled the entire large room, causing the cultivators to feel both surprised and happy!

They were surprised because they had never expected that this kind of unique treasure would appear at this auction! They were happy because if they were able to buy it and use it to refine medicine, it would be exactly like the other person had said—better than any top-grade magic tool! After all, what was being raised was one’s own magic power, instead of any kind of borrowed, external power!

Thus, after the skinny, tall man mentioned the base price, someone impatiently opened their mouth!

“A thousand spirit stones!”

As soon as one cultivator opened his mouth, the price of this spiritual herb had doubled! This caused many people who wanted to call out a price to be infuriated to the point of shouting abuse at them incessantly! However, immediately afterwards, people continued to raise the price.

“A thousand two hundred spirit stones!”

“A thousand......”

……

The people calling out prices continued one after another; in the blink of an eye, it broke through the large bottleneck of two thousand. Meanwhile, Han Li was staring at the thousand year-old spiritual medicine on the table in a trance!

When he first heard about the thousand year-old spiritual herb, he did not pay much attention to it. He only thought that a thousand-year old herb had been discovered in another location.

However, when the skinny, tall man showed off the thousand year-old Yellow Essence Mushroom in the box, Han Li immediately determined that the purported top-grade spiritual medicine was actually one of the two that he had sold to the Myriad Treasure Store earlier. This was because he had personally raised this spiritual medicine, so how could he not recognize it?

However, since the spiritual medicine was already in the hands of the Myriad Treasures Store, Han Li wouldn’t worry himself about the matter anymore! Thus, after slightly blanking out for a while, Han Li regained consciousness, watching the many cultivators fight with one another as if nothing had happened.

Hearing the rapid auctioning noises from these cultivators, Han Li felt somewhat self-satisfied in his heart!

After all, to have an item that one previously possessed cause other people to be so frantic could also be considered a source of pride!

Chapter 232: Great Development Technique

When Han Li heard the other person’s words, he didn’t actually open his mouth to say anything. Instead, he lowered his head and began to think while he tightly grasped the other person’s primordial spirit with a single hand that glowed with white light!

After a long while, Han Li lifted his head up and said coldly:

“If your primordial spirit’s invasion had taken me by surprise, would you have had mercy on me? Your magic power is much deeper than mine even though we're are both at Foundation Establishment. More likely than not, I would have been consumed by you.”

Han Li’s words were overflowing with ill intent!

“I can tell you a secret and give you an exceptional cultivation technique!” Senior Martial Brother Li was greatly frightened and began to send transmissions through his primordial spirit.

“Secret cultivation technique? Could this be the Great Development Technique of your Thousand Bamboo School?”

Han Li’s indifferent sentence immediately caused the primordial spirit’s green light to flash; in addition, it began to transmit with shock, stuttering:

“How do you know of this matter? You...... you’re the person who was snooping yesterday!”

At this time, Senior Martial Brother Lin finally realized what had happened.

“Okay, since you know that I am not clueless about your situation, you should obediently tell me everything! You wouldn’t want me to immediately destroy your primordial spirit!” Although Han Li spoke very casually, this caused Senior Martial Brother Lin’s primordial spirit to tremble in his hand.

“Didn’t Junior Martial Brother pretty much hear all that there was to say yesterday?” Senior Martial Brother Lin let out a long sigh and asked faintly.

Meanwhile, those people from the Thousand Bamboo School outside the formation, seeing that no response came after they transmitted their words through the large formation, couldn’t help but be shamed into anger; they released their puppet beasts, unleashing a new round of attacks. The large formation became lively once again, but the interior of the formation was still just as calm as before apart from some noise and aftershocks!

“Junior Martial Brother, what strange formation is this? It can actually withstand this fierce attack; it truly is unbelievable!” Senior Martial Brother Lin interjected upon seeing this scene; he purposefully acted surprised and spoke.

“Hmph, don’t worry about my formation, and don’t recklessly change the subject either. I have absolutely no interest in the internal strife of your Thousand Bamboo School. All I want to know is whether you have a portion of the Great Development Technique and if you gain any remarkable abilities as you cultivate it. If you want to purposefully stall for time, I will immediately destroy you,” Han Li said, his tone suddenly becoming cold as he knitted his eyebrows.

Next, the white light on his hand abruptly flourished, and with a gentle force of his finger, he instantly caused Senior Martial Brother Lin’s primordial spirit to cry out repeatedly that he wouldn’t dare!

“This Great Development Technique is the original secret technique created by my sect’s founding ancestor. It is a secret technique specifically used to greatly increase one’s divine sense, as well as to split one’s primordial spirit. This is also a necessary cultivation technique for our Thousand Bamboo School to cultivate in order to use the puppets; only when one has cultivated this technique can one imprint one’s divine sense on all the numerous puppets and control them with ease! Otherwise, even if I were to refine more puppets, what use would they be to me if I couldn’t control them all at once?” Senior Martial Brother Lin said unhurriedly, not daring to procrastinate after tasting Han Li’s methods.

“Since it is a basic cultivation technique of the Thousand Bamboo School, why would you still need to scheme about it? You even mentioned something about another half. What was your fight all about?” Han Li continued to ask expressionlessly.

“There’s not much to hide. Although the Great Development Technique is a foundational cultivation technique of my Thousand Bamboo School, the fundamental teachings of our school cannot be easily spread to the public. Thus, the Great Development Technique that the Thousand Bamboo School’s disciples cultivate is only the abridged version of the first layer. Although it is easy to cultivate, even after completely cultivating it, it is still far from the strength of the first layer of the actual Great Development Technique. In addition, the real manual for the Great Development Technique can only be cultivated by the high-level cultivators in the sect.“

“The people outside must have all cultivated the first two layers of the actual Great Development Technique to be able to control nearly a hundred mechanical puppets at once! Because I have cultivated the third layer of this technique, I am even better than them and can control three hundred at once. However, only the school master and his successors have the right to cultivate the Great Development Technique past the third layer!”

“During a rebellion within the Thousand Bamboo Sect, my father was plotted against by the current school master, Jin Nantian; even the entire Great Development Technique manual was forcefully taken away. I, as the young school master, was taking care of business outside of the school at the time. Because I had no way to resist the situation, I could only find a substitute to fake my death and left, hiding in the State of Yue, five thousand kilometers away. At that time, although I didn’t have the entire Great Development Technique, because I was the only son of the school master, I still knew the cultivation technique for the first four layers. Thus, I compiled it all into the first half of the Great Development Technique.

“Originally, I had wanted to spend the last years of my life here, but who knew that my breakthrough to the third layer of the Great Development Technique was just around the corner? This caused my desire for revenge to greatly rise. In a moment of confusion, I contacted a group of my loyal subordinates, asking them to steal the incantations for the final three layers for me, but who knew that my fate would turn out this way! I don’t know if they were captured after failing to steal it or if they directly betrayed me!”

Senior Martial Brother Lin spoke slowly this time and in great detail, but when he reached the end, his voice was filled with wrath and objection!

Han Li coldly watched the other person’s primordial spirit vent its anger and didn’t make any moves. When the other person had finally calmed down somewhat, he continued to interrogate without politeness:

“What exactly is the secret that you just mentioned?”

“This......? I hope that......”

“Ah! Stay your hand, I’ll speak, I’ll tell you right now!”

Senior Martial Brother Lin’s primordial spirit hesitated a little bit as if it wanted to bring up some conditions. However, Han Li didn’t even give him the opportunity to speak any further; he directly gave the other person another taste of suffering, almost shattering Senior Martial Brother Lin’s primordial spirit. This caused the other person to immediately change his tune, panic-stricken!

“If you won’t do this the easy way, we’ll do it the hard way! It’s best if you don’t raise any conditions before telling me everything that I want to hear.” Han Li’s tone was cold and bone-piercing.

Senior Martial Brother Lin had been completely shaken by Han Li’s vicious tactics; he said hurriedly with fright:

“In actuality, this secret is related to the Great Development Technique; in addition, it has been widely spread in the upper echelons of the Thousand Bamboo School. It’s only that nobody knows whether or not it’s true! However, when my father was still here, he secretly told me that there was a fifty to sixty percent chance that this secret was true!”

“I don’t know when it started, but in the upper echelons of our Thousand Bamboo School, a rumor was secretly spread that anyone who cultivated the Great Development Technique to a high enough layer could form their core much more easily than regular cultivators, and it would be easier for them to break through the bottlenecks in their cultivation. This was because the previous school master’s heir’s success rate of forming his core was extraordinarily high.” After a brief pause, he still told Han Li the secret.

“It can raise one’s chances of entering the Core Formation stage?” The originally cold-faced Han Li finally changed his expression!

“Yes; if Junior Martial Brother is willing to help me find a corpse so that I can refine and control it, I am willing to share the incantation for the first four layers with Junior Martial Brother. Afterward, we can join forces and devise a way to take the remaining layers from the son of that thief surnamed Jin. Then, we can reach Core Formation together; wouldn’t it be much faster?” He began to move his non-existent mouth again, attempting to entice Han Li.

Han Li snorted and remained silent. He lowered his head and entered deep contemplation once again, causing Senior Martial Brother Lin to instantly feel uneasy yet again!

“There is only a fifty or sixty percent chance that it can raise one’s success rate for Core Formation?” Han Li suddenly raised his head and muttered, his eyebrows tightly locked together.

“Junior Martial Brother, a fifty to sixty percent chance is already pretty good. After all, this is related to the formation of a gold core; you should at least try it!” Senior Martial Brother Lin added hastily upon seeing this. In reality, what his father had told him was not actually a fifty to sixty percent chance, but rather a thirty percent chance. As his words were leaving his mouth, the success rate had been doubled.

“Is this Great Development Technique easy to cultivate? Apart from increasing one’s divine sense, can it increase one’s cultivation base? In addition, how long has Senior Martial Brother Lin been in the Foundation Establishment stage, and how long have you been cultivating this Great Development Technique?” Han Li suddenly asked coldly, raising his eyebrows.

“Cultivating speed is decent, and it can add ever so slightly to your cultivation base......, I successfully reached Foundation Establishment over a hundred years ago; at that time, I was only twenty years old! I started cultivating the Great Development Technique after reaching Foundation Establishment. Yi, why does Junior Martial Brother ask these questions?”

Senior Martial Brother Lin had never thought that the other person would suddenly ask a train of questions. After staring blankly for a moment, he could only stammer and answer the first two questions because he had not had time to prepare his defenses. However, he answered the last two questions very clearly.

Han Li’s expression relaxed as if he were very satisfied with the other person’s responses. However, the right hand that was holding onto Senior Martial Brother Lin’s primordial spirit suddenly flashed with bright white light; then, he tightly closed his fingers! The primordial spirit in his hand only had time to let out a tragic yell before it instantly became dots of starlight, forever disappearing from this world.

“What a terrible coincidence! The thing I hate the most is being possessed by other people; this reminded me of some unpleasant things. In addition, although I am truly piqued by the Great Development Technique, it is difficult to cultivate and cannot increase one’s magic power. How could I cultivate it as my primary cultivation technique!”

“If my magic power hadn’t even been cultivated to the peak of the Foundation Establishment stage, what use would the Great Development Technique be to me even if I were to cultivate it diligently? This fellow’s natural talent was pretty good, but after cultivating this Great Development Technique for nearly a hundred years, he was still only at the peak of the third layer, and because he was distracted, his magic power hovered around that of the mid-Foundation Establishment stage. A fish and a bear’s paw, how could they be so easily linked together?[1] In addition, there is nothing strange about the Thousand Bamboo School’s previous school master being able to balance the two and form a Golden Core. Since he could become a head of a school, he definitely would possess a peerless innate talent and could be considered a one in ten thousand genius. Thus, the credibility of the claim that the Great Development Technique can increase one’s chances of forming one’s core is even lower! I am definitely not considered a genius, so I have no faith that I can cultivate both my own magic power and the Great Development Technique to any deep point!”

“The worst is that he doesn’t even possess the entire Great Development Technique; he even wants me to become an enemy of a sect school. Isn’t this just bringing about my own destruction? Even if I were to let you go, who could guarantee that you wouldn’t bear a grudge about today’s matters and use underhanded methods behind my back!”

“Please tell me, with all these reasons, how could I let you go!?” Han Li muttered to himself, looking at the right hand that had taken the life of a Foundation Establishment cultivator.

[1]. TL: A fish and a bear’s paw means you can’t have your cake and eat it too.

[Back]

Chapter 234: Restrictions and Spiritual Medicine

When Han Li heard this, he secretly said in his heart, “Sure enough, he asked about this matter!”

However, he still appeared stunned outwardly and exclaimed, “Primordial spirit? This disciple has not seen any sort of primordial spirit; could Senior Martial Brother Li’s primordial spirit have left his body before he died?”

Han Li had decided in his heart long ago that as long as the other person asked about the primordial spirit, he would insist that he didn’t know anything. Could he really tell his Martial Senior that he had extinguished the primordial spirit after it tried to possess him?

“You didn’t see it?”

The fatty gazed at Han Li for a while with an enigmatic smile; his gaze caused Han Li’s to feel unsettled, and his heart thumped repeatedly.

“Mn, since you didn’t see it, Senior Martial Brother Lin’s primordial spirit could have been lost inside the great formation and dissipated on its own!” the fatty said indifferently, his face twisting after a moment.

Hearing this, Han Li let out a sigh.

However, he was very clear in his heart that the fatty did not believe what he said, but based on Martial Senior Lei’s seemingly nonchalant attitude towards Senior Martial Brother Lin’s survival, he would not investigate too seriously.

After all, everyone knew that the first thing a cultivator’s primordial spirit would do after leaving the body was to immediately attempt to take over someone else in order to be revived; however, apart from Han Li, no other cultivators were present in the formation, so the only body that could be possessed would have been Han Li’s. Since Han Li was still fine, it could only mean that Senior Martial Brother Lin had failed to possess his body and his primordial spirit had been eliminated.

As for whether or not Han Li’s body had been appropriated by Senior Martial Brother Lin’s primordial spirit, could Senior Martial Brother Lin be controlling Han Li’s physical body?

The answer was even more obvious at a glance!

This was because possessing someone was very harmful to the primordial spirit; even if the possession was successful, there was simply no way to control someone else’s body freely without spending at least a week to recover behind closed doors. Naturally, this Martial Senior Lei could see through it.

Thus, both Han Li and Lei Wanhe were both well aware of how Senior Martial Brother Lin’s primordial spirit met his end!

However, because his initial impression of Han Li was pretty good and he was too lazy to ask about this kind of matter, this fatty allowed the topic to pass somewhat carelessly. On the other hand, Han Li, who understood clearly what was happening, still pretended to be confused because he knew that no matter what his reasons were, if this matter were to spread, he could not escape from the offense of mutilating a cultivator from the same sect. This would be very unfavorable towards him.

But in this way, Han Li actually felt that this Martial Senior Lei was much more pleasant than his own master.

“Martial Nephew’s cave is truly too crude! How can you welcome outsiders in this way? Although we cultivators aren’t too concerned with these things, it still has to be at least barely passable!” For some reason, this Martial Senior Lei didn’t leave this location after finishing up his business; instead, he stood at the entrance to Han Li’s cave and began to slowly evaluate.

Upon hearing this, Han Li bitterly laughed for a moment; he had only used a few days to leisurely construct this cave; how could he find time to be meticulous? However, Han Li thought of another matter after hearing his Martial Senior mention this.

Thus, after laughing briefly, he respectfully said to Lei Wanhe:

“Martial Nephew has a few matters that I want to ask Martial Senior Lei about. Can Martial Senior Lei come into this disciple’s cave and rest for a moment so that this disciple can slowly explain it to Martial Senior Lei? In addition, this disciple has a few mature medicinal herbs; I want to ask Martial Senior to appraise them so that this disciple can use them to refine pills with reassurance.”

“Medicinal ingredients!”

The fatty’s expression originally did not change when he heard that Han Li had some questions for him and wanted him to enter his cave. However, when Han Li mentioned that he had a few old medicinal herbs, a trace of a smile appeared on his face, and he nodded in agreement.

Thus, Han Li invited Lei Wanhe into the hollow, large entrance hall; then, he said he would go and retrieve his spiritual herbs and asked Lei Wanhe to wait for a brief moment. Afterward, he hurried into his storage room and retrieved two six or seven hundred-year-old herbs, then returned to the lobby.

Han Li didn’t carry those few spiritual medicines inside of his storage pouch with him at all times to preserve their medicinal properties over a long period of time.

Using jade boxes or other similar magic tools to store spiritual medicines was only a temporary method; over long periods of time, its medicinal strength would still slowly leach away. Thus, practically every cultivator’s cave had a secret storage room. Only in this way could one guarantee the medicinal properties of the spiritual medicine would not be lost.

However, because Han Li was worried that this Martial Senior Lei’s spiritual sense was extraordinary, thus allowing him to see the items hidden in his storage room as well as the spirit well spring, he had activated the Five Elements Reversal Formation’s spiritual sense blocking magic much earlier.

Now, if this Martial Senior Lei wanted to snoop around, he would most likely be very disappointed at this moment!

That jade slip had made it very clear that breaking off one’s spiritual sense was very simple to implement as an additional ability, so when this ability had been refined into the set of magic tools, it was similar in strength to the complete formation, not weaker than it in the slightest. This was also the only effect in which it was comparable to the complete formation.

After Han Li had set up the large formation, he had once tested the strength of this ability; as expected, his spiritual sense could only spread a few feet around him. There was simply no way for him to further increase the range of his spiritual sense.

As for this Martial Senior Lei, even though he was a Core Formation cultivator and his spiritual sense would inevitably surpass Han Li’s, he most likely would not be able to search beyond the hundred-foot-long entrance hall. This was also the reason why he dared to invite the other person in. Otherwise, the other person could use his spiritual sense to sweep both the secret storage room and the spirit well spring that he had sealed up.

He believed that this Martial Senior Lei Wanhe most likely did not harbor any ill intentions.

However, it would probably have been worse if he hadn’t invited this Martial Senior Lei into his cave at the beginning, which would only serve to increase the fatty’s suspicions. After all, if a Martial Senior were to arrive in front of a junior’s cave but wasn’t invited into the cave, it would truly be somewhat out of the ordinary.

Even if the other person were to overlook it initially, once they thought about it carefully after the fact, wouldn’t it be even more of a disaster?

In addition, there were some things that Han Li actually wanted to ask this fat Martial Senior, and he genuinely wanted to develop some connections with this person. After all, he was a Core Formation cultivator; if Han Li were to build up a positive relationship with this Martial Senior, it would be very beneficial to him in the future.

As Han Li quietly thought this to himself, he held two medicinal boxes in his hand and walked into the entrance hall. Then, in front of Lei Wanhe, he took off the covers of the boxes one by one, asking the other person to perform the so-called identification.

At this time, Lei Wanhe felt very unhappy in his heart.

This was because he had actually sent out his spiritual sense when Han Li went to retrieve the medicinal ingredients, wanting to survey and size up the extent of his cave.

This wasn’t because he had any malicious intentions; rather, it was a subconscious action that he performed as a Core Formation cultivator.

However, his spiritual sense had only left his body a distance of roughly a hundred feet before it could not continue to disperse even an inch; it felt incredibly sluggish as if five hundred kilograms had been placed on his spiritual sense!

This caused Lei Wanhe’s large face to immediately reveal an expression of shock.

It wasn’t that he had never been in circumstances where his spiritual sense was limited. He had experienced these circumstances many times in the caves of cultivators he had good relations with. This meant that there were some restrictions in place that could cut off one’s spiritual sense.

However, his friends were all Core Formation cultivators; the fact that their caves had these kinds of restrictions was not so strange. However, this Martial Nephew was clearly a Foundation Establishment cultivator, and this cave appeared to have been constructed not long ago. For this kind of restriction to appear in this cave was quite strange indeed!

Lei Wanhe did not actually connect the appearance of this restriction with the formation outside of the cave.

This was because to him, it was already very impressive for the large formation outside the cave to have such a strong defense. If it could also be manipulated to break off one’s spiritual sense, wouldn’t it be similar to the great protector formations of some small sects?

How could such a strong restrictive formation appear outside of a Foundation Establishment cultivator’s cave!

This Lei Wanhe most likely never could have imagined that Han Li’s formation was actually the simplified version of the widely known “Five Elements Reversal Formation”! Even if its magic power was only one-tenth that of the original formation, it would not be much worse than a city faction’s great formation!

Thus, when Han Li opened the medicine boxes for him to look at, the fatty’s heart was still pondering this matter. His gaze did not actually immediately go towards the contents of the box. It was as if it didn’t matter whether he looked inside the box or not!

However, when his gaze finally landed upon the two six or seven hundred-year-old medicinal herbs, his originally laid-back attitude immediately disappeared! As for restrictions and spiritual sense, he tossed these to the back of his mind.

At this time, Lei Wanhe’s eyes existed solely for these two medicinal herbs that released a very pressing Spiritual Qi!

“This disciple bought these two spiritual medicines in the secular world for quite a few spirit stones; however, Martial Nephew’s experience was too shallow, and I had no way of determining the age of the medicine, which is why I never used them. Martial Senior Lei’s arrival today is very timely; you can help Martial Nephew identify them!”

“Mn! ......”

Lei Wanhe didn’t hear what Han Li said at all! He carelessly “Mn”ed a few times before carefully picking up a spiritual medicine and scrutinizing it in detail.

Han Li secretly watched the other person’s expressions very carefully and lightly smiled in his heart. It seemed he had picked the correct spiritual medicines!

He had heard others mention that Core Formation cultivators’ need for spiritual medicine greatly surpassed that of Foundation Establishment cultivators.

After reaching the realm of Core Formation, one mustn't easily say that they wished to turn their Core into a Nascent Soul. It wasn't a matter of simply cultivating one's magic power a layer higher, it was a matter that was beyond difficult .

Thus, taking lots of medicinal pills became the common way for Core Formation cultivators to raise their magic power.

Chapter 240: Pages of a Book

Seeing that Han Li was quite discreet, Li Huayuan revealed an expression of satisfaction. Then, he reached his hand out in midair and gently grabbed at something; instantly, a red streak of cloud flew out from his hand, wrapped around a jade slip, and brought it back to his hand.

Li Huayuan didn’t even glance at it and directly handed it to Han Li; then, he used the same method to grab seven or eight items in a row before halting. At this time, Han Li was already holding a huge pile of items, too many for his eyes to take in.

“These cultivation techniques can all progress one’s magic power quickly, and they are also easy to cultivate; pick one to use as your main cultivation technique. You have to put the other ones back in their original position. When you have finished picking one out, come tell me!” Li Huayuan said to Han Li indifferently. Then, he sat down cross-legged on a prayer mat in the stone room.

Han Li felt that his eyes were seeing stars; although there weren’t many cultivation techniques, they all had their own unique attributes.

For example, one of them, the “Essence Gathering Technique”, apart from having a decent speed in increasing one’s magic power, also had the “Essence Gathering Spirit Armor”, an incredibly practical minor divine ability. When facing an enemy, in addition to the protection of a defensive magic technique, one could condense one’s magic power into spirit armor as an additional layer of protection. It could serve as a life-saving technique, and the spirit armor’s defense could also slowly increase as one progressed in the Essence Gathering Technique.

Another jade slip recorded the just-as-impressive “Mirage Spirit Art”, which also included the “Mirage Shadow” ability. One could produce an avatar exactly like oneself at any time to confuse enemies. The higher one’s cultivating layer was, the more avatars one could produce, which would confuse enemies even more.

Apart from these two kinds of cultivation techniques, the other cultivation techniques included small abilities that were extremely suited for escaping despite not being too powerful. It seemed as if the creators of these cultivation techniques were also very clear that these cultivation techniques would not allow individuals to fight fiercely against others; instead, it was more important to flee with one’s small life.

However, after Han Li had browsed through all of them once, a golden page inside a jade box jolted Han Li awake.

That was because this page’s script and size were too familiar. Han Li confirmed that it was identical to the silver page that he himself possessed![1] The only difference was that this page seemed to be thinner, and its surface did not have those strange patterns; instead, it was covered with densely packed ancient writings. But when he took a closer look, the technique that was recorded was a common magic technique, the “Essence Concentration Technique”. Its ability was also an extremely average support technique called the “Spirit Gathering Technique” and could only increase the speed at which Spiritual Qi was gathered.

Han Li studied the golden page numerous times, but doing so only increased the uncertainty in his heart. However, he also knew that even though he had a strong urge to pull out the silver page in his storage pouch and compare the two of them, now was not the time to solve this mystery.

Regardless, he had to make a decision now, otherwise he would arouse his master’s suspicions.

With this in mind, Han Li hefted this golden page in his hand and made his decision.

As such, he opened his mouth and said to Li Huayuan, who was resting with his eyes closed:

“Master, I have made a decision. I choose this cultivation technique!”

When Li Huayuan heard this, he opened his eyes. Seeing the golden page in his hand, he was slightly startled, but he didn’t say anything. He simply nodded his head and brought him out of the stone room.

The young woman had been waiting for the master-disciple pair. When she saw them return, she smiled warmly before asking:

“How is it, did you make a decision?”

“Many thanks for Madame’s concern. This disciple has already made a selection!” Han Li respectfully answered.

“Then I can be at peace!” Hearing this, the young woman smiled happily again. It was as if she cared even more about this matter than Han Li did, which surprised him.

“Alright, since you have been repaid for saving my wife, let us talk about the matter of officially accepting you under my guidance! Are you genuinely willing to enter my tutelage and officially become my disciple?” Li Huayuan suddenly asked, his expression thickening.

Han Li’s heart trembled, and he hurriedly stepped forth, knelt, and said:

“Disciple Han Li’s heart is genuine; I do not dare to have even a trace of pretense.”

Although Han Li spoke in this way, in actuality he began to mutter in his heart:

“If you genuinely take care of me, I will naturally be a hundred percent sincere and willingly be your disciple until the very end. However, if you have any bad intentions, I will not be so silly as to be manipulated by you!”

Li Huayuan naturally did not know the thoughts in Han Li’s heart. Otherwise, he would have exterminated Han Li with one hand a long time ago.

“Right, us cultivators are simple people; from today onwards, you are Li Huayuan’s official disciple. I hope that you’ll diligently cultivate in the future so that my reputation doesn’t wane.” Li Huayuan lightly smiled with a warm expression.

Han Li and Li Huayuan fulfilled the roles of a filial disciple and a compassionate master for a while, but soon after receiving Li Huayuan’s instructions, Han Li bid farewell and left.

As he was leaving the cave, he happened to run into that Eldest Martial Brother Yu. In the end, this individual insisted on sending his Junior Martial Brother out. However, how could Han Li, who had just yesterday experienced firsthand the devilish, unceasing chattering, inflict such pain upon himself? He declined profusely on the spot; in the end, the other person left with a regretful expression, and Han Li was able to escape the entanglement.

As Han Li stood upon the small boat, he couldn’t help but think about all that had happened in the past two days.

His impression of his master, Li Huayuan, was much better than it had been before, especially since his master’s attitude sharply differed from the indifference he showed during the expedition to the forbidden area. He didn’t know if it was because he had saved his master’s wife or because he had successfully established his Foundation, but now he was finally being viewed with importance by this Core Formation cultivator.

Regardless, Han Li finally felt that this trip had not been in vain; not only did he obtain a large backer in the cultivation world, he also obtained that golden page. Now, he could hope to reveal the secrets hidden in the silver page.

Even if he had no way of unraveling its mysteries, Han Li did not mind; at the very last, he would cultivate the “Essence Concentration Technique”. Although this cultivation technique didn’t have any great effects, Han Li had other ways of protecting himself, so he did not worry about this matter.

When he returned to his own cave, Han Li immediately went into his own room and hurriedly pulled out the gold and silver pages from his storage pouch, carefully comparing the two.

The silver page was still the same as the last time he studied it; Han Li placed both the silver page and the gold page in front of his eyes and superimposed the two. As expected, they were identical in size. With one glance, one could tell that they were closely linked.

Han Li took these two pages, one on the left and one on the right, weighing them individually in each hand. He judged that the silver page was slightly heavier. It seemed as if his speculation that the golden page was somewhat thinner was not incorrect; their thickness was truly different.

Han Li tilted his head and thought for a moment. Suddenly, he took only the silver page and raised it to his eye, carefully scrutinizing the strange patterns on it and stroking it with his hand incessantly.

At this time, his eyes twinkled indefinitely as if there was a very difficult problem ahead of him that he could not make a decision about.

However, an unwavering expression still appeared on Han Li’s face.

He suddenly placed the page between his two hands, then he gently rubbed his hands together. Instantly, the silver page was enveloped in a fierce flame, casting a red glow onto Han Li’s face. However, he did not care at all, instead staring at the page in the flames without blinking. At this time, the surface of the page was beginning to melt due to high temperatures,

Suddenly, Han Li’s expression changed, and then an expression of joy surfaced on his face because the silver page, now with its surface layer melted, actually revealed a golden light — sure enough, the page contained a secret.

Seeing this situation, Han Li carefully controlled the flames, not allowing the golden layer to also be damaged. However, Han Li clearly was overly worried; the newly-revealed golden page seemingly didn’t fear being roasted by the fierce flames and didn’t warp at all.

When a brand-new golden page was completely revealed, Han Li waved his hand, and the flames immediately disappeared. Then, he began to read the newly-obtained page, his heart beating like crazy.

He only read the first few words before he froze, stunned. His expression instantly became extremely unsightly.

That was because this page was actually a manual written to teach people how to control flying swords and was specifically geared towards those who cultivate sword arts; although it appeared to be extremely remarkable, it was something that Han Li simply did not need.

It seemed as if that bare-footed man from the Giant Sword Sect had cultivated the page’s contents. However, though these techniques may have been considered treasures to Qi Condensation disciples, to Han Li, who had reached the ‘Great Success’ stage of Foundation Establishment, they were only average and simply had no way of piquing his interest.

Han Li was still unwilling to give up!

He closely examined it one more time, even going so far as to use the fierce flames to burn it again, but he made no further discoveries.

The more Han Li looked at this golden page, the more he felt resentful. He had busied himself with this for the greater half of the day!

Having wasted so much time, he actually obtained such a useless item. How could he not feel extremely depressed? Han Li was especially provoked upon seeing the two words “Sword Art” because he had already cultivated an Azure Essence Sword Art; could it be that he would have to cultivate yet another sword art?

The gloomy-faced Han Li suddenly grabbed the page and threw it into midair. Immediately afterward, he used his right hand and pointed, shooting out an azure sword edge as wide as a bowl, directly hitting the page. Han Li decided to completely destroy this thing, lest he become angry just from looking at it.

Woosh. The explosion that Han Li had expected did not appear. Instead, the azure swordstreak, disappeared into page upon contact as if it had been absorbed.

“This is......” Han Li was very shocked, but immediately after, his heart stirred with anticipation.

[1]. The silver page first appeared in Chapter 213: Preparation

[Back]

Chapter 241: Three Essence Revolutions Technique

He raised his hand and cast a “Floating Technique” on the golden page that had fallen in his hand, causing it to float many feet in the air, acting as a target. He then began to use small bursts of Azure Essence sword streaks to attack it bit by bit, eagerly gazing at the page which seemed to absorb all of the sword streaks like a bottomless pit.

While doing this, Han Li had also tried to shoot an ice arrow towards it to see if that magic spell could also be absorbed. In the end, one arrow caused the page to go flying, ending Han Li's experiences with a fright. Instead, he obediently continued to shoot sword streaks into it.

Han Li’s Azure Essence sword streaks of the fourth layer should've been quite powerful, but the page had yet to respond as he was on the edge of exhaustion. Han Li bitterly complained as a result.

He truly did not know whether or not all his hard work would go to waste if he didn’t satisfy this page’s absorption of sword streaks all in one go!

Just as Han Li was conflicted about whether to proceed or stop, the page finally began to change, and the golden light on the page’s surface exploded out. The page was no longer able to absorb the sword streaks; instead, it began to reflect them, carving quite a few holes in the walls of the cave.

Han Li repressed the excitement in his heart, and he watched the page’s transformation without blinking at all.

The light on the page slowly began to retreat and converged into words of light as large as ants. The page soon became densely dotted with golden light, like the stars in the sky, causing Han Li to feel great shock!

Then, with a “patter”, the floating spell suddenly lost its effectiveness, and the golden page fell straight to the ground. Han Li, still in shock, instinctively and immediately stretched out and grabbed the golden page.

But just when Han Li’s fingers made contact with this item, it was as if the words of light had found an outlet and rushed in through that hand, fiercely channeling themselves throughout his entire body.

Han Li was greatly shocked, and the color drained from his face! He hurriedly wanted to toss aside the page, but the page forcibly stuck itself onto Han Li’s hand as if it were alive. Han Li was unable to shake it off despite his best efforts.

The transmission of the words of light was just too fast; in an instant, all of the words of light had crawled all over Han Li. Glistening words of light covered Han Li’s body from head to toe, appearing incomparably strange.

Han Li was helpless and scared witless!

Suddenly, the words of light appeared to have received a command and flocked toward his head. The countless words seeped into his brain in an instant, but because of the sudden rush, Han Li immediately held his head while screaming in pain.

If the current circumstances continued for even a bit longer, Han Li’s brain would most likely violently burst. Fortunately, the pain only lasted a short moment before the words of light all finished entering his head. Han Li then weakly fell to the ground and was unable to move in the slightest.

After no less than the quarter of an hour, Han Li regained some of his spirit and was finally barely able to stand. Although the pain inside his head had greatly alleviated, buzzing still lingered, and his nerves were stretched thin.

Han Li hurriedly climbed into the stone bed, closed his eyes, and regulated his breathing, allowing his mind to completely relax.

Han Li meditated like that for three days and three nights. Not only did all feeling of discomfort disappear from his head, but he also figured out the reason behind the overflow of words of light.

“Azure Essence Sword Art”! Furthermore, it was the complete magic art, all thirteen layers without any gaps or lost sections. It could even be cultivated all the way until the legendary Deity Transformation stage without question. These were the words that were brought forth from the words of light.

Just as Han Li started to receive this information, he was faintly shocked but his face didn’t show a shred of happiness.

This was because of the supplementary cultivation technique at the very end, the “Three Essence Revolutions Technique”. At first, this piqued Han Li’s interest, so he looked through it as he wished.

After browsing the first few passages, he blankly stared for a moment. He believed that he had misunderstood, but after he read through that part several more times, he was convinced that he was not mistaken, causing Han Li to enter a state of raging ecstasy.

This “Three Essence Revolutions Technique” actually possessed the miraculous, heaven-shaking effect of evading the Core Formation stage bottleneck! This information seemed like a voice from the Heavens, causing Han Li to believe that it was a dream.

Ever since he entered the world of cultivation, nearly every cultivator had talked about the problems of Core Formation. Everyone had sighed and shook their heads! All have said that breaking through to Core Formation was basically reliant on one’s luck. It was a matter completely decided by the Heavens! Naturally, those with excellent aptitude had already cultivated to the peak of Foundation Establishment and possessed the qualifications for Core Formation. In addition, those possessing heavenly spiritual roots naturally did not have any problems in this area.

To be blunt, Han Li’s confidence in achieving Core Formation was almost nil! With great difficulty, he spent all his life trying to find a way, so at this point, he was truly reluctant to give up! But despite this, Han Li was unwilling to so passively renounce the pursuit of eternal life merely because it was difficult. Even as hopeless as it was, his thirst for Core Formation and his will to struggle only grew stronger!

But now, a straight path to Core Formation appeared before him, allowing him to bypass the bottleneck. How could Han Li not be in ecstasy?

But regardless of Han Li’s excitement, this cultivation art couldn’t be considered a shortcut. In fact, it was completely unverified.

The expert who created this cultivation technique and the Azure Essence Sword Art had long since reached Core Formation when he created these techniques, which he based on an insane idea about Core Formation! He stated at the very end of the cultivation technique that even if one completely followed the cultivation technique and fulfilled all that was required, the odds of immediate formation of a core was only one half!

However, this was enough for Han Li! Even if one were to say only one in ten instead of one in two odds, it would be enough for Han Li to pursue it without hesitation.

But after Han Li’s moment of ecstasy, he carefully analyzed the cultivation technique, and what he found decimated his hopes. Even if Han Li were a person with strong aspirations, he could not help but appear to have taken a direct blow, his face increasingly pale.

Those cultivating the Three Essence Revolutions Technique obviously needed to first cultivate the Azure Essence Sword Art since this technique was originally founded on its basis. Although the Azure Essence Sword Art was extraordinarily difficult to practice, that was not the most important point. What caused Han Li’s face to become unsightly was due to the meaning behind the technique’s name. The individual must first cultivate to the sixth layer of the Azure Essence Sword Art then disperse their sword art cultivation, after which they must cultivate all over again.

According to its founder, only like this would someone be able to use the “Three Essence Revolutions Technique”. By repeating cultivating his magic power, his true essence would able to further compress and have his magic power become several times more pure. After doing this three times in succession and cultivating back to the peak of Foundation Establishment, he would be able to form a core in his Dantian with ease.

According to this expert’s conjectures, a Gold Core was originally created by solidifying one’s true essence and condensing it. If the true essence was already solidified, forming a core would naturally be effortless!

Even if Han Li felt that what this expert said was reasonable, he was truly hesitant to foolishly disperse his own cultivation.

This wasn’t because Han Li was scared of the hardship of regaining his lost cultivation but rather because he wasn’t confident that he would be able to cultivate three times within his lifespan.

Even if he had the assistance of the small mysterious bottle, this was a matter of extreme risk! After all, according to the expert’s plan, it would take longer and longer to cultivate as he would need to condense and compress his true essence more each time.

The great benefits of doing this were, without a doubt, extremely great. It would allow him to have true essence and magic power several times greater than that of common cultivators, but at the same time, he would certainly be required to spend more time than common cultivators.

With a trifling two hundred years of life, would he be able to do all of this? Han Li truly did not know!

After a moment of indecision, Han Li looked toward the golden page that he received from Li Huayuan. Only after an inspection of what it contained would he be able to come to a decision.

As a result, an equivalent sword stream entered the gold page and was rewarded with an equivalent headache. Han Li experienced it once more, accepting the contents of the other gold page.

“Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Sword!” This was what entered in Han Li’s mind.

Han Li became extremely interested and patiently arranged the words of light before pouring through it.

It turned out that inside the gold page were actually instructions for how to refine a Core Formation flying sword magic treasure called “Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Sword”. This wood attribute flying sword was actually quite similar to Han Li’s “Gold Beetle Swarm Blades” as it was refined as a set of magic treasures.

At least twelve wood attribute flying swords were required to form a set. It was quite strange. Naturally, if he were able to collect enough materials and had enough true essence, he could theoretically refine thirty-six or even seventy-two as a set.

Chapter 242: Making Talismans

Han Li carefully put away for the two golden book pages and planned his future actions meticulously.

Since he wanted to cultivate the Three Essence Revolutions Technique, the small mysterious bottle’s green liquid must be used to its full extent. Thus, he quickly gathered together the materials for the two ancient formulas. If it could be bought, it was bought; he let nothing slip away.

With this said, apart from spiritual power, the green liquid also had other components, but they still remained a complete mystery to him. There was no way that Spiritual Qi by itself was able to miraculously mature plants.

After entering Yellow Maple Valley, he had researched it several times. regardless of how diluted the spiritual liquid was, with just a tiny drop of green liquid mixed with water, all the animals that tasted it had similarly exploded. It wasn’t a matter of how diluted the green liquid was but rather its unknown components running rampant.

After receiving several similar results, Han Li was forced to begrudgingly give up.

But using the mysterious small bottle to simply refine pills was a bit narrow! Han Li felt that using its wondrous effects to mature plants had many more uses; to use it just for pills seemed wasteful.

After a moment of consideration, Han Li felt that with Foundation Establishment battles, apart from magic tools and cultivation techniques, mid-grade or higher talismans were an absolute necessity. However, these mid-grade talismans were extremely expensive! A single talisman often cost several tens of spirit stones. Han Li could only shake his head repeatedly!

A good number of these mid or higher grade Five Elements talismans had truly great power. They could take the place of incisive Daoist magics, capable of saving one’s life.

If a magic technique’s grade was too high, then even if a Foundation Establishment cultivator were to use it, it would require no small amount of magic power and time. As such, purchasing a few of these talismans was essential as a life-preserving last resort.

Thus, Han Li decided to refine talismans, actual mid-grade talismans.

Because refining talismans required blank talisman paper refined from spirit herbs of a certain maturity, Han Li wanted to bring out the bottle and make full use of its wondrous effects.

Naturally, high-grade talismans couldn’t be made with this method. Those required spirit hides of a few particular demonic beasts, and Han Li was currently not capable of acquiring such hides.

As for the cinnabar used to refine talismans, there was no need to be picky since most of the supply was refined from the blood of a few spirit beast species, the majority being extracted from domesticated spirit beasts. It fundamentally wasn’t worth much.

One had to be somewhat selective with the talisman brushes used to make talismans. However, Han Li already had the Golden Sincerity Brush, which should suit his needs.

When Han Li thought of the Golden Sincerity Brush, he naturally thought of that young, easily embarrassed Han Yunzhi and couldn’t help but slightly smile. At this moment, she was probably at Spirit Beast Mountain!

But in the blink of an eye, Han Li regained his focus and once again pondered about the feasibility and risks of refining talismans.

He had the tools and an unending supply of materials. The fundamental problem of a talisman-refinement expert, having enough materials, was no problem for him. Currently, the only restriction he had was his cultivation of mid-grade and higher Daoist magics.

Talisman-refinement experts must first be able to use a magic technique before refining it onto a talisman. Otherwise, there would be nothing to inscribe onto the talisman paper. After all, talismans were only a method of sealing a magic technique in advance.

When he thought of having to cultivate mid-grade magic techniques, Han Li felt a pounding headache!

He didn’t know whether it had to do with his spiritual roots, but when he practiced Daoist magics of the Five Elements, he felt that his talent was extremely lacking. Even after spending several times more effort and time than other cultivators, he wouldn’t make the slightest of gains and remained completely ignorant of the magic’s essence!

However, after he entered Foundation Establishment, he was able to easily learn those few elementary magic techniques. Furthermore, he was proficient enough to perform most of them in the blink of an eye. But for mid-grade magic techniques, it was the same as before. He could only look up to the sky and sigh!

Han Li knew that if he arduously cultivated a few mid-grade magic techniques, he would most likely be able to seal and imprint a few talismans. He had no extravagant hopes of being able to refine all of the mid-grade magic techniques he wished.

With a great amount of mid-grade talismans, not only would he have a great advantage in battle, but he could also sell them openly without arousing the suspicion of others.

Thus, Han Li was freed from the plight of lacking spiritual stones. He currently didn’t dare to conspicuously take out spiritual herbs to trade for spirit stones!

Furthermore, Han Li had further thoughts. If his cultivation truly scattered and he had to cultivate back what he lost, during that time, he would unquestionably be at his weakest. If an enemy or someone with a grudge found him, how wouldn’t he be in great danger!? After all, the world of cultivation wasn’t some peaceful world; anything could happen.

But if he had a lot of talismans on hand, he would be able to preserve a certain amount of strength. Even if he couldn’t subdue an enemy with the assistance of talismans, he could most likely escape with them.

Although learning how to refine talismans would surely interfere with the advancement of his magic power, regardless of how he saw it, it would only take up some of his time. The gains were greater than the losses!

After Han Li tossed and turned several times in his chambers, he decided to simultaneously cultivate the Azure Essence Sword Art and practice talisman-refinement. Having made his decision after much deliberation, Han Li immediately set into motion.

During the next few days, he made two trips to his own sect’s market city as well as the Heavenly Star Sect’s market city to look for seeds and sprouts of spiritual herbs used in talisman paper refinement.

The materials written in the ancient pill formulas were naturally extremely rare and priceless materials. Fortunately, Han Li didn’t have any problems with the maturity of these medicinal herbs and was fortunate enough to gather enough materials for the “Qi Refining Powder”, causing him to be overjoyed.

As for the materials for the talisman paper, because he was starting with low grade-talismans, they were easily required. Of course, a large amount of cinnabar was indispensable.

After three or four days, Han Li created an opening in his great formation outside his Immortal’s cave and entered it, closing it behind him. Then he entered secluded cultivation for his first time after reaching Foundation Establishment.

……

Time does not stop for cultivation. Four years passed in the blink of an eye. Underneath the concealment of the formation spell, the cave’s entrance had been tightly closed since that day and hadn’t been opened since.

Then one day, a blue streak of light suddenly flew from the distant horizon. After it circled several times around the great formation, it turned into a chuckling Confucian Scholar holding a blue wooden board in his hand.

“So this is young Junior Martial Brother’s Immortal’s cave! Why did you pick such a remote place? Furthermore, the Spiritual Qi also isn’t very abundant. If Martial Senior Lei hadn’t given me a few directions, it would have truly been hard to find!” The Confucian Scholar muttered to himself with an expression of surprise.

Soon after, the Confucian Scholar sized up the great formation outside the Immortal’s cave, suddenly displaying a desire to test it out.

“Martial Senior Lei said this young Junior Martial Brother’s great defensive formation was incomparably ferocious and that if a Core Formation Cultivator were to come, they wouldn’t necessarily be able to break through. This must truly be false. How could it possibly be so ferocious? Should I give it a try?”

But after a bit of consideration, the Confucian Scholar dejectedly hung his head and said to himself, “Forget about it. This will interfere with Master’s plans!”

With that said, he took out a sound transmission talisman and looked at Han Li’s great formation. The sound transmission talisman suddenly turned into a streak of fiery light and silently entered the formation.

Then the Confucian Scholar immediately threw the wooden board in his hand into the air and left, flying away on his flying magic tool.

At this moment, in the secluded room with the spirit well spring, Han Li was meditating with his eyes closed.

His appearance was actually exactly the same as four years ago, without the slightest of change. However, his body was enveloped in a layer of faint azure light that continuously flickered, appearing as if it were an exceptionally beautiful illusion.

But if someone were to look at around, they would be beyond speechless. That was because there were talismans of all grades scattered around Han Li, from the elementary low-grade “Fireball” and “Ice Arrow” techniques to the elementary high-grade techniques “Earth Wall” and “Fire Cloud” and more. It seemed as if this were a large storehouse for talismans. In addition, there were a few empty boxes of cinnabar as well as stacks of blank talisman paper scattered about, appearing extremely messy.

Not knowing how much time had passed, Han Li wrinkled his brow in response to something and opened his eyes.

After a moment of thought, he suddenly stood and walked out of the seclusion chamber. As soon as he stood, all of the talismans and other items on the floor silently entered his storage pouch. His room instantly became spotless.

As he walked out of the seclusion chamber, Han Li waved his hand, and a small yellow flag appeared in it. Then he threw it out, turning the small flag into a streak of yellow light that flew outwards.

Before Han Li could finish walking to his bedroom, the small flag that had turned into a yellow light returned with a streak of fiery light in tow.

When Han Li saw this, he calmly moved his hand and summoned the small flag into it. He opened his other hand and shot out azure light toward the fiery light before him.

Chapter 246: Dong Xuan’er

This Martial Aunt Hong Fu brought the young woman to the back room and had her examine the flawless arm of the deeply blushing Dong Xuan’er. The gecko cinnabar[1] on it revealed that her chastity was shown to actually be intact. This caused Han Li’s Master’s Wife to be greatly shocked!

From the appearance of her flirtatious behavior, how could this Dong Xuan’er possibility not have had intercourse! On the day that the couple tried to renege on the matter of pair cultivation, they had pretended to not know of the rumors and remained ambiguous.

However, they completely didn’t expect that the girl’s reputation had long been common knowledge. This very matter was what drove the couple to renege on their agreement for the sake of their reputation.

While the young woman was astonished, Hong Fu explained to her. Because her disciple desired the wondrous effect of preserving her appearance, she had first cultivated the top-grade magic technique she had on hand, the “Spring Transformation Art”,[2] which altered the bearing of her appearance though cultivation. A few cultivators with women essence identification techniques had seen Dong Xuan’er and assumed she had already lost her virginity, giving birth to many unflattering rumors.

It was without a doubt that this disciple truly did not care much for her own reputation and actually had a rather familiar relationship with many male cultivators. However, because of the seductive effect of the Spring Transformation Arts along with her extraordinary status, to have no illicit affairs with any of the male cultivators who were circling around her was a truly remarkable and unexpected matter.

However, the male cultivators who stayed by her side grew more numerous as Dong Xuan’er gradually formed a habit of shooting flirty looks at young men, immediately planting the strange notion that she wanted them to get underneath her skirt. This even went far enough as to cause discord between a few men, all rivals for her affection!

Fortunately, as a prerequisite for Hong Fu allowing this girl to cultivating the Spring Transformation Art, she was not allowed to throw away her chastity. If she didn’t find any trace of the gecko cinnabar, Master Hong Fu would have immediately dispersed her magic power and would have forced her to live on as a mortal. This was to prevent Dong Xuan’er, who had bewitchment techniques from cultivating the Spring Transformation Art, from ruining the principles of the Dong Clan.

Underneath very restrictive conditions, although Dong Xuan’er had often sent flirting glances at these young men, she hadn’t dared to step too far out of line!

However, these small antics slowly reached Hong Fu’s ears and caused this female Core Formation cultivator to become furious. She firmly punished Dong Xuan’er and immediately confined her in a restrictive formation for a period of time.

But it was already too late, and Dong Xuan’er terrible reputation had already spread throughout Yellow Maple Valley. This rumor had quickly spread and was fundamentally impossible to stifle. Even the Core Formation cultivator Hong Fu was unable to do anything about this!

Currently, even if those cultivators who knew of her reputation found out that Dong Xuan’er had truly remained chaste, they wouldn’t dare to become pair cultivation companions for the sake of preserving their own reputation.

However, she had reached a stage of cultivation for Spring Transformation where she was required to pair cultivate in order to progress her magic power, else it would regress.

As for those cultivators who still sought Dong Xuan’er, Hong Fu did not find any that satisfied her, finding faults in their moral character and lewd attempts. But eventually she made a trip to Li Huayuan’s Immortal’s cave and chose Han Li.

Having heard all of this, the young woman wore a very embarrassed expression and returned to Li Huayuan’s side. After she told her husband, they both remained silent for a good amount of time.

Although the couple had truly mistaken Dong Xuan’er’s purity, it was as Hong Fu had said. Even if she had remained truly chaste, her reputation was truly spoiled, preventing Li Huayuan from willingly allowing his own disciple from being pair cultivation companions with her since the damage to his own reputation would be far too great. Thus he could only feel guilt toward this Martial Aunt Hong Fu.

In order to make up for his guilt toward Hong Fu, Li Huayuan naturally didn’t obstruct Han Li’s trip to the Treasure Seizing Assembly in the slightest. Instead, he spared no effort to facilitate this long trip for Han Li and Dong Xuan’er.

In Li Huayuan’s mind, with regards toward Han Li’s terrible impression toward Dong Xuan’er, this long trip would change nothing. In truth, ever since his seventh disciple Wu Xuan had first seen Dong Xuan’er, that girl had constantly remained in his mind. Several days before, he had actually summoned to courage to ask Li Huayuan whether or not he could raise the issue to Hong Fu to see if she would reconsider Wu Xuan.

Naturally, Li Huayuan couldn’t agree to such an absurd action. After fiercely rebuking this disciple, he sent the disciple out to handle external affairs to avoid having Wu Xuan stir up trouble within the mountain.

After the strict scolding, Wu Xuan became much more obedient and obeyed orders to handle matters, but Li Huayuan was still clearly able to feel this disciple’s wily thoughts were still present He couldn’t help but sense an oncoming headache.

After seeing off the two young cultivators, Female Immortal Hong Fu chatted with the husband and wife a bit more before departing. Li Huayuan and the young woman entered Green Ripple Cave and started their daily cultivation as the matter of Han Li and Dong Xuan’er had been set aside for the time being.

……

The number one clan of the State of Yue, the Yan Clan, had its foundation in the unremarkable Lin Province. Not only was the area of this province ordinary, but the population was also of an average number. It could be said to be a completely ordinary land.

Qing Liang Town was a common small town of the Lin Province. Were it not for the exceptional scenery of Yan Liang Mountian, there wasn’t anything that the population could have said to distinguish this place from any other. The Yan Clan’s most important location, Yan Ling Castle, was located within Yan Liang Mountain.

Currently, Han Li held a sheet of paper in his hand. This was the invitation letter to the Treasure Seizing Assembly. The location of the assembly’s meeting place was written on it, Yan Ling Castle.

After taking another look at the invitation letter and seeing that he wasn’t mistaken, Han Li calmly put it away. Then he heard mocking words of ridicule from the girl at his side.

“You really are a blockhead! You actually read the invitation letter five or six times through and still don’t feel ease. You truly have no small amount of shortcomings!”

This young woman’s voice was very soft, yet it contained a deep allure. It was very capable of charming males and would even drive younger men wilder.

However, Han Li’s expression didn’t change in the slightest; it was as if he hadn’t heard her. He unexpectedly raised his hand and shot three bowl-sized fireballs to the sky, erupting when they were high enough. He then insipidly said, “If the Yan Clan still doesn’t send people to us after another moment, then we will leave and wait until tomorrow. Junior Martial Sister, since you have enough energy to quarrel, you may as well keep an eye out at a higher area and see if there is anyone else nearby just in case.“

“Senior Martial Brother Han’s guts are truly very small! We are at the entrance of the Yan Clan and you still believe there are any dangers? I see that you are a completely foolish and paranoid person!” Dong Xuan’er slanted her red lips and lazily said this. She leaned against a pine tree without the slightest intent of obeying.

At this moment, Han Li and the young woman stood at the peak of a somewhat small mountain, waiting for something to happen.

This was where the invitation letter indicated they would pick up guests. However, the two had arrived a while ago but they still hadn’t seen anyone from the Yan Clan. Han Li couldn’t help but grow greatly alert for fear there would be some mishap.

However, this little “princess” Dong viewed Han Li’s cautiousness with contempt, believing Han Li was merely cowardly!

It has already been seven or eight days since they left Green Ripple Cave.

But on the journey, perhaps due to having inharmonious dispositions, the two found each other rather displeasing to the eye. A man and a woman would have some have feelings toward each other during such a long journey, but with them, not the slightest feeling had developed.

Dong Xuan’er did not know why her bewitching flirts that had charmed hundreds of male cultivators hadn’t the slightest effect on Han Li. Because of her wicked disposition, not long after she failed to control Han Li, she burst out, releasing a great temper.

However, Han Li didn’t pay attention to the young girl and fundamentally ignored her rudeness. He only uttered one sentence: I can tell Martial Aunt Hong Fu the exact words you just said. This immediately stifled Dong Xuan’er.

Although the young woman was accustomed to being spoiled with affection, she knew that Hong Fu was truly furious regarding her own reputation.

She truly took to heart the warning she was given when she had departed! If the loathable man before her truly told her master a few unpleasant words, heavy criticism would be unavoidable. Even locking her up again wouldn’t be out of the question.

Recalling her last period of confinement, Dong Xuan’er couldn’t help but shiver. Although she wasn’t willing to be completely subdued, she didn’t dare to act as recklessly as before.

However, Han Li didn’t make it too difficult for her, even allowing the girl to have cheap victories in verbal exchanges, not caring in the least. But if Dong Xuan’er was the slightest bit excessive, he would bluntly bring up Martial Senior Hong Fu, immediately rigidly suppressing Dong Xuan’er without the slightest leeway. After all, before departure, Hong Fu had spoken to the two, allowing Han Li to hear her stern warning.

On the journey, as this girl eloquently mocked and taunted him without end, as if he hadn’t heard her words, Han Li only hurried on the journey. But when he insipidly mentioned Hong Fu’s words, the originally eloquent Xuan’er’s expression greatly changed, and she didn’t dare to be so impudent.

Thus, the two hurried on their journey as they clashed during the day and slept during the night. Several days later, they eventually reached the peak of Yan Liang Mountain.

However, they were greeted by unexpected silence. The people from the Yan Clan should have already appeared, but the two of them have had the to wait for over half a day, causing them to be a bit impatient.

[1]. TL: Gecko cinnabar supposedly tells if you’re a virgin.

[Back]

[2]. TL: the Spring 春 in Spring Transformation Art can also mean joy, lust, and youth

[Back]

Chapter 252: Separation

“Do you know a bit about the details of this person’s cultivation? If he isn’t an important disciple or the Yan Clan and his cultivation isn’t high, I can go have a chat with him and should be able to smoothly resolve this,” Han Li calmly said as he rubbed his nose.

In fact, he clearly understood that being able to force a mortal girl required a high enough cultivation. Thus, he could only be a bit careful about this.

“I had Caihuan investigate this matter before. Apparently his fundamental cultivation had reached the fifth layer. Although his surname is Yan, he is certain to be an unimportant character of the Yan Clan. Otherwise, if he were an important disciple, why would he live among us mortals!”

Lady Yan was worthy of being the former head of the Mo Estate. Even though she had reached such dire straights, she managed to neatly arrange this matter and thoroughly understood it.

“This is of no question! In a moment, Junior Martial Sister will just have to show me the way, then I’ll go and settle this problem!” When Han Li heard this, he nodded his head and replied.

“Many thanks, Senior Martial Brother! I knew that Senior Martial Brother was certain to help!” When Mo Caihuan clearly heard this, she sweetly called out with extreme happiness.

“Han Li, we’ve truly troubled you! If we hadn’t, how else could this mother and daughter possibly challenge a cultivator?” Gratitude flashed through Lady Yan’s eyes but then she sighed and helplessly added, “Although this place appears to restrict cultivators from harassing us mortals, there are far too many counts of cultivators humiliating mortals, but how could the Yan Clan possibly punish all those cultivators! Moreover, if a mortal is not careful and actually start a feud with a cultivator, he would evaporate without a trace. This is a rather common occurrence.”

Han Li had heard the unwillingness to be powerless in her words. After all, compared to the grandeur of the ultimate power grasped by the Mo Estate, their current life of swallowing their anger was, as Lady Yan had described, truly humiliating.

After Han Li heard this, he was silent for a moment, Then he asked a few questions of his misgivings.

“Master’s Wife, Junior Martial Sister should have long reached a suitable age for marriage. Why hasn’t she found a suitable partner within the castle yet? If she married a cultivator, wouldn’t you have someone to rely on?”

“Marry?”

“I won’t marry those Yan Clan cultivators!”

Just as Han Li had finished speaking, Lady Yan bitterly smiled as Mo Caihuan loudly rejected this with an entirely unhappy expression.

“Why?” Han Li was somewhat astonished.

“Senior Martial Brother! The cultivators of the Yan Clan fundamentally do not treat us mortal girls justly! If a mortal were to marry to them, she would basically be treated as a mortal slave, nothing more. It would be undesirable for any girl to be in this position since she would be beaten and scolded often. I would rather remain single for my entire life than marry!” Mo Caihuan’s voice was quick and anxious. It was clear she greatly feared this.

“Han Li, you didn’t know this but your Junior Martial Sister made a friend here, a mortal in this castle, and she was married to a Yan Clan cultivator. The result was not as expected. She was frequently abused, and when her appearance aged, they found an excuse to abandon her, leaving her extremely miserable! That cultivator then married again to a young pretty woman. Sigh, if only there were a good-natured cultivator like her stepfather...there are truly too few of them there. I am also unwilling to subject Caihuan to hardship. As for marrying her to a mortal, her perspective is too large, how could she possibly put them in her eyes!” Lady Yan explained Mo Caihuan’s actions.

“So it’s like that! But if that’s the case, will Junior Martial Sister never get married her entire life?” Han Li naturally asked, wrinkling his brow.

When Han Li said this, Lady Yan’s expression changed as if she wanted to say something. But after a moment of hesitation, she decided to not say it. It was unknown what Mo Caihuan was thinking since she too lowered her head and remained silent.

Then Han Li realized the atmosphere felt a bit amiss, as if...

He immediately broke the mood, saying, “Junior Martial Sister, show your Senior Martial Brother the way. Let’s resolve this matter first and talk about this later!”

“Alright!”

Mo Caihuan hesitated for a moment before agreeing. When Lady Yan saw this, she did not have any intention to oppose.

Thus, Han Li and Mo Caihuan departed from the store for the time being and went straight toward the cultivator’s residence, which was quite far away.

……

“Senior Martial Brother, what layer is your cultivation? When you knocked on his door, it appeared to be like a mouse seeing a cat. He called you ‘Senior’ incessantly and bowed to you so many times! With that kind of respect, it was as if he saw his own ancestor.” Mo Caihuan returned to the lively bearing that Han Li remembered. On the desolate path on the way back, she continuously giggled. That was how a young twenty year-old woman should act!

When Han Li saw this, he faintly smiled and humbly answered, “It’s nothing, I was just a layer higher. According to the customs of the cultivation world, he truly should be calling me ‘Senior’!”

When Mo Caihuan heard this, happiness flashed through her eyes, and she giggled even more.

“Regardless, when I remember that funny expression when he saw me, I can’t help but laugh!”

This time, Han LI didn’t say anything and only silently smiled toward Mo Caihuan. After a moment, Mo Caihuan became shy and turned her face away, saying nothing else.

But a moment later, she said something that greatly surprised Han Li.

“Senior Martial Brother, without spiritual roots, is there truly no method to cultivate? I also want to be a cultivator like you!” Mo Caihuan turned her head toward him with a face of grief and a voice with hope.

When Han Li saw this scene, he felt slight heartache but could only remain silent. Ever since ancient times, it was impossible to cultivate without spiritual roots. This has been a constant, rigid truth of the cultivation world for hundred of thousand of years! How could he possibly have great enough ability to break this!

When Mo Caihuan saw Han Li’s expression, her originally blazing heart grew cold. She knew that this extremely capable Senior Martial Brother also to have no method for this.

She could not help but become saddened, silently falling a few steps behind Han Li. The journey slowed, and the two appeared to become quiet.

When the two weren’t far away from the small shop, Han Li suddenly stopped and turned towards Mo Caihuan, saying, “I still have matters to attend to and can’t return to see Martial Mother! Let’s depart here. Fortunately, I will be here at Yan Ling Castle for several more days. Perhaps there will be an opportunity to see you in the future.”

“What? Senior Martial Brother wants to leave now?” Mo Caihuan was startled at first but then appeared greatly disappointed.

“En, here are a few tens of spirit stones. Give them to Martial Mother to set them aside for emergencies. Right now, this is all I can do!” Han Li took out a small leather pouch from his storage pouch and handed it over to Mo Caihuan.

“Many thanks, Senior Martial Brother!” Mo Caihuan said this with a soft voice, appearing extremely feeble. Reluctance to separate appeared in her eyes.

When Han Li saw this display, he didn’t know why, but he felt a peculiar pain in his heart.

After he hesitated for a moment, he took out a silver bottle and tossed out a pink pill.

“Take this. Although it won’t make you a cultivator, it will make it so your appearance will never age and you will forever stay young. This can be considered my present to you as your Senior Martial Brother!” Han Li said with a solemn expression.

“Senior Martial Brother, I...”

When Mo Caihuan heard this, she couldn’t help but be pleasantly surprised. Her desire to say the words in her heart grew stronger. However, Han Li did not let her say them. He flicked his finger and the medicine pill flew into her mouth, causing her to involuntarily swallow.

“Junior Martial Sister, I am leaving! You and Martial Mother take care of yourselves!”

When these words were spoken, Han Li faintly shook and his appearance remained for a second. He then completely disappeared.

“Senior Martial Brother!”

Mo Caihuan called out, astonished. She hurried rushed forth several steps and looked around in every direction. Could there still be any trace of Han Li?

Helpless, Mo Caihuan could only slowly walk back to the store with a saddened expression.

After a short moment, Han Li appeared in a room not too far away. After he silently looked on for a moment more, he disappeared again without hesitation.

Although Han Li was not certain what this Junior Martial Sister was going to say to him, he could make a fairly accurate guess.

But unfortunately, while they were destined to meet, they were not fated to be together! His feelings toward her had not reached that stage.

Not to mention his lifespan as a Foundation Establishment cultivator was truly far too different from her own. That was also why he was unwilling to touch these feelings. After all, powerlessly seeing the people he loved wither before his eyes was truly something Han Li found intolerable!

……

“Heavenly Crane Residence” The name of this teahouse appeared before Han Li. It was an ancient building, three stories high. As expected, it was somewhat imposing.

With only a rough look, Han Li did not think deeper and entered. This was because he had already felt over ten vibrations of magic power within the building, all of which were on par with his own. Only cultivators on the stage of Foundation Establishment or greater could release such spiritual power.

He entered the teahouse and swept his gaze across without stopping in the slightest. Then he went up to the second floor. This was because on the first floor, there were only mortals without the slightest magic power.

Although there were a few cultivators on the second floor, the majority of them were of the Qi Condensation stage. They were fundamentally unable to enter Han Li’s eyes at this moment. Han Li felt the fluctuation of magic power grow greater as he approached the third floor, Han Li’s real objective.

Chapter 263: True Strength

Han Li took a look at the warrant in his hand. It was a conscription order for all traveling disciples, signed by every sect master. He felt extremely depressed!

The conscription order had to be genuine as the sect masters’ spirit emblem wasn’t something that could be forged. However, he truly did not want to follow these orders!

From the other party’s words, Han Li had learned about the Six Devil Dao Sect’s invasion and the great, unavoidable calamity that was about to fall upon the State of Yue’s cultivation world.

Regardless of whether or not the Seven Sects of the State of Yue could resist, innumerable cultivators were certain to die. Even Core Formation Experts would have their core destroyed and perish in no small number.

Thus, when Han Li learned of this astonishing information, what he wanted to do the most was to immediately return to his Immortal’s cave and seclude himself for several tens of years.

However, he also knew that this was merely a pipe dream. As a disciple of the Seven Sects, how could he so easily escape from this great inferno?

While Han Li thought about this, he had already been conscripted by the Masked Moon Sect cultivator in front of him. At this moment, the Masked Moon Sect cultivator said with a smile, “Has this Junior Martial Brother clearly read it? Could Junior Martial Brother state his name and cultivation? We will be working together in the future, so the more we know about each other’s capabilities, the better!”

Han Li composed himself, looked at this person, and then looked at the thirty-plus cultivators behind him. Among these cultivators, there were three late Foundation Establishment cultivators. The rest were Qi Condensation disciples. This caused Han Li to be slightly at ease. At the very least, it didn’t seem this assignment was going to be very difficult.

With this thought, Han Li cupped his fist and said, “Yellow Maple Valley’s Han Li! Early Foundation Establishment!”

Although the Foundation Establishment cultivators could clearly see each other’s cultivation, it was a matter of courtesy. Han Li sincerely carried this out. After all, the other party included late Foundation Establishment disciples with cultivation bases far greater than his own. He wasn’t willing to rashly offend them. Soon after, Han Li asked with misgivings, “Brother, why do you not suspect my identity? Right after you stopped me, you immediately showed me the conscription warrant. Surely you didn’t rely solely on my Yellow Maple Valley uniform?”

When Han Li originally saw this group of Saber Transformation Dock and Masked Moon Sect cultivators, Han Li originally planned to flee. However, he didn’t think this fellow with amazing eyesight would flash several times and appear in front of him, blocking his way and announcing that he was being conscripted.

“Hehe! In the last Trial by Blood and Fire, this one had previously seen Junior Martial Brother! I didn’t think that several years afterwards, Junior Martial Brother Han would actually reach Foundation Establishment. This is truly a matter worth celebrating!” This male Masked Moon Sect cultivator who appeared thirty years old said this with a slight smile, causing Han Li to feel great surprise.

“Who is your esteemed self?”

Upon hearing the other party’s words, Han Li began to feel that he felt somewhat familiar. It seemed that the man really had seen him at the Trial by Blood and Fire!

“This one is Xuan Yue, a steward of the Masked Moon Sect. Last time, I accompanied Martial Aunt Ni Chang’s squad. There, I saw the shocking scene of Junior Martial Han’s great harvest with my own eyes!” The man lightly chuckled, saying this with deep meaning.

At this moment, Han Li suddenly realized something. This person was one of the four Masked Moon Sect Foundation Establishment leaders from that time. Han Li hadn’t paid much attention to him, so he only remembered a vague impression. But after some further thought, he became slightly shocked. He had been in a hurry just now, but this person was actually able to recognize him with a glance from such a far distance. This was truly incredible.

“This one knows that Junior Martial Brother Han had been hurrying on his journey and certainly had some urgent matters. However, this one is truly lacking manpower for this mission and had no better option than to have Junior Martial Brother provide a bit of assistance,” Xuan Yue politely explained.

When Han Li heard this, the corner of his mouth twitched, and he couldn’t help but bitterly smile, thinking, “This late Foundation Establishment cultivator, you already took out the conscription warrant. How could I possibly refuse! I can’t say no unless I want to be branded for being insubordinate.”

As Han Li thought this, he took another look at the other three Foundation Establishment cultivators behind him and could only summon the courage to say, “Since Senior Martial Brother Xuan explained this, I will naturally follow your commands! However, this one must report an important matter to his sect master. I hope that Senior Martial Brother Xuan’s sect members will deliver this information!”

Han Li then systematically narrated what had occurred at Yan Ling Castle in full detail. Naturally, Han Li had left the details of his escape ambiguous.

As such, when Xuan Yue and the others heard of this, they turned pale with fright. They hastily sent two Qi Condensation disciples to each sect to deliver this information. Then with unsightly expressions, they continued on their way with Han Li.

Considering their current strength and the collusion between the Yan Clan and the Devil Dao, they didn’t dare to criticize him for leaving the others behind. They could only pass this scalding hot potato to the Seven Sects by dispatching messengers to them. Naturally, the validity of Han Li’s information would be verified by the upper echelon.

As they journeyed on route, Han Li eventually learned of their assignment from the other cultivators. They were being sent to reinforce the garrison of a particularly large spirit stone mine. The original security assigned there was fundamentally incapable of resisting a minor Devil Dao raid.

Knowing that his assignment wasn’t to become cannon fodder in an upfront melee against the Six Devil Dao Sects, Han Li finally let out a sigh of relief.

In truth, even if he returned to Yellow Maple Valley, he was likely to be immediately be dispatched on a mission. Furthermore, his assignment might not necessarily be better than this one.

Although this assignment was slightly dangerous, so long as he was a bit careful, the possibilities of making it through in one piece was rather high. After all, this spirit stone mine of theirs was only somewhat large, spanning over ten mountains. If the enemy wanted to mount a raid on the seven sect’s spirit mines, it was likely they would target the largest mines first.

With this thought, Han Li’s conflicted mood faded away as he became much more familiar with Xuan Yue and the other cultivators throughout the following days.

Several days later, the group of cultivators finally arrived at a large wasteland within the borders of the State of Yue. That spirit stone mine was located within a huge canyon in the wasteland that was more than three hundred meters deep.

Under Xuan Yue’s guidance, they flew into the canyon, which was concealed by a formation spell. At the same time, several Seven Sect cultivators came out to greet them.

The leader of the original guards of the spirit stone mine was an old man at early Foundation Establishment wearing Heavenly Imperial Fortress clothes. Besides him were five or six Qi Condensation disciples.

With such weak guards, it was no wonder the upper echelons of the seven sects had anxiously dispatched support.

The old man who called himself Yu Xing led them into a huge cave dwelling inside the canyon. There, he gave Han Li and the others a detailed explanation on the circumstances of the spirit stone mine.Then, Xuan Yue swiftly and decisively arranged their defenses.

He took out over ten formation flags and formation disks and had the male cultivators arrange an autonomous attack formation named the "Four Fiend Formation" underneath the illusion formation. He also had Han Li and the other cultivators divide into groups to take turns patrolling and standing guard near the spirit stone mine in order to prevent enemy raids. Cultivators not on duty could meditate and cultivate their magic power.

Han Li was very pleased with Xuan Yue’s arrangements.

Like this, Han Li would be able to compensate for the deficiencies in his strength!

From what he experienced from his fight with the Ghost Spirit Sect, Han Li had come to understand that his previous manner of relying on strategy and nimble movement to deal with the enemy was fundamentally incapable of dealing against enemies with large disparities in strength. Upon meeting a ferocious character like the Ghost Spirit Sect’s young master, everything he could possibly muster had appeared powerless before him. Even the treasure talisman he had put high hopes in had almost been snatched away. He was no longer able to once again fix his problems with a single blow.

If it weren’t for the surprising effects of the poisonous fog released by the “Azurefire Miasma”, he would have long been buried underneath the yellow earth. Even his very own soul may have been collected by his opponent and tormented in more than a hundred ways. When he thought of that dreadful fate worse than death, Han Li felt chilled to the bone!

A great fear of that top-grade Devil Dao secret technique, the Great Blood Spirit Arts, had been born in Han Li’s heart!

He clearly understood that if he were to come across the Ghost Spirit Sect young master again, it was likely he would only be able to resign himself to death against his opponent’s secret techniques. Unless he cultivated the Azure Essence Sword Art to Core Formation, its divine abilities fundamentally wouldn’t be able to contend against that opponent.

During the Six Devil Dao Sect’s invasion of the State of Yue, the Seven Great Sects had vigorously struck back during the confusion, so melees between cultivators became commonplace. During this time, long-term plans had become secondary in favor of quickly increasing one’s strength, allowing a cultivator to preserve his life in this period of chaos.

Thus, his original plans for cultivation must adapt!

The Azure Essence Sword Art would be set aside for the time being. He would first cultivate the “Great Development Technique” to substantially increase his strength.

Having previously seen the overbearing power of mechanical puppets, Han Li was convinced that even if he could only cultivate the first layer of the Great Development Technique, he would have enough power to defend himself. After all, he already had several tens of mechanical puppets on hand.

Naturally, he would have to study those puppet sutras and hope he would be able to create a few simple mechanical puppets in the short term. With that along with the “Great Development Technique” he would have a continued source of strength throughout his time in Foundation Establishment.

After repeatedly pondering over this several times, Han Li felt this decision was correct and cultivated the “Great Development Technique” during his time off duty. At the same time, he also used a few simple materials he had on hand and started attempting to create elementary mechanical beasts, devoting his energy to creating puppets similar to his figurines.

Chapter 265: War Situation

According to the “Great Development Technique”, after cultivating it to the first layer, splitting over ten strands of divine sense would be of no problem. After reaching the second layer, one could divide up to a hundred. Upon reaching to the third layer like “Senior Marial Brother Lin” had done, one could split their consciousness into several hundreds of strands.

When he thought of being able to control several hundreds of puppets in a battle after reaching the third layer, Han Li had felt a bit strange.

However, this abnormal feeling was due to Han Li being unstoppable among Foundation Establishment cultivators.

But once he reached Core Formation, he would have to refine several hundreds of puppets of grade three of higher, equivalent to the strength of Foundation Establishment cultivators. Otherwise, no matter how many he refined, they would unable to withstand a Core Formation cultivator’s attack. That scene where Fatty Lei had swept away several hundreds of the Thousand Bamboo School’s grade two puppets was still clear in his mind!

Since refining each grade two puppet required the materials for a high-grade magic tool, to refine an even higher grade puppet would require materials for a top-grade magic tool at the very least!

As such, if Core Formation cultivators who cultivated the puppet technique wished to suppress other Core Formation cultivators of the same strength, they would have to spend enough materials for several hundreds of top-grade magic tools at the very least. From this thought, Han Li could not help but be apprehensive for a long while!

Not to mention the materials that would be wasted from refinement failure, as well finding hundreds of strong enough souls.

This was also a major reason so few knew of the Thousand Bamboo School’s puppet technique.

After all, a sect’s strength was evaluated on the number of Core Formation cultivators it possessed. With regards to battles between Core Formation cultivators, the Thousand Bamboo School was powerless while other sects thrived. Even if their Foundation Establishment disciples were ferocious, they could only hole themselves up in a single region and become a mere local hegemon.

Naturally, this was just some speculation from Han Li after he cultivated the Great Development Technique and the puppet techniques!

However, this puppet technique would cause Han Li’s strength as a Foundation Establishment cultivator to substantially increase. This fact wasn’t false in the least! As of now, Han Li couldn’t be bothered with future deficiencies.

After all, this great war stirred across the cultivation worlds of several countries had just started!

Not long after Han Li started guarding this spirit stone mine, a great ambush had unfolded at some desolate desert mountain between the Six Devil Dao Sects and the Seven Sects of the State of Yue.

Han Li gradually came to know the specific circumstances. Originally, Spirit Beast Mountain of the Seven Sects was actually a branch of Devil Dao’s Controlling Spirit Sect, but the neutral sect had secretly eliminated the Devil Dao’s intermediaries several thousand years ago and buried them in the State of Yue.

As for this invasion of the State of Yue, the Devil Dao had planned to take advantage of their formal relationship and hoped to use the same tactic they had used to seize the State of Jiang and Che Ji to great effect.

But who could have known that the ancestors of Spirit Beast Mountain had passed on their unwillingness to be part of the Controlling Spirit Sect to their descendants through the past thousands of years? They were absolutely unwilling to have another overlord suddenly appear above their heads.

As a result, after Spirit Beast Mountain released this information to the other six sects, they used an unknown method to convince the Devil Dao sects to attack a stronghold of Seven Sect cultivators.

As they mounted a raid with several thousand cultivators, they were ambushed by a great number of Seven Sect cultivators on route. With the Seven Sect’s absolute advantage, the Devil Dao suffered a great loss, even losing two Core Formation cultivators during the fight.

This was a great blow to the Six Devil Dao Sects, and naturally it was greatly celebrated by the Seven Sects of the State of Yue, greatly boosting their morale. Humiliated, the Six Devil Dao Sects flew into a rage and began their large-scale assault.

Not to be outdone, the Seven Sects laid out their defensive formations.

Among the common border shared by the State of Yue and the States of Jiang and Che Ji, over ten great battles had occurred there, resulting in the deaths of over ten thousand cultivators. With the additional deaths of seven or eight Core Formation cultivators, the battles had been extremely desperate!

On the day a few cultivators came to pick up spirit stones, they told the guards this with lingering fear. This caused Han Li and other cultivators who heard this to become extremely apprehensive, secret rejoicing at not needing to fight in the war. Just by seeing how many Core Formation cultivators died in battle, one could imagine how dreadful the situation has become!

However, the Six Devil Dao Sects were one of the two great powers in the Heavenly South Region. Their strength truly couldn’t be compared to the likes of the cultivation world of the State of Yue.

After seven or eight battles, the Seven Sects clearly understood they would not be able to continuously withstand the opposition’s fierce assault. If the Seven Sects didn’t prepare and establish great restriction formations in advance as cornerstones of their desperate struggle, they would be defeated without much resistance.

But even if this were the case, the Seven Sects wouldn’t be able to withstand for long.

During this time of certain crisis for the State of Yue, the Seven Sects had sent requests to the cultivators of the mid-level States of Yuan Wu and Zi Jin to come to their aid.

Before the Seven Sects had started their war against the Six Devil Dao Sects, it turned that they had already wisely sent eloquent messengers to the two country’s sects to request aid.

When the cultivation sects of these two countries received these letters, they were naturally afraid that after the Devil Dao seized the State of Yue, their countries would be the next ones to be taken over. Without having the messengers spend time pleading, they agreed to provide aid. Joined together against a common enemy, the two countries sent a majority of their cultivators to provide assistance during that starry night.

This new alliance greatly reduced the disparity in strength between the State of Yue and the Six Devil Dao Sects. By relying on the protection of their powerful great formations, they were able to firmly resist the Devil Dao’s assault.

As such, the Six Devil Dao Sects’ plan to seize the State of Yue in a single burst was naturally shattered. The war sunk into a deadlock and became a battle of attrition.

As a result, large decisive battles became less frequent while smaller scale surprise attacks at the rear occurred in great number on both sides, particularly at locations where materials and spirit stones were produced. These raids eventually became the primary objective of the Seven Sects and Devil Dao.

Perhaps the warfront was too far away, but this specific spirit stone mine had not yet suffered an enemy attack. This was nothing short of a miracle! After all, other equivalently-sized spirit stone mines had all already suffered three to four raids.

But the more the raids occurred, the more the Seven Sects became ill at ease. Half a month later, a group of twenty cultivators were dispatched as support, headed by a late Foundation Establishment cultivator.

Thus, the spirit stone mine naturally became far stronger! However, like a mountain longs for rain, Han Li felt a desire to cultivate the Great Development Technique even more diligently. The distance to break through to the first layer was still far away.

Among the second group of Qi Condensation disciples to come, Han Li unexpectedly came across an acquaintance, that ugly man Zhong Wu he previously met at the Trial by Blood and Fire.[1]

Zhong Wu also recognized Han Li.

However, now that Han Li had a cultivation base at Foundation Establishment, his expression darkened all over, switching between shock, envy, admiration, as well as many other emotions. Seeing him once again truly astonished Han Li.

Finally, Zhong Wu bitterly smiled. He saluted Han Li in advance and somewhat unwillingly called him “Senior”.

Resisting a smile with difficulty, Han Li insipidly replied.

When Han Li thought of Zhong Wu’s many changing expressions as he sat in meditation, he couldn’t help but knowingly smile and opened his eyes. At this moment, his mood was truly unsuitable for cultivating the Great Development Technique; he would continue when his heart became tranquil!

……

Time passed by quickly. Spending a small portion of time on guard duty and the majority of his time cultivating the Great Development Technique and refining mechanical puppet beasts, a month passed for Han Li. During this time, Han Li could clearly feel that he was on the verge of breaking through the first layer of the Great Development Technique.

This caused Han Li to be pleasantly surprised!

With regards to Han Li’s cultivation of Five Element Daoist magic and the Azure Essence Sword Art, his aptitude toward them was shown to be inferior! However, he was able to cultivate this Great Development Technique extremely smoothly and without the slightest difficulty, feeling as if success flowed naturally. In addition to feeling happiness, Han Li also felt awe in his heart!

As for this first grade two mechanical puppet, after failing over ten times, he finally refined it two days ago. Although it was a bit crude when compared to the puppets of the Thousand Bamboo School and its strength was rather inferior, it caused Han Li to beam with happiness. After preparing materials brought to him by other cultivators, he started refining them in great quantity.

But today, just as Han Li was sitting in meditation in a quiet room, he heard an extremely sharp whistle from the outside. Then people loudly yelled, “Not good! The Devil Dao is attacking! Prepare to fight!”

Han Li’s heart trembled. His expression became solemn as he left the quiet room.

At this moment, the Seven Sect cultivators who were originally meditating and resting in the cave solemnly walked out just as Han Li had. After they mutually looked at each other, they walked out of the cave dwelling one after another.

The Masked Moon Sect’s late Foundation Establishment Xuan Yue and Spirit Beast Mountain’s Lu Tianmeng were expressionlessly floating underneath the offensive formations and looked up from the great canyon.

Over ten cultivators who were on duty stood behind him with anxious and frightened expressions. But after they saw Han Li and the others coming to support them, they became far more calm.

Han Li followed Xuan Yue’s gaze and looked up from the great canyon. As expected, there were traces of enemies, about twenty or thirty assailants.

However, Han Li clearly understood that since the enemy had dared perform a raid from such a distance, it was likely that they were all at late Foundation Establishment; they wouldn’t have brought any Qi Condensation disciples to weigh them down.

Thus, in terms of strength, they were absolutely weak in comparison! This battle was not likely to go very well!

[1]. Zhong Wu first appeared in the Trial by Blood and Fire, Chapter 193: Division Between Enemy and Friends.

[Back]

Chapter 266: Fierce Battle

Han Li’s side had nine Foundation Establishment cultivators and over sixty Qi Condensation disciples. Although they were a bit weaker than the opposition, they had the Four Fiend Formation, so it wasn’t as if they were completely defenseless.

As a result, Xuan Yue called out, having Han Li and the other cultivators hide near the Four Fiend Formations and observe the enemy’s movements.

At this moment, Han Li was able to take a distinct look at the Devil Dao attackers.

They were all wearing either red or yellow robes. It seemed they were cultivators from two sects.

Standing at the forefront were an ordinary-looking red-robed young woman and an old yellow-robed man who appeared to be sixty to seventy years old. Their cultivation wasn’t particularly special, one being at early Foundation Establishment and the other at late Foundation Establishment. They were talking to each other with slight smiles on their faces.

“Be careful. These people are from the Devil Flame Sect and the Heavenly Fiend Sect.” Lu Tianmeng, being the only one who had experienced multiple encounters with the Six Devil Dao Sects, said this to the other cultivators with great caution as if he felt great fear towards the people from these two sects.

When the Han Li and the other cultivators heard this, their expressions naturally grew increasingly serious.

At this moment, the young red clothed woman stopped chatting, turned her head, and insipidly said a few words.

Because Han Li and the others were too far away, they weren’t able to hear very clearly what she said, but her words made the red-robed cultivators behind the young woman move forward before slowly flying down toward the canyon’s four offensive formations.

At this moment, the yellow-robed old man also silently waved his hand, and his yellow-robed cultivators became streaks of yellow light that headed toward the Four Fiend Formation. Within the formation, Han Li and the others unknowingly held their breaths and impatiently revealed their magic tools.

These yellow-robed cultivators naturally didn’t foolishly charge straight into the formation. Instead, they stopped about a hundred meters away from the Four Fiend Formation. Then, magic tools flew out, aggressively throwing themselves at the great formation.

The collisions of the magic tools’ wondrous light and the Four Fiend Formation’s azure, red, blue, and yellow-colored restrictions released waves of thunderous explosions, causing the expressions of the Seven Sect cultivators underneath to slightly change.

“Half of you will go out to deal with those Heavenly Fiend cultivators. Do not let them break the great formation! The other half, be on guard against the Devil Flame Sect cultivators!” The Masked Moon Sect’s Xuan Yuee muttered to himself for a moment before decisively giving his orders.

Then a small pure white sword flew out of the formation and turned into a streak of white light, obstructing a flying saber as well as bead magic tools.

Hearing those words, a team of cultivators followed Xuan Yue and also released several of their own magic tools, obstructing most of the opponent’s offense. Han Li was naturally one of these people. With flawless proficiency, he released his “Golden Beetle Swarm Blades” to form a net of golden light, trapping a long azure spear magic tool.

Because Han Li had chosen to battle the owner of the magic tool, who had the same level of cultivation as he did, the battle seemed extremely tense as golden light and azure streaks danced about. But in fact, Han Li was easily in control and had the time to take a look at other areas of the battlefield.

The situation appeared to be handled!

The cultivators at Han Li’s side were mostly Qi Condensation disciples. Their magic tools could not compete with their enemies’. Only with the cooperation of five or six members would they barely be able to resist the attack of a single Foundation Establishment cultivator. But because they were underneath the protection of a great formation, these cultivators were able to dodge into the formation during a time of crisis and avoid death. As for the other Foundation Establishment cultivators, they naturally were the same as Han Li, each blocking a yellow-robed cultivator in a dazzling light show.

“So this is the strength of the Six Devil Dao Sects.”

Han Li felt this was a bit strange. If their enemy’s strength were as such, then how could defending the spirit stone mines prove to be such a problem!

Just as he thought this, the red-robed cultivators from the Devil Flame Sect eventually arrived beside the Four Fiend Formation. This caused Lu Tianmeng and the cultivators that had yet to act to diligently pay attention to them. A few of the younger Seven Sect cultivators were somewhat eager to act.

The red-robed cultivators didn’t immediately enter the fight. Instead, they stood in a strange formation.Following a command, they all took out a fiery red banner with a Golden Crow on a scorching sun, releasing a brilliant red light. From a single look, one could this this was no ordinary object.

“Not good! These people are Wild Flame cultivators! They want to release an Azure Sun Devil Flame. Quickly block them!”

When Lu Tianmeng saw these red-robed cultivators act so calmly, he felt an ill premonition in his heart. As they stood in a battle formation and each took out a banner, he suddenly recalled an astonishing scene he witnessed from the day he fought in a great battle against the six sects. He couldn’t help but shout with a whitened complexion.

This Spirit Beast Mountain cultivator then instantly rushed out of the formation and hastily reached for the storage pouch at his waist, immediately releasing two flying centipedes about a meter long.

These two centipedes were covered in sinister black and yellow stripes and sprouted dark green translucent wings. Under Lu Tianmeng’s hurried whistles, they charged toward the red-robed individuals with an ominous light emitting from their eyes.

Upon hearing these words, although the other Seven Sect cultivators that had yet to act did not know what “Wild Flame cultivators” and “Azure Sun Devil Flame” were, they knew that since it was able to cause their late Foundation Establishment captain to become bewildered, it was no small matter, so they did not hesitate to follow his orders.

The other Foundation Establishment cultivators followed closely behind Lu Tianmeng and also sent their magic tools after the two centipedes towards the red-robed cultivators.

At this moment, more than ten Wild Flame cultivators were still chanting as they held the large banners without moving in the slightest, turning a blind eye to the attacking cultivators. This caused Lu Tianmeng and the other cultivators to grow greatly excited.

The very first to arrive in front of the Devil Flame Sect cultivators were one of the two flying centipedes. It opened its mouth and ruthlessly sprayed out dark green poisonous gas.

But at this moment, something shocking had occurred.

With the green poisonous gas having not yet left the huge centipede’s mouth, several slender streaks of silver light flickered from its body. Its body then suddenly fell to pieces, having been cut by the streaks of light.

Without waiting for the Seven Sect cultivators to recover from their shock, the same scene immediately occurred to the other centipede. This caused Lu Tianmeng’s expression to greatly change, and he hastily stopped moving. He then took out a small shield and placed it in front of his body.

Overwhelmed with shock, the several cultivators behind him also took out defensive magic tools and defensive talismans, fearing they would meet a similar end as the centipedes.

However, something even more outrageous occurred!

Just as the few magic tools that had closely followed behind the centipede began their attack, an abundance of fine silver strings appeared in front of them, tightly wrapping around them without allowing the slightest of movements.

The Seven Sect cultivators that had just left the great formation looked at each other in dismay. In a moment, they no longer knew what to do!

“Quickly use the Spirit Light Technique. There are others in front of those red-robed cultivators, hidden by some sort of secret concealment art!” After a flashing blue light from his eyes, a cultivator who had experienced a loss of a magic tool shouted this out with shock.

These words caused the other cultivators to suddenly come to a realization. However, only Foundation Establishment cultivators could use the Spirit Light Technique. Qi Condensation disciples could only helplessly watch!

Han Li also used the Spirit Light Technique to look at that location!

He had seen the entire previous scene and was shocked by no small amount! Now that he was reminded to use the Spirit Light technique, he saw several indistinct white silhouettes in front of the Devil Flame Sect cultivators that were holding the banner. These figures held a long slender sword-like weapon in one hand and controlled a thin silver thread in the other, restraining the magic tools.

At this moment, after Lu Tianmeng and the other cultivators had discovered the white silhouettes, they did not hesitate to attack with all sorts of magic tools and magic techniques, suppressing the white silhouettes. However, those white silhouettes held on tenaciously. Regardless of what magic tool or Daoist magic was used, they seemed to cause no large injuries to the white silhouettes as if they simply had immortal bodies.

But fortunately, the white silhouettes could only use one hand to slice and the other to tangle. With a bit of careful dodging from the Seven Sect’s side, the silhouettes only method of attack was neutralized!

“What sort of crafty thing is this?”

Han Li exclaimed in great surprise! These silhouettes obviously weren’t those of ordinary humans. Could they be refined sacrificial ghost spirits?

As he thoughtfully pondered this, he commanded the golden blades in front of him. This careless attitude finally offended the middle-aged Heavenly Fiend cultivator!

As the cultivator commanded the azure spear to tangle with Han Li’s golden blades with a darkened face, he noiselessly patted his storage pouch. A continuously spinning white bead suddenly flew from it.

After this bead charged out, it grew to the size of a room as it flew, fiercely striking toward Han Li’s head.

Even though Han Li wasn’t paying much attention, how could he not notice such large movements from the enemy?

He calmly chopped his hand through the air, and an azure sword streak several meters long flew from his hand towards the bead. The sword streak chopped against the bead and was unable to advance for the moment.

Then, Han Li took out his “Black Dragon’s Gasp from his storage pouch. As the sword streak was on the verge of collapse, it took its place and formed a deadlock with the bead. This caused the Heavenly Fiend cultivator to become extremely angry, but he had no other option at the moment!

“Not good!”

Lu Tianmeng’s extremely anxious shout caused Han Li’s heart to tremble. He hastily looked to the side and noticed that the red-robed cultivators had stopped chanting. At the same time, they lifted their banners into the air. The top of the banner began to faintly emit an azure flame.

“So that’s the Azure Sun Devil Flame.” Han Li widely opened his eyes and rigidly stared at the azure flame, feeling a bit restless.

Seeing the opponent finish casting their magic, Lu Tianmeng’s heart completely sunk! However, he wasn’t even close to breaking through the white silhouettes before him!

Chapter 269: Blood Red

“Could it be it wishes to eliminate us in one stroke?” Zhong Wu asked with a white complexion.

“Humph!”

Xuan Yue didn’t speak and raised his hand instead. Seven to eight fireballs flew from his hand, shooting toward the dense spiderweb.

Peng peng! The spiderweb was left completely intact. Not even the slightest sign of a burn could be seen.

At this moment, the others weren’t surprised. They had clearly anticipated that this spiderweb wasn’t so fragile.

During this moment, the white spider slightly bent its legs, and with ferocious power, it pounced straight toward Xuan Yue’s direction with its entire body.

Xuan Yue’s expression darkened. He pressed a yellow talisman against the ground, and immediately after, it noiselessly dissolved into floor.

Subsequently, a huge stone spike sharply rose not far away, precisely hitting the abdomen of the spider as it leaped in midair. The spider was rigidly pinned to the roof of the cavern, incapable of moving for the time being.

“Good!”

When Lu Tianmeng saw this, he loudly shouted and revealed an expression of happiness.

Then, he threw out a dark green bag with the bag’s opening pointed at the spider at the ceiling, revealing faint warm light.

At this moment, the spider trapped at the cavern ceiling started hissing. It drew its legs towards its abdomen and held the stone spike tightly. Then it fiercely exerted force.

The sounds of crashing stones were heard. The tip of the stone spike had actually been easily crushed into countless falling stones.

After recovering its freedom, the demonic beast jumped down. When it had broken the stone spike’s tip, its small eyes flickered with green light as if it were angered.

It lowered its body and then straightened it. It seemed to want to pounce toward the cultivators once again.

But at this moment, the warm light rushed out from the bag and precisely swept away the spider as it was midair. Then as quick as lightning, the light returned, with it the spider that had unexpectedly shrunk as it was collected into the bag.

Han Li and the others at the side were startled. Such a seemingly ferocious spider had actually been so easily captured alive. This was truly hard to imagine.

Lu Tianmeng also wore an expression of pleasant surprise.

Although the might of his “Sun and Moon Pouch” was quite considerable, it had already been used many times to collect a large number of demonic beasts. Even so, it was still able to smoothly capture this spider, which caused him to be greatly surprised. Feelings of ecstasy then began to rise in his heart. If he could tame such a demonic beast, wouldn’t his power increase by several times?

With this thought, although Lu Tianmeng had regained his calm, his happiness was displayed on his brow. He impatiently waved at the green bag, and it slow flew back under everyone’s gazes.

The other cultivators naturally knew what such a live demonic beast meant to a member of Spirit Beast Mountain. They couldn’t help but display an expression of envy. However, just as this expression was revealed, that flying bag suddenly stopped in midair and moved no more.

Lu Tianmeng grew frightened and hastily attempted to retrieve his bag by forcefully using more magic power. However, after the bag swayed several more times, it still stopped in midair.

Everyone watching from the side knew something was amiss. They hastily went on guard.

The surface of the leather bag suddenly became bumpy; it seemed that demonic beast was causing these oddities from within the bag. These strange occurrences continued for a short moment before disappearing. But soon after, it suddenly began to swell and with a loud bang as the bag exploded into pieces. The white spider had actually forcibly destroyed the magic tool and restored its original size.

After once again escaping constraint, the demonic beast clearly entered a craze. Its translucent pure white body gradually turned red and began to shoot off fearful blood-red rays of light. It began grinding its mouthful of sharp teeth, releasing fearful crackling noises.

When Lu Tianmeng and the others saw this, they all solemnly drew back several steps, planning to use explosions from magic tools to increase the distance between them.

However, the blood red spider cut forward with its many legs and charged toward the two cultivators furthest away as fast as lightning.

After seeing only two streaks of white light flash by and hearing “Pupu”, the two cultivators’ defensive barriers had been destroyed in a single strike, their bodies severed in two, meeting a violent end. Among these two was unexpectedly that ugly man Zhong Wu. Unfortunately, he had believed he was safer as he was farther away!

After seeing the two cultivators’ deaths along with the spider’s lightning-fast movements, the others that had scattered the farthest turned pale with fright and feared they would follow the pair’s footsteps.

However, they were too late. The demonic beast’s body had already flashed and turned into a streak of blood-red light, shooting toward the Saber Transformation Dock cultivator.

This cultivator’s face became deathly pale. He grit his teeth, shooting two black throwing knives at the approaching spider.

However, the spider opened its mouth, and shining white liquid shot out toward the throwing knives, causing the throwing knives to lose their magic power and fall to the floor. Then it leaped up with its huge body and bit off the head of the Saber Transformation Dock cultivator. The headless corpse spouted out blood like a fountain, causing those who saw it to become aghast.

The others, Han Li included, no longer hesitated and immediately sent talismans and magic tools to smash its head!

However, even since the spider’s body turned blood red, it became as fast as the wind. Within this narrow cavern, the magic tools and magic techniques simply couldn’t follow its nimble movements. A short moment later, another two cultivators met their violent end underneath its fierce teeth.

Although one of them had timely used a colored scarf to obstruct its advance, in the blink of an eye, the spider shredded through the scarf and killed him. This spider’s legs and fierce teeth were truly sharp! Their hardness was absolutely that of a top-grade magic tool or higher.

At this moment, only Lu Tianmeng, Xuan Yue, and Han Li had remained! The trio’s complexion had become ashen with extreme fear and anger!

If they were in an open area, then these cultivators wouldn’t have died so easily. After all, with flying magic tools, they definitely would’ve lasted longer!

Bang! The spider flashed to the side of Lu Tianmeng. As it attempted to cleave his body in two through his protective barrier, a black object appeared to obstruct it.

This flat and round object appeared to be a small shield, but under careful observation, its surface seemed to have cracks. It was actually a miraculously strange turtle shell. Apart from a shallow mark that remained from the strike, it was completely intact; it was truly astonishing.

Seeing it had no effect, the huge spider immediately gave up on Lu Tianmeng and flashed with red light, arriving at Han Li’s side with its jaws open.

However, Han Li’s cold expression shook several times. His body suddenly became vague and immediately disappeared. He then appeared over twenty meters away. This caused the demonic beast to unexpectedly stay still from surprise.

During this delay, Xuan Yue took out a small yellow cup and arrived next to the spider. After the small cup flashed with yellow light and expanded, Xuan Yue slapped it underneath, trapping it once again. Afterwards, Han Li expanded his Black Dragon’s Grasp to its greatest size and cautiously hovered over the cup, fearing another escape from the demonic beast.

“You two, be at ease. My Heaven Shrouding Cup was refined from copper essence, a material used to refine magic treasures. It absolutely wouldn’t be able to escape!” After Xuan Yue’s expression relaxed, he explained this to Han Li and Lu Tianmeng.

Hearing this, Han Li’s expression relaxed, and he retrieved his Black Dragon’s Grasp. It seemed he was truly at ease.

However, Lu Tianmeng walked to the front of the copper cup and took a few looks at it before muttering to himself and shaking his head with worry, saying, “This won’t do! I feel unassured! Continue using your cup to trap the beast and give me time to prepare a magic treasure and thoroughly kill this monster.”

When Xuan Yue heard this, he wrinkled his brow, but he didn’t say anything and followed along.

Han Li then looked at the transportation formation and the skeleton’s command medallion. After a moment of thought, he walked to the side and sat cross-legged in meditation, leaving the previous matter up to the other two.

At this moment, Lu Tianmeng took out a treasure talisman flashing with azure light. He pressed it between his palms and slowly filled it with spiritual power.

It was obvious that a late Foundation Establishment could use a treasure talisman quickly without having to charge it with power. A short moment later, he separated his hands, and an exquisite small rod shot forth and revolved around his head.

“Are you ready? I’m going to release the demonic beast!” When Xuan Yue saw this, he asked this with concern as he controlled the small cup.

“I’m ready. You both can die at ease. That Greater Displacement Medallion is mine!” Lu Tianmeng widely opened his eyes, suddenly revealing a sinister appearance.

After this large shout, the tip of the short rod released innumerable rays of light. In a flash, one rod became two, two became four and four became eight.... In the blink of an eye, over several hundred similar small rods had appeared. Each of the small rods released a small, buzzing rumble. Then, under Lu Tianmeng’s control, the majority of the rods charged toward Xuan Yue in a dense formation, while a small portion went toward Han Li as he was meditating cross-legged.

When Han Li saw this, his expression slightly changed. He didn’t dare to clench the item in his hand and rigidly stared at the approaching talisman treasures. Xuan Yue’s expression was dull, as if he were turning a blind eye to this crisis.

Seeing the pair’s expression, Lu Tianmeng’s proud expression froze. As he shouted ‘Not Good!’ in his mind, he thought to take out the tortoise shell. However, behind him, the sound of the ground rupturing came from behind him. Then, a streak of red light struck at his side.

Suddenly, Lu Tianmeng’s body fell to the ground in two pieces. Right after, the red light leaped back a certain distance away and stopped. It was unexpected the blood red spider that had escaped its trap at an unknown time.

Chapter 273: A Timely Encounter

After pulling out a majority of the spirit stones in his pocket, Han Li even collected a majority of the ingredients necessary for the new ancient pill formulas.

As for the remaining missing ingredients, Han Li gritted his teeth and risked taking out two four-hundred-year-old spirit herbs to sell. His other option was to participate in a few more assignments to kill Devil Dao cultivators. In this way, not only could he earn a reward of a considerable amount of spirit stones, he could also exchange the items found in the enemies’ storage pouches for even more spirit stones.

Based on the numerous treasure talismans he possessed and the strength of the Great Development Technique, even if Han Li ran into late Foundation Establishment cultivator, he could escape from the opponent safe and sound. Similarly, if early or mid Foundation Establishment cultivators were to run into Han Li, they naturally would not have any strength to retaliate and could only flee for their life from Han Li.

Of course, how could important Foundation Establishment cultivators like the Ghost Spirit Sect’s young master participate in these kinds of operations?

Just like this, Han Li earned himself a small bit of reputation among the Seven Sects Foundation Establishment cultivators this past year.

Everyone knew that a vicious character had emerged from the Yellow Maple Valley. While his cultivation base was only that of the mid Foundation Establishment, he inconceivably hunted down over ten Devil Dao cultivators and was still able to return whole.

Han Li used the spirit stones that he had exchanged for to gather all the remaining ingredients for the ancient pill formulas. Upon hearing that the campgrounds of a few other sects also had similar exchange locations, Han Li asked Fatty Chen to be on the lookout for pill formulas, but now it seemed there wasn’t much hope.

Just as Han Li wanted to say goodbye to the other person, a gust of fragrant wind suddenly reached his nose.

Slightly stunned, Han Li twisted his head around to take a look; an elegant and cold female cultivator was approaching from behind.

Come to think of it, he and this woman had not run into each other ever since the departure from the forbidden area, so he didn’t know when she had arrived at this camp.

“Fifth Uncle, this is the item that you asked for!”

Junior Martial Sister Chen indifferently sized up Han Li. Soon after, a trace of shock flashed across her eyes, but she still arrived in front of Fatty Chen and handed a storage pouch over to him.[1]

“Hehe! Niece Qiaoqian, your arrival is too timely; I was just thinking about these goods!” Fatty Chen said with delight upon seeing Junior Martial Sister Chen, his jowls flapping.

“Fifth Uncle?”

Han Li was stunned by Fatty Chen’s title for quite some time!

He never expected that this fatty whom he had known for the greater half of a year was actually Junior Martial Sister Chen’s senior. Just based on his mid Foundation Establishment cultivation base, his status in the Chen Clan would definitely not be low.

After initially glancing at Han Li, Junior Martial Sister Chen did not send a single glance in Han Li’s way. This cold treatment caused Han Li to feel unhappy in his heart!

“Senior Martial Brother Chen, I will take my leave now, but I will definitely come visit you in the future!” Han Li said politely, unwilling to stay any longer. He turned his head around and walked out of the market.

At this time, Chen Qiaoqian finally gazed coldly at Han Li’s disappearing figure; her eyebrows were tightly knit as she asked Fatty Chen, who was inspecting the storage pouch:

“Fifth Uncle, was this scaredy-cat trying to buy something from you?”

“Scaredy-cat?”

Fatty Chen was shocked by Chen Qiaoqing’s words.

“Yes, the fellow who was just standing here!”

“You’re talking about...... Han Li?” Fatty Chen blinked his tiny eyes as an expression of disbelief surfaced on his face.

“Yes, I’m talking about him. Is there something wrong with that?” Chen Qiaoqian asked, somewhat curious.

Back then, during the expedition to the forbidden area, Han Li had not given this Junior Martial Sister Chen any good impressions. She always reckoned that Han Li was someone who had run into a great deal of good fortune and always took the opportunity to escape from a fight.

Fatty Chen sat in silence for a moment before suddenly sighing, saying with a strange tone:

“Qiaoqian, you’ve just arrived here and are ignorant about some matters. Although I don’t know why you think this guy is a scaredy-cat, your fellow sect member’s reputation here is not small! He is an extremely strong character who exterminated over ten Foundation Establishment cultivators in succession and is definitely not a mediocre individual. I even want to recommend this person to the clan leader after a few more battles. If we can win over this guy, he will be a great help to us!”

“He exterminated over ten Foundation Establishment cultivators?” Junior Martial Sister Chen asked, the cold expression on her face turning into one of amazement; she truly did not dare to believe what she was hearing.

She couldn’t help but gaze blankly at the exchange location’s front door, but by now, Han Li had already left the room for quite some time.

After walking out of the exchange location, Han Li pondered for a moment, then headed towards his master Li Huayuan’s residence, preparing to pay his respects to his master according to common convention.

As a Core Formation cultivator, Li Huayuan’s residence could not be compared to those of regular cultivators! He lived in a cozy little house in the middle of a large formation; his wife naturally lived together with him.

As for Han Li’s seven Senior Martial Brothers, apart from the eldest, who was still standing guard outside of the Green Ripple Cave, all the others had missions and were not present here. The only ones remaining here were Han Li and his Fourth Senior Martial Brother, Song Meng.

The first day that Han Li arrived and went to see Li Huayuan, his cultivation base of mid Foundation Establishment caused his master to feel great shock!

After all, Han Li had only successfully entered Foundation Establishment a few years ago.

Under normal circumstances, even cultivators with good talent would need to spend ten or more years before advancing from early to mid Foundation Establishment, so Han Li’s sudden advancement in leaps and bounds naturally aroused Li Huayuan’s curiosity.

After finding no evidence from searching Han Li’s body, he asked some questions related to the cause for Han Li’s cultivation base to grow so quickly.

Han Li naturally would not reveal the truth; instead, he put on an act of confusion, as if he also didn’t know what had happened, causing Li Huayuan to feel depressed for quite a while before dropping the matter altogether! After all, he was currently confronting grave difficulties. He was not in the mood to spend too much time investigating this matter.

As for the matters of the Yan Clan defecting and Dong Xuan’er falling into enemy hands, Li Huayuan and Hong Fu both already knew about it. Apart from being extremely enraged by this, they did not actually blame Han Li too much.

After all, the opponent’s strength was too great; for Han Li to be able to escape with his life was already not an easy feat.

Just as Han Li was thinking these things, he had already arrived outside of Li Huayuan’s residence!

What shocked him was that his Fourth Senior Martial Brother Song Meng was actually standing outside the room with his arms hugging his shoulders, strangely full of energy as if he were a posted sentry standing guard.

Upon seeing Han Li, Song Meng’s face revealed a trace of laughter. He said in a deep voice:

“Junior Martial Brother Han, you’ve come to pay your respects to Master once again!”

Han Li gently laughed and gave an “en”.

After Han Li had become somewhat famous, Song Meng forced Han Li to spar with him privately. Although Han Li had relied on a magic tool to penetrate his defenses and claim a small victory, he slowly began to feel friendlier towards Han Li, and between the two of them, they actually began to laugh and talk with one another.

“Junior Martial Brother Han, Master is currently discussing with some guests, so you should wait outside for now! Come to think of it, I’ve made some progress in my cultivation technique; why don’t you spar with me in a bit!” Song Meng smiled as he explained to Han Li, but immediately after he made an invitation that caused Han Li’s head to hurt greatly.

Ever since Senior Martial Brother Song had lost to him, every so often he would ask that Han Li spar with him one more time. However, how could Han Li be willing to reveal his true strength? Naturally, he firmly refused every time.

If this were the Yellow Maple Valley, this Senior Martial Brother Song wouldn’t be so easy to shake off! Luckily, many strong cultivators were in this campground, and many opponents as well. Song Meng, seeing that he did not succeed after pestering Han Li a few times, was unable to bear his own temperament and went to go find other people.

Only then could Han Li finally let out a sigh of relief!

Thus, upon hearing Song Meng’s last sentence, Han Li bitterly laughed once; no matter what, he did not dare to easily agree to what was being discussed!

However, Han Li was very interested in Li Huayuan and the group of guests with him.

After all, for Song Meng to use such respectful words meant that the people in the room most likely were Core Formation cultivators. But just when he wanted to gather some information from Song Meng, the tightly-shut door suddenly opened, and a few male and female cultivators walked out from inside.

Li Huayuan and his wife followed closely behind, clasping their hands and sending them out.

As expected, they were all Core Formation cultivators! Han Li clearly saw that of the four men and three women, their cultivation bases were unfathomably deep!

He and Song Meng did not dare to block the road and hurriedly split, one left, one right, helplessly standing to the side!

Li Huayuan instantly saw Han Li, but he only gave a light smile before paying no further attention to him. The other cultivators naturally also glanced at Han Li, but most of them ignored him after that. After all, a mid Foundation Establishment cultivator was truly nothing worth taking note of.

However, a slender and perfectly figured female cultivator with a veil over her face suddenly stopped after her gaze swept over Han Li, her figure shaking. At the same time, a strange, difficult-to-discern light flashed across a pair of bright eyes.

“Has Celestial Nangong met this lowly disciple before?”

Upon noticing this female cultivator’s strange behavior, the other cultivators couldn’t help but glance at this woman somewhat strangely; even more, Li Huayuan opened his mouth to ask this, feeling even more shocked.

As soon as the words “Celestial Nangong” reached Han Li’s ears, Han Li’s heart jumped.[2] A surge of indistinct emotions rampaged through his heart.[3]

Although he forcefully maintained his expression, he still couldn’t help but glance at this female cultivator.

[1]. In Chapter 165: Night Encounter, Junior Martial Sister Chen was attacked by Senior Martial Brother Lu. Junior Martial Sister Chen was saved by Han Li resulting in Han Li acquiring two Foundation Establishment Pills.

[Back]

[2]. In Chapter 208: Joyous Meeting, Han Li slayed the Inky Flood Dragon with the help of Celestial Nangong. The Flood Dragon released an aphrodisiac upon death, leading to a passionate night.

[Back]

[3]. In Chinese the five flavors 五味 are: spicy, salty, sour, sweet, and bitter. Basically, that earlier phrase meant his heart was in emotional turmoil.

[Back]

Chapter 276: Taking Action

“Close friend? Could it be the individual whom fellow Daoist wanted to save with the spirit herb?” Han Li seemed to have casually asked this, but he was inwardly very happy. He had been bitterly worried that he wouldn’t be able to raise the subject of that formation master by Qi Yunxiao’s side. He naturally couldn’t let this golden opportunity slip by.

Qi Yunxiao was stunned when Han Li asked this question and was a bit hesitant.

But soon after, he thought of something and made up his mind, nodding his head, “Senior is not wrong. This spirit tea was made this one’s close friend. As for that previous matter, it was thanks to medicine created from Senior’s thousand year-old spirit herb that my friend’s life was saved. However, although her life had been saved, her injury is recovering extremely slowly. Therefore.... Therefore, this Junior wants to shamelessly ask Senior if he has another thousand year-old spirit herb. Even if it isn’t a thousand year-old spirit herb, as long as it’s seven or eight hundred years old, it would fulfill my wish for my close friend to fully recover. This one is willing to promise all sorts of formation flags in exchange for the spirit herb.”

After that was said, Qi Yunxiao had a face full of anticipation and was attentively staring at Han Li.

When Han Li heard Qi Yunxiao’s words, he was slightly surprised, but his heart soon relaxed. Since the other party still sought something from Han Li, it seemed he would naturally succeed in his request for the other party to repair the transportation formation.

However, his face naturally wore an awkward expression; he would make Qi Yunxiao feel like he would owe Han Li a favor!

With this thought, Han Li muttered to himself for a moment. After a long moment later, he said with reluctance, “This one does have such a spirit herb on hand. However, this one intended to refine a medicine pill with it and use it. This is truly....”

Although Han Li didn’t finish his sentence, the hesitant expression on his face was enough for Qi Yunxiao to imagine the difficulty of this matter.

After all, Qi Yunxiao should clearly know what refining a top-grade medicine pill signified to a cultivator.

When Qi Yunxiao first heard Han Li had such a medicinal herb on hand, he immediately revealed an appearance of wild happiness. However, when he heard the words that followed, his expression became extremely apprehensive. Without even waiting for Han Li to finish his sentence, he immediately said with a half-pleading tone, “Junior knows that making Senior Han Li give a spirit herb is a bit forceful. However, this one truly feels great anguish from seeing his dear friend suffering day after day! So long as Senior agrees to cede the spirit herb, this one will allow Senior to chose from this one’s formation establishment magic tools as he wishes. Even if Senior wishes to take them all, Junior will have no complaints.”

When Han Li heard the other party’s words, his heart was greatly moved.

Even if this Qi Yunxiao’s formation establishment magic tools weren’t as abnormal as the “Five Elements Reversal Formation”, they were sure to be rarely-seen quality goods. If he had several more sets on hand, he would be able to increase his defenses by no small amount. Even better were the formation spells with extremely powerful offensive capabilities; if he could trap strong enemies within the formations, it would also be another incisive method of attack.

However, the main objective of this trip was to have the other party restore the damaged transportation formation. If he were to take a few formation establishment magic tools, then this matter couldn’t be fulfilled, and if he asked for too much, he would give the other party the impression that his greed was insatiable. Han Li did not currently wish for these two to become hostile towards him.

After Han Li pondered about this, he intended to refuse the other party’s exchange and raise the matter about the transportation formation. But at this moment, the flustered yell of a young woman suddenly came from outside.

“Young Master Qi, it’s bad! My clan’s young madam has encountered mishap! Please save my clan’s young madam!”

Qi Yunxiao’s face immediately changed once the voice penetrated the walls.

He hastily stood and left the room without even said anything to his guest, Han Li. The shopkeep standing to the side similarly ran out the room with a panicked and pale face.

Han Li raised his eyebrows, but his expression didn’t change. Still, he felt puzzled and slowly walked out with hands behind his back.

Outside the room, Qi Yunxiao and the shopkeep were attentively and nervously listening to a talking woman who appeared eighteen or nineteen years old.

This girl was pretty and had fair skin. As she was talking about something, she had an anxious appearance. She immediately shut her mouth with fright when she saw a stranger, Han Li, walk out of the room. An expression of vigilance flashed from her eyes.

Seeing this, Han Li gave a smile without paying it any mind and stood still. He didn’t walk any further.

But after Qi Yunxiao turned to look at Han Li, it appeared as he had grasped life-saving medicine and flew to Han Li’s side. He excitedly pleaded to him, “Senior, this one’s close friend is currently being restrained by cultivators with malicious intent. Right now, only Senior can save her. So long as Senior agrees to take action, this Junior will be sure to give heavy payment as equivalent thanks!”

“Could Daoist Friend Qi please give me a few details? Is the young woman spoke of, your dear friend, the formation spell master?” Han Li wrinkled his brow, asking with some surprise.

“That’s right! The Five Elements Reversal Formation establishment magic tools that Senior previously used were jointly refined by this one and that young lady!” Qi Yunxiao hastily said as he looked at Han Li with impatience.

It was at this moment that the pretty woman then discovered that she was incapable of seeing how deep Han Li’s cultivation was even with her cultivation base at the fifth layer of Qi Condensation. This caused her to open her mouth in shock and then look at Han Li with fear.

Han Li then turned his body to the woman and said with a deep voice, “Could this young woman explain it once more? I want to know the whole story!”

Although Han Li knew this was the best opportunity to gain favor, he needed to know the enemy’s strength and numbers. He didn’t wish to fail and be in need of rescue himself.

“.... Oh! It’s like this. Today, the young lady and I arrived somewhere nearby...” When the pretty woman saw Han Li ask her this, she couldn’t help but repeat the story once through in a fluster.

Originally, this young woman’s young madam had ran out of high-quality tea leaves to refine into spirit tea. As per previous custom, she went to the nearby Jade Cloud Mountain to pick a few, leaves, but she unexpectedly ran into a group of male Qi Condensation cultivators. When the master and servant saw so many cultivators appear, they already felt something was wrong and intended to immediately leave the mountain.

But who would have thought that there was a person from these group of cultivators who would recognize one of the women as a formation spell master who had set up a formation spell for some small clan. This person immediately informed this matter to his colleagues; As a result, this group was filled with evil intent and intended to capture this woman alive, forcing her to give them her knowledge of formation spells.

However, the young madam was exceptionally quick-witted and didn’t wait for the opponent to act, having her servant rush off the mountain to escape. But as she herself was halfway down the mountain, she discovered people relentlessly pursuing her. They were growing increasingly closer and would soon overtake and capture her.

Without a better option, she could only use the formation flags she had on hand to arrange a simple formation spell in the middle of the forest, protecting herself. Then she had this servant rush towards Qi Yunxiao in order to call for help.

As Han Li heard the other party’s account, he muttered to himself indecisively.

According to the young woman, the enemy consisted of only seven or eight Qi Condensation disciples. He no longer had any qualms and quickly decided that he must help them.

With this thought, Han Li nodded his head and said, “We’ll follow the lead of this young lady!”

After saying this, under Qi Yunxiao’s grateful gaze, Han Li threw out his sleeve, and a small white boat appeared, enlarging itself before everyone’s eyes.

“Everyone, get onboard! We must save someone from danger. Although this magic tool is a bit small, it flies extremely fast and will have no problem flying with four or five people.” Han Li’s body flashed and reappeared in front of the small boat. He then turned his head and said this to the others.

Qi Yunxiao and the young woman came to a sudden realization and boarded the small boat. But when the shopkeep also thought to board it, Qi Yunxiao stopped him and said, “Uncle Lin, your cultivation is far too low. If you were to go, there would be many dangers. Please stay here! We will immediately return after we save her!”

When the shopkeep heard this, he appeared hesitant. But he knew that Qi Yunxiao meant him well, so he remained with some slight unwillingness.

Thus, Han Li and the others flew on the small boat and turned into a streak of white light, disappearing off the edge of the horizon.

Han Li quickly flew the Divine Wind Boat south with all his strength. Its quick speed caused the two passengers to keep their eyes wide open from surprise. Not long after, they arrived above a besieged formation spell in a forest.

At this moment, there were seven or eight people viciously attacking the spell formation with magic tools. It seemed the layer of faint azure light that covered the forest had weakened to the point of near destruction.

When Qi Yunxiao saw this, his eyes grew red, and he immediately wanted to jump off. However, Han Li held him still and insipidly said to him, “Don’t rush! It seems the magic tools they are using aren’t bad. From this alone, they seem to be from some cultivation clan. Since they knew this young lady was a formation spell master, even if you were to repel them here, they would continue to tangle with you in the future. It would be better for me to help you eliminate them cleanly and wipe away the problem entirely!”

When Qi Yunxiao heard that these people would unceasingly tangle with him in the future, he couldn’t help but angrily nod his head.

When Han Li saw this, he faintly smiled and then looked at the unknowing cultivators below; cold light flashed from his eyes.

He suddenly raised his two hands, and two streaks of black light and six streaks of yellow light flew out. In the blink of an eye, they arrived in front of these cultivators and easily encircled the frightened assailants. They all fell to the floor one by one, killed by Han Li instantly.

Qi Yunxiao and that maid looked at the scene, overwhelmed with shock. Although they knew the difference between Qi Condensation and Foundation Establishment cultivators was certain to be great, they did not think at all that Han Li would be able to quickly kill so many people with ease. It should be known that the highest cultivation base among these men was the twelfth layer. Qi Yunxiao himself was only at the ninth layer.

Han Li didn’t pay any attention to these two’s gazes of reverence and had the flying magic tool descend.

Without waiting for the Divine Wind Boat to completely touch the ground, Qi Yunxiao hastily and impatiently leaped off, rushing into the forest. He yelled with great nervousness, “Yin’er! Are you alright! The enemies have all died! You can come out now!”

Chapter 278: Half-Year Appointment

Being the one involved, Xin Ruyin started to become similarly excited!

After all, this regarded a complete recovery from her long-lasting affliction. However, her expression changed from dark to bright several times. She hesitated and said while biting her red lips, “What sort of matter does Senior wish for Junior to help with? Please do not hesitate to say! As long as it doesn’t violate my conscious and morality, this young woman will certainly agree!”

When Xin Ruyin said this and looked at Han Li with clear eyes, she feared Han Li would be unable to answer to her request.

Seeing this woman’s cautiousness, Han Li couldn’t help but give a knowing smile.

This reminded him of his own circumstances at the beginning of his journey of cultivation. He had also been very cautious and feared that treading the wrong path would result in his death.

“Fellow Daoist Xin doesn’t need to be so nervous. I only want fellow Daoist to restore a formation spell. So long as you are able to restore it, I will offer you the spirit herb!” Han Li soon answered with a calm expression. He didn’t evade her straight gaze, but rather met it with a magnanimous gaze.

After Xin Ruyin heard this, she was a bit skeptical.

She then let out a breath and relaxed, blossoming a lovely appearance. She said, “If it is truly a matter of restoration, then it will be no problem! Ruyin will do all she can to restore it. Senior, please be at ease.”

The girl’s originally neutral expression suddenly became a clear and bright smile. Han Li couldn’t help but be stunned by the beauty of her charm! There was no need to mention that her long-time admirer, Qi Yunxiao, had long since fallen into a spell of imbecility from the smile and was incapable of waking himself.

When Xin Ruyin saw the strangeness of Han Li’s gaze, she couldn’t help blush a bit more, causing her charm to become even more lovely.

At this moment, Han Li hurriedly restrained his previously out-of-control mind and continued, “Truthfully speaking, although this one knows that Fellow Daoist Yin’s research into formation spells is certainly deep, I don’t know if it can truly be repaired. Also, the original formation is incapable of being moved, thus this one made a copy of its designs. I hope fellow Daoist will be able to look at the designs and repair it!”

With this said, Han Li took out the jade slip from his storage pouch and handed it over to Xin Ruyin. She immediately injected her consciousness into it with great curiosity.

After examining it, she involuntarily cried out from shock, “Ancient transportation formation?!”

When Han Li heard her shout, the biggest worry in his heart disappeared without a trace!

‘As expected, that transportation formation was an ancient transportation formation. Now, let's see if this woman can repair it.’

As Han Li thought this, he couldn’t help but pay close attention to Xin Yurin’s facial expression, afraid that she would reveal an expression of embarrassment!

After Qi Yunxiao heard the words “ancient transportation formation”, his face became filled with amazement, and his eyes widened from astonishment.

After no less than the time it took for an incense stick to burn had passed, Xin Ruyin took a long stretch and eventually withdrew her consciousness from the jade slip. Then she lowered her head and entered deep contemplation for a moment before raising her elegant head, earnestly saying to Han Li, “This is a genuine ancient transportation formation. Someone at my level normally wouldn’t be able to repair a completely ruined ancient transportation formation, but the damage on this formation is quite small, mainly at one small corner. Fortunately, I’m familiar with this specific portion of the formation spell, having studied a few ancient formation spells. As a result, I should have a good chance to restore this ancient transportation formation.”

When Han Li heard those words, his naturally filled with happiness, but her following words were a devastating blow.

“However, these ancient spell formations are rarely used, and my research into them isn’t very deep. Thus, Senior must give me some time so I can completely restore the design of the ancient transportation formation in the jade slip!” Xin Ruyin continued with a face of slight embarrassment.

“Of course. How long does Fellow Daoist Xin think it will take? I will certainly return by then.” After Han Li thought for a moment, he agreed.

“Even though I only studied ancient formations for a short time, half a year should be enough!” Xin Ruyin said without the slightest of hesitation. It seems she had come up with an estimate earlier.

“That’s fine. After half a year, I will come to pick up the restored design. I hope young lady Xin will not disappoint me!” When Han Li heard this, he nodded his head with a faint smile.

At this moment, Han Li formally entrusted the restoration of the ancient transportation formation to this female formation spell master, Xin Ruyin. Then he spent the afternoon further chatting with Qi Yunxiao and company before bidding his farewell.

Before departure, Han Li urged the two to be a bit more careful. It would be best to move farther away. After all, there would certainly be people sent to track down the killers of that group of cultivations. Since they were in the vicinity, they would truly be too easy to discover.

When Han Li said this, Qi Yunxiao and Xin Ruyin took a look at each other and displayed an appearance of embarrassment. They declined to comment on Han Li’s suggestion to change residence.

Although Han Li felt baffled and worried, he didn’t inconvenience them with further words and hurriedly flew his magic tool to the State of Yue.

……

The capital city of the State of Yue, the renowned Yuejing![1]

Not only was it the largest city of the State of Yue, it also happened to be located at the very center of the country. Its roads led in every direction, making it the heart of the entire nation’s economic trade.

Naturally, the land of such a city had long been completely occupied. Not only was the price of housing several times greater than that of other cities, but there were also many individuals willing to pay this price but none willing to sell!

After all, living in Yuejing itself was a symbol of one’s status.

Also, the entire city of Yuejing was divided into four districts: north, south, east, west.

The imperial city was located in the north district. Naturally, only members of the royal family were permitted to live there. Across the city was the south district, home of bureaucrats and officials of all ranks. So long as one monotonically spent half their time on duty, they would have the qualifications to live there. If no one in a household hold an official’s position, that household would naturally be forced to move to another district!

[1]. in Yuejing越京, 越 Yue is the name of the country and 京 jing means the capital of the country. So the name of the city literally means the capital city of Yue.

[Back]

Chapter 279: The Great Wealthy Qin Residence

Within the city of Yuejing, the south district was distinctly different from the west district.

The west district’s tall and great residences were actually jaggedly arranged flat rooms. Those who lived there were all lower-class workers with odd jobs, small peddlers and merchants, and other impoverished people. Naturally, a portion were loafers who came from other districts aftering being kicked out of their household.

Far and away from the west region, the rich merchant households existed in the east district.

Although these households didn’t have anyone working in the bureaucracy and couldn’t live in the south district, their grand residence and courtyards were more magnificent than any other. None of them spared their great wealth in order to bring their households name to fame, suppressing other nearby great families and putting themselves on top.

Naturally, there were a few famous households that the others nearby fundamentality couldn’t compete against. Not only was the amount of land they owned great, but also their riches and prestige far exceeded the others’. The people who lived in these households were merchants that were beyond extremely wealthy

In a corner of the east district, such an extremely rich and powerful household existed, the Qin Residence.

Their residence spanned over one and a half acres. If one knew exactly how much land cost in Yuejing, one would be speechless for a long while.

Not only was the Qin Clan extremely wealthy, but they also controlled a fourth of the copper mines in the State of Yue. Furthermore, it was said that their clan master possessed remarkable ability and had officials that specifically spoke on their behalf in the royal court.

As such, even the servants of this great and noble household held great confidence, having more sway in their household than other servants.

The gatekeeper of the Qin Residence, Qin Gui, also thought as such.

Every time someone came to the Qin Residence requesting to meet with the clan master, regardless of their identity or background, even if they were a bureaucrat, they were always completely polite towards even a low servant of the Qin Clan and didn’t dare to offend them in the slightest.

As time passed, this caused Qin Gui to feel as if he himself were superior.

Thus, every time someone sought to pay respects and meet someone from the Qin Clan, their gifts naturally couldn’t be small. Otherwise, Qin Gui wouldn’t look upon them favorably; he might even wait three or four days before reporting their presence to a superior.

Naturally, if a great character knocked on their door, Qin Gui would act in accordance to custom, complete loyal subservience.

Towards those young masters and young madams who entered and left the estate frequently, he would eagerly and attentively be at their beck and call.

Although many of the masters whom Qin Gui served weren’t completely satisfied with him, word spread recently that he would be promoted to become an external steward and would go out to take control of some business. After Qin Gui heard this, he became increasingly happy, and in the following days, he felt that his steps were as light as a feather.

Right now, Qin Gui was arrogantly sitting a stool and lying in a shady, cool spot against the gate. This morning, the clan master had left to discuss some business. The several young masters and young madams had already left with their noble friends to take a stroll at Chongshan Temple. Currently, apart from the madams within the estate, only the widowed young madam Biao remained.

This caused to him let out a breath of relaxation, glad of the chance to take a break.

When Qin Gui was half asleep with a light cool wind blowing against them, he suddenly heard the shy voice of a male youth in front of him.

“Excuse me, is this the Qin Residence?”

Just as Qin Gui was about to fall asleep, this voice had disturbed him and woken him up. He felt extremely wronged and couldn’t help but loudly yell with great anger while his eyes remained closed, “Who are you shouting to! Are you wailing at a funeral! Can’t you see that the great Gui is lying down!”

With that said, Qin Gui was completely unwilling to open his eyes to take a look. His face wore an extremely resentful expression.

From the other party’s timid voice, he felt that the owner of the voice was but a minor character who dared to treat him so imprudently.

Qin Gui eventually had a clear look at the person before him, a coarsely-dressed man who appeared about twenty-four years old. He had an extremely ordinary appearance and had an early smell coming from his body. He was clearly one of those country bumpkins[1] that had just arrived from the countryside!

Seeing this, Qin Gui became increasingly arrogant.

He sat up from his chair, and without saying anything further, he began showering down admonishments nonstop. It was as if disturbing the great Qin Gui’s rest was a severe and unforgivable sort of crime!

While he was reprimanding the newcomer, Qin Gui’s saliva splattered all around and continued spraying there for more than the time it took to make a cup of tea. This rustic youth appeared as if he hadn’t understood the great Qin Gui and appeared to at a loss for words. He could only listen to Qin Gui’s tirade with a foolish expression!

After a long while, Qin Gui clearly vented the fiery resentment within him before reluctantly stopping his verbal attack.

Soon after, he gave the youth a slanted look. It seemed as if he wanted to say something to him. He then casually asked, “What are you doing at our Qin Residence? We aren’t lacking laborers or servants. Hurry up and leave! The servants at this residence aren’t the same as other servants! We won’t take in those with muddy origins. Come back after you find a backer!”

Relying on his past experiences, Qin Gui immediately concluded this youth whose clothes still stunk of dirt was certainly someone who wildly imagined to work at the Qin Residence!

“I’m not looking for work... Qin Yan is my uncle. My family told me to deliver this letter to Uncle Qin!” The youth had recovered from the tempest of verbal abuse. After hearing Qin Gui’s words, he took out a wrinkled letter from his bosom and stuttered, giving Qin Gui an explanation.

“What? The lord is your uncle!”

Qin Gui had felt his mouth go dry, so he went to go take a few gulps from a nearby teapot. But when he immediately heard the youth’s words, he spit out a mouthful of tea from shock and asked this with a face pale from fright.

“This... I also don’t know. But my family had me address him as Uncle Qin!” The youth shook his head with a somewhat embarrassed appearance.

However at this moment, Qin Gui no longer dared to easily mock him. If this person truly had some relation to his own lord, then nothing good would come out of it.

Then after a moment of hesitation, he carefully asked, “That letter, could you let this one take a look at it? Please be at ease, esteemed sir. This one only wants to look at the surface of the letter. He doesn’t dare to tear it open!”

When the youth heard what Qin Gui said, he unexpectedly agreed, nodding his head. As he handed it over, he muttered something, “I originally wanted to hand this letter to you so you could quickly hand it over to Uncle Qin!”

Qin Gui took the extremely wrinkled letter and immediately looked at it several times.

Ordinary servants normally wouldn’t be able to read, but during Qin Gui’s childhood, he had spent half a year in a private school and was actually literate. As such, the much desired duty as gatekeeper fell upon him.

“To be personally opened by Honorable Nephew Qin Yan!”

These large pitch-black words on the letter caused Qin Gui’s heart to beat wildly. From their tone, it seemed the letter was written by his own lord’s senior.

WIth this thought, Qin Gui’s face immediately changed. With great effort, he squeezed out a faint smile and said to the youth, “Young Master, our clan’s lord is not here right now, but his wives are within. Would you like to pass this letter onto his wives?” Qin Gui couldn’t help but greatly change his attitude and immediately upgrade the youth’s title.

“This won’t do! This letter must be personally opened by Uncle Qin!” After the youth hesitate for a moment, he resolutely shook his head.

“So it’s like that. Then should I first make a report to the madams and see how they respond to your esteemed self?”

Qin Gui didn’t dare to let the youth leave. If this were an important matter and he were the one to interfere, then great misfortune would come around to meet him. But if he handed this matter over to the madams, then it wouldn’t matter what he did; as a long-time servant, he had his own scheming.

The youth readily agreed.

After Qin Gui let out a breath of relief, he hastily went to call for a passing servant to help him watch the youth and ran into the residence.

When other servants came across him and saw that he was running as if his buttocks were on fire, they were a bit shocked.

Qin Gui immediately ran to the back court and said a few words to the head maid there before returning to the entrance to deliver a response with relief.

Having returned to the entrance, Qin Gui hastily said a few words to the youth with a smile. A young attractive maid ran over.

When she arrived in front of the two, she took several curious glances at the completely rustic youth and relayed a madam’s reply. The youth would first rest in a side room and wait for the return of the lord before his identity was judged to be true or false. After all, there were a great many members of the Qin Residence; he could by the child of a senior’s concubine that came knocking on their door!

Since the higher ups had already dealt with this issue, Qin Gui felt at ease and continued to guard the main gate.

That young maid then brought the youth to wait at a guest room for the time being.

On the way, several people saw the youth’s rustic appearance and glanced at him several times in surprise, causing the youth to greatly feel uneasy. He simply lowered his head and continued following while looking the young servant girl’s back.

When the maid turned her head and saw the youth’s strange behavior, she couldn’t help but chuckle. She looked several at the man with beaming smiles, finding it quite entertaining.

When a side room in the front wing was arranged for the youth, the young maid repeatedly warned the youth to not run around and returned back to report while giggling.

After the young maid left the room, the youth with the originally clumsy appearance suddenly straightened his back, and the foolish dullness in his eyes could no longer be seen. This person seemed to appear confident and at ease. The slightest trace of his rusticness could no longer be seen.

“I truly did not think this Qin Clan was actually so well-known! It’s impossible for the Devil Dao to let such an obvious target pass by.” The youth took a look outside the room and slightly wrinkled his brow, muttering a few words to himself.

Han Li had exhausted himself by flying at top speed for over ten days before finally arriving at Yuejing. The Qin Residence was the target Li Huayuan requested Han Li to protect.

However, when Han LI thought of the identity Li Huayuan arranged from him, he couldn’t help but feel greatly gloomy.

In the letter, Li Huayuan had the Qin Clan Master arrange the identity of a Qin Clan side branch descendant, causing Han Li to play a destitute relative from the countryside. This was to fool the Qin Residence so he could remain for a long time.

Although Han Li disliked the identity of being a destitute youngster from the countryside, his disguise didn’t require any effort. After all, Han Li was the genuine child of peasant family of some remote countryside village. Thus, he didn’t need to put much effort to closely resemble the right tone and mannerisms.

After Han Li shut off the room, he meditated and refined Qi on the bed. He hoped that while he protected the Qin Residence, he would be able to slightly progress his own cultivation.

It was already evening by the time Han Li completed a cycle of cultivation. At this moment, someone finally knocked on the door.

Han Li’s spirit shook, and the expression on his face soon completely vanished. He immediately resumed the appearance of the foolish rustic youngster.

Once he opened the door, he saw a servant standing before him.

“My clan’s lord has returned. The madams are currently calling for you. Follow me!” The servant said to Han Li with no trace of politeness. He then turned around and left. It seems Han Li wasn’t worthy enough for the servant to put him in his eyes.

This was of no surprise. The gatekeeper Qin Gui was the same.

As a madam’s trusted aide, he had seen many destitute relatives of the Qin Residence arrive every year like an autumn wind. Naturally, he didn’t particularly pay them much mind.

This person thought was it was most likely the lord would meet with this country bumpkin, give him some silver, and then send him on his way. He basically wouldn’t stay in this residence for much longer!

Han Li sincerely agreed and followed this person out of the side room, heading straight towards the Qin Residence’s receiving hall.

At this moment, there was a graceful and magnificent madam who appeared over forty years old. She was sitting next to the Qin Clan Master Qin Yan and talking about Han Li’s arrival.

“Since he dares to come knocking on our door with a letter, he most likely isn’t a fake! It seems he was truly sent from a clan senior to come visit us.”

“Let us see what request he has in the end. If it isn’t excessive, then we will completely satisfy it! Don’t snobbishly cast out this branch clan member and soil our reputation. We cannot lose face because of this.”

Qin Yan was over fifty years old, but because he had took care of his health well, he appeared only forty years old, not elderly in the slightest. After he drank a gulp of swallow nest tea and moistened his throat, he said this leisurely.

[1]. TL Note: the word meaning country side bumpkin is actually earth steam bun 土包子, heh; he's a steambun(idiot) that came from the countryside.

[Back]

Chapter 281: The Qin Residence and Young Madam Biao

After two hours had passed, Han Li left the secret room with Qin Yan, once again returning to his country bumpkin appearance.

Having returned to the guest room, the Qin Clan Master looked at his third wife and immediately ordered them to arrange a clean room in the back of the residence as Honorable Nephew Han would be staying with them for an extended time.

The surface reason was plain. As his Senior, the lord wanted to cultivate this Junior and pay back the kindness that the boy’s elders had bestowed upon him.

When the third wife saw this, her jaw dropped, but she didn’t say any words of opposition!

When the exceedingly shrewd woman clearly heard this, she knew that Qin Yan already made his decision and wouldn’t change his mind. Furthermore, she could perceive that this Honorable Nephew Han had something suspicious going on with her lord husband.

But since Qin Yan didn’t tell any of the particulars, she naturally wouldn’t perform any actions that would provoke disfavor.

However, she had guessed with a bit of wild imagination that since he was so serious toward this Honorable Nephew Han, it was possible that when Qin Yan was young, he had left an illegitimate child while he was out fondling flowers and trampling grass. How else could he turn so pale from reading the letter and be so cordial right after?

The more the lively-minded third wife thought of this, the greater she felt this to be true. She felt a bit unhappy, but she appeared as if nothing happened and acted increasingly familiar toward Han Li.

As such, under Lord Qin’s repeated suggestions, Han Li followed Qin Ping to see his residence until he was fully satisfied.

This time, Qin Ping’s expression wasn’t as rigid as before. Instead, his face wore a smile as he continuously addressed him as “Young Master Han”. He had selectively forgotten his previously cold behavior.

Although Han Li appeared overwhelmed by a superior’s favor, he secretly sighed to this mortal servant. His art of changing in the direction of the blowing wind was truly superb. He was unexpectedly able to switch from arrogance to deference without the slightest appearance of embarrassment.

He didn’t know whether to say that his face was thick-skinned or if he was long accustomed to such events.

Soon after Qin Ping brought Han Li on a small path to the back of the residence. They arrived at a peaceful three-room courtyard.

The exquisite and refined surroundings were exceptionally peaceful, causing Han Li to inwardly nod his head; it was very much to his liking.

It seems this Qin Yan had gone through quite a bit of thought to give him such a suitable dwelling.

“Young Master Han, this is your residence! This is the best courtyard within the Qin Residence. If someone were not the lord’s valued guests, they basically wouldn’t be allowed to live here!” After Qin Ping let Han Li into the courtyard, he fawningly gave Han Li an explanation.

Han Li scratched his head and naively grinned. He repeatedly giggled as if he didn’t know what to say.

With great tact, Qin Ping switched to a different subject, “Young Master Han hasn’t eaten dinner yet, no? This servant will go the kitchen and bring you some food. Please wait for a moment!”

With that said, Qin Ping respectfully withdrew from the courtyard and left.

As Han Li saw this person gradually grow farther, he faintly smiled and entered the rooms.

The room’s arrangements greatly matched the environment, each piece of furniture being uniquely elegant.

After he went through it once through, Han Li found it increasingly agreeable. He couldn’t help but think of who arranged the place like this.

That Qin Ping had moved quite quickly! Not long after, a female servant arrived with a large bamboo tray holding food.

Smelling the fragrant scent of food, Han Li, who had fasted for several years, felt a bit ravenous and impolitely swept clear the several delicate dishes with a bowl of rice.

In the end, Qin Ping saw what remained of the meal and naturally found it a bit funny. But his appearance still remained respectful as he invited Han Li to the hall. Lord Qin wanted to introduce Han Li to the members of the Qin Residence.

……

When Han Li arrived at the guest hall for the second time, it wasn’t just Qin Yan and the Third Madam. There were also twenty to thirty men and women sitting and standing about.

When Qin Yan called out Han Li to sit beside him with great familiarity, a few of the older members within the hall were surprised, but the others didn’t react. The young madams and lords of the Qin Clan, however, were unable to keep their calm. The more favored young master immediately asked with dissatisfaction:

“Grandfather, who is this brother? Us brothers and sisters have never seen him before; could you have called us here because of this person?”

Qin Yan naturally heard the unhappiness in his grandson’s voice, but he didn’t give him any face, instead glaring at him before saying coldly:

“Get back! Do you have the right to speak in this place? What ‘this person’, ‘that person’! This is Han Li, my Honorable Nephew Han. His elder has bestowed our Qin clan with great favor during a time of life and death. You are forbidden from being disrespectful to him!”

This sentence from Qin Yan instantly caused everyone in the room apart from his third wife to cause a commotion.

Various conjectures and curious gazes simultaneously landed on Han Li, who wore a perfect unsettled appearance, shifting around a few times as if needles were being poked into his rear.

As for the Qin Clan’s young master, he silently retreated, his face alternating between frightened red and embarrassed red.

He absolutely did not expect that Qin Yan, who normally doted on him, would now speak so mercilessly towards him. This caused him to lose a lot of face in front of so many brothers and sisters!

Because of this matter, this young master naturally would not have any goodwill towards Han Li! Of course, he was not so naive that he would make any ill-intentioned moves towards Han Li, especially after Qin Yan had given such orders.

After all, it seemed like this country bumpkin had a very high standing in his grandfather’s heart. He didn’t wish to lose Qin Yan’s favor because of this matter.

With this person set as an example, other people naturally would not make any hostile movements. Instead, many people revealed kind appearances after meeting Han Li’s gaze.

At this time, Qin Yan pointed out and introduced all the people in the room to Han Li with a smile:

“This is my eldest son Qin Zhi, who is currently helping me organize all of the business in Yuejing. He has a pretty good head on him. This is my second son......”

Even as Han Li pretended to wildly nod his head, he secretly memorized every Qin Clan member that Qin Yan introduced; after all, these people were the ones that he needed to protect!

However, this elderly Lord Qin could really procreate; in total, he had five sons and three daughters, and he even had quite a few grandsons and granddaughters.

In their midst, the eldest and second son all seemed to be around thirty years old and even had families. The one who had taken the initiative to ask a question was the eldest son’s second son.

But what was funny was that Qin Yan’s youngest fifth son was only five or six years old, a little child who could only suck his thumb.

When Han Li thought about that sixteen or seventeen year-old youth being forced to call this child with a drippy nose “Fifth Uncle”, he felt that it was quite comical.

As for Qin Yan’s wives, apart from the third wife he had met earlier in the morning, there was another forty year-old or so second wife, as well as seven or eight relatively young concubines.

Qin Yan’s first wife was not in the hall; at the moment, it was said that she was praying to Buddha and abstaining from eating meat. She would no longer come out to see anyone.

Apart from these people, there were two forty year-old or so males; naturally, they were Qin Yan’s second and third younger brothers.

They were each responsible for a portion of the Qin Clan’s business and could be considered the more important members of the Qin Clan. Of course, they likewise had a few sons and daughters in the room, but Han Li only memorized these people’s names, too lazy to pay them any further attention.

After all, the energy he possessed as one person was limited; he could only focus on protecting the people Qin Yan introduced in this room.

“Yi! Where is Young Madam Biao?”

When Qin Yan introduced all the people inside the room once, he suddenly discovered that they were missing a person; he couldn’t help but ask this to his third wife sitting beside him.

“Lord, Young Miss Biao felt that as a widow, it would not be too appropriate for her to meet any outsiders, and thus she didn’t come! Should I go and call for her?” the third wife softly asked. A hesitant expression appeared on her face.

“Oh.” Qin Yan thought for a moment before continuing, “Don’t worry about it, Martial Nephew Han is not an outsider; it’s best if she comes and sees him!”

“Yes, my lord!”

“Little Lian, go quickly and call for the Young Miss Biao; tell her that the lord asked for her to come!”

The third wife indifferently commanded a young maid standing behind her.

“Yes, Madam.” This little maidservant who previously guided Han Li immediately and quickly ran out through a side door with small steps.

At this time, Qin Yan turned his head around and said in a low voice to Han Li:

“There’s one more person who didn’t come, a young woman whom my first wife saved seven or eight years ago while she was visiting her parents.”

“This woman is extremely pitiful. Not only did she lose her memory because she hit her head, her body was covered with wounds. My wife’s character is pretty good, so after treating her and seeing that the girl had no place to go, she had one of her brothers take her in as an adopted daughter, at least providing her with some shelter!”

“However, this woman truly is unlucky. Although she was married to a groom picked by her adoptive father, she was only married for three days before her spouse actually slipped and fell into a river because he was too drunk. It’s reasonable to say that such a young woman would naturally choose to remarry, but this woman actually has the temperament to die chaste and decided to live as a widow for the husband whom she only lived for three days with. This is a hot topic around here, but it has given my wife’s clan a great amount of face!”

“Afterwards, her adoptive father passed away due to sickness. My wife, seeing that the truly pitiful young lady was watching over an empty house all alone, decided to bring her over here to accompany her. In passing, she would also ease this woman’s anxiety!”

As Qin Yan spoke, he sighed incessantly!

Chapter 283: Old Affections

Han Li felt that if he told Mo Fengwu that Mo Caihuan and her mother had disappeared, he would be telling her far too much.

So long as Mo Fengwu knew that her family still lived in this word, that was enough! Whether or not this girl would be able to meet with Mo Caihuan and her mother depended on the world.

Han Li then briefly recounted the events of how he came across Mo Caihuan, causing Fengwu to nearly cry tears of joy.

Mo Fengwu clearly understood that because of Han Li’s identity as an Immortal cultivator, he didn’t need to fabricate such lies to deceive such a weak girl as herself. The reason why the other party was being so polite to her was most likely due to that fated meeting with him so many years ago.

Thus, Mo Fengwu brought her hands together in joy and raised them to her chest, silently praying for a moment before returning to her normal state.

However, her expression toward Han Li was clearly no longer as cold as before.

She clearly realized that in all likelihood, were it not for Han Li’s assistance at Yan Ling Castle, Lady Yan and her daughter would still be in a predicament!

“Many thanks to Young Master Han telling me about the whereabouts of Caihuan and fourth mother.” After Mo Caihuan calmed down, she slowly gave her thanks.

But without waiting for Han Li to reply, she said, “Although my younger sister and her mother are alright, the whereabouts of my eldest sister and my other mothers are unknown. They’ve most likely fallen to some evil scheme. Fengwu cannot help but want to avenge them! However, Fengwu lacks the strength. Can Junior Martial Brother Han help me?”

Mo Fengwu’s words revealed a feeble appearance. A layer of fog covered her eyes in an instant, as if she were about to sob from grief.

When Han Li saw this, he stoked his nose and felt a headache!

He originally thought that if she knew of Mo Caihuan and her mother’s whereabouts, she wouldn’t be so anxious to take revenge. But he didn’t think that Mo Fengwu, whom he hadn’t seen for so many years, would become to strongly attached to this matter!

To tell the truth, killing a Qi Condensation cultivator would be far easier than killing a mortal with status for no reason.

Han Li learned the reason why after he entered Yellow Maple Valley. It turned out that all the many provinces of the State of Yue had been clearly divided between several large clans and the Seven Great Sects.

So long as a powerhouse of great influence had existed for some time within a province, cultivators would secretly pay some attention to them. Some would even be provided assistance from cultivators

Originally, the Lan Province’s Mo Estate and the Hegemon’s Villa were new and developing powers. Thus, they weren’t contacted by cultivators. Else, when Han Li was sent to kill the Hegemon’s Villa’s Ouyang Feitian, how could he have gotten away so easily without being investigated?

However, the Rainbow Sect was different.

That sect had been established more than a hundred years ago and was regarded to be ancient. Thus, the Spirit Beast Mountain of the Seven Great Sects, the controller of the Lan Province, tacitly approved of them. The shadow of Spirit Beast Mountain was most likely looming behind them. As a result, when the Mo Estate fought against them, they suffered great defeat.

As a disciple of Yellow Maple Valley, he couldn’t kill a major mortal leader supported by another sect for no cause or reason; otherwise, he wouldn’t be able to explain himself.

However, with the recent invasion of the State of Yue by the Devil Dao, the secular world had suffered damage. This gave him a good opportunity to act during this time of crisis. With just a bit of carefulness, he shouldn’t have any problems.

As Han Li thought this, he didn’t expose any emotions. Instead, he stood up and paced back and forth within the room.

After another moment of consideration, he gazed at Mo Fengwu’s charming face and calmly said, “Young Lady Fengwu, normally I wouldn't be able to agree to this request since doing so would bring about great problems for me! But the recent circumstances in the cultivation world are quite peculiar. An opportunity might actually arrive. Let’s do it like this! If there’s an opportunity in the future, I will attempt to eliminate the Rainbow Sect’s master. But if it is truly impossible, I hope Young Lady Fengwu will extinguish her thoughts for revenge!”

When Mo Fengwu heard Han Li’s words, she immediately began crying tears of joy. Seeing her bright and beautiful crying beauty caused Han Li to become despondent for a moment.

The year he first saw Mo Fengwu, he was quite moved by that sweet-tempered second young madam of the Mo Estate. To this day, that memory still gave him a kind and warm pleasant feeling, causing him to recall it fondly!

That was the first time he felt feelings of romantic passion!

This small promise was none other than a show of affection!

Despite this thought, his appearance was the same as always. He planned to bury this emotion deeply in his heart and no longer speak of it again.

From Han Li’s agreement, Mo Fengwu eventually looked over to him with happiness.

Her face was filled with appreciation. She didn’t say anything further and walked toward Han Li. Suddenly, she pressed her soft and fragrant lips lightly against his face. Then, with a bashful and slightly perplexed expression, she said, “With Junior Martial Brother Han’s promise, even if you can’t kill that person, Fengwu cannot thank you enough!”

After saying this, the young woman silently donned her cloak and hurriedly left his room.

Han Li touched the spot on his face where he had been kissed with an odd expression. Not long after, he held his chin with a single hand and sunk into deep thought for a very long time.

……

At daybreak on the second day, Han Li woke up from Qi refining meditation and thought of the events that happened last night. He couldn’t help but inwardly sigh. If Mo Fengwu also possessed spiritual roots, he would definitely introduce her to Yellow Maple Valley and cultivate the Great Dao as her Dao Companion.

With this thought, Han Li washed his face and walked out of the room.

He intended to become familiar with the layout of the Qin Residence and then further consider his other matters.

But he didn’t think that just as he walked out, he would discover the smiling Qin Ping in the courtyard.

Without waiting for Han Li’s astonished inquiries, he quickly stepped forward and explained, “This one was ordered by Lord Qin to serve as Young Master’s personal servant for the time being. In the future, if Young Master Han requires any errands to be done, do not hesitate to tell me.”

As Qin Ping spoke to Han Li, his expression was respectful and excited.

His thoughts were quite simple. Although this Young Master Han came from a small region and people wouldn’t see him as very bright, this person was at the center of the lord’s eye and held the lord’s complete favor.

Besides, if he served this Young Master well, perhaps he might also invite the lord’s favor!

As Qin Ping thought this and made his own selfish calculations, he constantly looked down at this young country bumpkin master with disdain, especially when he first heard he was to be his servant!

Qin Ping had already been told by a madam’s maid that this was most likely to be the lord’s illegitimate child. So long as the lord lived, who would dare to treat this young master unfairly? Also, how long he would follow Young Master Han was a matter that would depend on how the tides changed.

This would raise his position far faster than running errands for the third madam!

Han Li naturally didn’t know of this person’s true thoughts, instead feeling only that Qin Ping conducted himself in accordance to Qin Yan’s wishes. He knew he was unfamiliar toward Yuejing and the Qin Residence, so having this person immediately come to guide him was quite timely!

Just as Han Li thought this, he couldn’t help but reveal a smile. Then he bluntly said to Qin Ping, “I haven’t yet seen a large portion of these buildings, so I want to take a look around. How about you accompany me?”

“Yes, Young Master!”

Given his first assignment, Qin Ping enthusiastically answered.

As such, Han Li had Qin Ping lead the way and strolled around the huge Qin Residence.

Although he spoke of the women's quarters, it wasn’t suitable for Han Li to see them up close. Even so, when people saw them pointing it out from a distance, they didn’t dare to say any gossip. After all, Qin Yan’s previous words affected the entire Qin Residence.

“This is the Second Master Fugui’s courtyard. Apart from the second Lord, his two youngest sons also live there. Neighboring that...”

Qin Ping guided Han Li quite well. Unbeknownst to him, han Li secretly committed every name that Qin Ping told Han Li as well as where each master lived.

But when he spoke of “Young Madam Biao” Mo Fengwu’s residence, Han Li’s mind stirred. He paused and looked at it for quite a long time before turning his head away.

Not a long time after, Han Li finished looking through the Qin Residence once through, but somehow it seemed that Han Li was not yet content.

In the end, he bluntly had Qin Ping bring him out of the Qin Residence and out to a lively place in Yuejing. As they wandered randomly, Qin Ping continued to give him explanations.

...…

The entire morning passed by as they walked through a few scenic spots in Yuejing.

Qin Ping’s originally enthusiastic expression had long disappeared. At this moment, he was limping behind Han Li with a bitter face.

Who would’ve thought that even after walking for so many hours without the slightest amount of rest, he would still be forced to continue to comment and explain without end? Anybody would feel similarly frustrated in this situation.

Qin Ping even went as far as to suspect whether or not he had chosen the wrong master.

Chapter 286: Prince's Residence.

Prince Xin’s Residence actually wasn’t in the imperial city. Instead, it was constructed in the south district. After Han Li and company sat in a carriage for two hours, they eventually arrived at a certain street.

The architectural styles of the south region and the Qin Residence were clearly different. Most of the buildings here were constructed to standard and template.

How great an official’s position was, meaning how high they were in that position, could be clearly told by the size and style of their residence.

All of the officials’ residences were located at this district. The strict following of feudal rank and elevation strictly divided the officials. Nobody here dared to alter these buildings as they wished, else they would break a law and invite punishment.

As a relative of the King, Prince Xin possessed royal status, so naturally his residence was one of the best in the south district.

The mansion residence’s area was larger than the Qin Residence by about a half. However, this was balanced by huge residential rooms.

When the carriage to Prince Xin’s residence stopped, Han Li took a look at the mansion residence and immediately felt that the mortal world was thriving in wealth.

The residence’s gate was over fifteen meters tall and over ten meters wide. Thickly wrapped with yellow copper, it was embedded with several tens of huge nails, appearing quite luxurious and imposing.

In addition, there were two ten-meter stone platforms to the sides of the gate, each with a fierce azure lion statue. They were each sparklingly polished through its entire body, so bright they were hard to look at.

But what awed people the most from Prince Xin’s residence were the sixteen neatly armored palace guards standing on the steps outside the gate. Prince Xin had borrowed these guards from the imperial city barracks to prevent any mishap from happening.

The steward of Prince Xin’s estate was a small old man. In the place of the host, Prince Xin, he was on the steps greeting every new guest with a smile across his face. He didn’t dare to neglect even a single guest.

At this moment, several tens of carriages of various sizes had stopped in front of the residence’s gate, occupying nearly all of the empty space in front of the mansion.

In front of the huge azure stone platforms, five or six guests who had yet to enter the residence were exchanging greetings. Their clothes were magnificent, their movements elegant; it seemed their status was not low.

Seeing this, Qin Yan straightened his clothes and over-cautiously stepped off the carriage.

After a diligent glance in every direction to ensure there were no cultivators nearby, Han Li left the carriage at ease.

As for the young masters and madams of the Qin Clan, they left the carriages as soon as they arrived. They stood in front of the mansion, talking cheerfully.

Han Li looked at the guests who were still in front of the steps and discovered that apart from the juniors of the Qin Clan, almost all the other guests had also brought along their children and other such youths.

“Could it be that the so-called Prince Xin deliberately sent all of these invitations to the Prince’s Residence as a pretense to deliberately gather youths to this place?” With this thought, Han Li felt there wasn’t any substantial evidence and took a glance at Qin Yan.

From his wrinkled brow, it seemed Qin Yan was also slightly surprised.

“Grandfather, we’re going in first! The young prince is waiting on us!”

A sixteen to seventeen year-old Qin Clan young master saw that his lord grandfather still hadn’t moved far from his carriage and couldn’t help but gather the courage to say these words under the encouragement of his siblings. He seemed afraid that Qin Yan would criticize him.

“Alright, I got it. Everyone can go in!”

Greatly going against these youngsters’ expectations, Qin Yan nodded and happily agreed. This caused these youths to feel slightly overwhelmed by favor! They couldn’t help but happily walk among their peers.

However, without waiting for Qin Yan to bring these people forward, the steward of the Prince’s residence immediately spotted this group after dealing with another guest. He immediately took the initiative to welcome them with a large smile. Walking over to them, he said very cordially, “Sir Qin, you’ve arrived at last! My Lord Prince talked for several days about how you haven’t come to visit for so long. Please enter as soon as possible! I’m sure the Prince will be very happy to see you, Sir Qin!”

“Hehe, recently, I haven’t...”

This steward of the Prince’s residence wasn’t ordinary. With just a few eloquent words, he was able get everyone who heard him to smile and feel warm inside.

Qin Yan couldn’t help but smile as he chatted with this steward with ease.

However, because there were still guests arriving at the prince’s residence, the steward couldn’t speak much longer with Qin Yan and brought them inside the residence. Then after a few modest words, he quickly went back to the residence’s gate.

Although Han Li remained at Qin Yan’s side, he remained silent. However, the moment when Han Li looked at the back of the steward, suspicion flashed through his eyes.

He didn’t know why, but although Han Li definitely didn’t feel any spiritual power fluctuating from the steward’s body, Han Li suddenly felt his blood run cold when this man drew near, as if a fearsome demonic beast were approaching him. This caused Han Li to feel greatly uneasy!

Although Han Li did not know why he felt this, he had always fully trusted his senses. He immediately added this steward to the list of names he should be wary of.

“Honorable Nephew Han, let’s go! I’ll give you an introduction to a few old friends of mine!” When Qin Yan saw the steward depart, he said this toward Han Li with a smile.

This caused the several Qin Clan members standing next to Qin Yan to immediately grow sour. They all felt that this clan lord of theirs was far too biased.

However, Han Li only smiled to himself. He knew this was truly just an excuse Qin Yan came up with so that Han Li could stay by his side at all times.

They were then led to a large guest hall of Prince Xin’s residence by Qin Yan.

There seemed to be over a hundred people in the hall. But although there seemed to be many guests, since people arrived in groups of two and three, the Qin Residence's party of eight was the same size as parties from three sects.

At this moment, Prince Xin had yet to appear in the hall. It seemed he wouldn’t appear until all his guests were present.

Just as Qin Yan arrived at the entrance of the large hall, he was immediately cordially called out by a few familiar long time friends.

Qin Yan naturally saluted and replied to them all. But when he swept his eyes across the room, he said a few words of apology and walked over to a sickly old man accompanied by a young man and a young woman.

The man had an earnest face with thick eyebrows and large eyes. Although the woman’s appearance wasn’t outstanding, her large eyes were provocative, and she looked through the juniors at Qin Yan’s side with no trace of politeness. Han Li was naturally among those she had swept her eyes over.

“Senior Brother Hua, I didn’t think such a great medicine god as yourself would show up here! I would have thought that with your disposition, you would decline an invitation to such an occasion.” Qin Yan walked in front of the old man and sat down next to him with no trace of politeness, teasing him with a soft voice.

“Ke! I originally thought not to come, but the strange illness afflicting the prince’s concubine had been cured. This greatly piqued my curiosity, and I thought to see what expert doctor was able to perform such a miraculous feat!” The old man that Qin Yan familiarly addressed as ‘Senior Brother Hua’ softly replied with a faint smile.

“Oh! So it’s like that. So the rumor that Prince Xin had invited Senior Brother to treat his favorite concubine’s illness wasn’t just a rumor. Could it be that Senior Brother Hua’s healing arts weren’t enough to treat this illness?”

When Han Li saw Qin Yan’s great astonishment, he reasoned that the medicinal expertise of this old man should be very well known within Yuejing.

“Hehe, there are countless odd and fantastic illnesses in this world. I only gained my current reputation through pure luck! There are a few strange untreatable illnesses that are quite strange and difficult even with my medical expertise.” The old man smiled without seeming to mind. His view of the world seemed quite wide.

“But I still can’t believe it. There is actually another great doctor within Yuejing who has superior medicinal expertise?” Qin Yan shook his head. He seemed to hold much confidence in this old man’s healing arts.

But when Old Man Hua heard this, he faintly smiled and didn’t speak any further. Then he pointed to the young man and woman at his side and said, “These two are Hua Nan and Hua Fang. You’ve seen them before. Come over and greet your Grandpa Qin!”

Old Man Hua was clearly viewed with much respect in these two’s eyes. This pair agreed without the slightest hesitation and rushed over to salute and greet Qin Yan.

“Hehe, I didn’t think that your grandson and granddaughter would suddenly grow so big since the moment I took my eyes off them so many years ago. I don’t have anything good to give on hand. How about I give them these jade-embedded pendants as a welcoming gift!” As Qin Yan amiably said this, he felt around his body and took out a pair of flawless dark-green jade pendants. From a single look, one could tell these items were exceptionally valuable.

Although a strange expression of satisfaction flashed through the man’s eyes, it quickly disappeared. The woman’s face, however, was filled with joy, and she looked at the jade pendant with her fiery gaze.

“Don’t hesitate. If you want them, then take them! Old Brother Qin is no stranger to our household!” When Old Man Hua saw this, he couldn’t help but yell this with a smile.

When they heard this, the man and woman then dared to take the jade pendants that Qin Yan offered them. Their expressions were quite happy.

“Apart from this one, I’ve already seen the other juniors several times already. Could it be the dear nephew who recently arrived at Yuejing?” The old man’s gaze then arrived at Han Li, sizing him up with great curiosity.

“That’s right. This is Han Li! He’s a descendant of my Senior.”

“Honorable Nephew Han! This is your Senior Uncle Hua, one of the two great medicine gods of Yuejing!” At this moment, Qin Yan then thought to introduce Han Li to this Senior Brother of his.

“Greetings to Senior Uncle Hua!” Han Li sincerely shouted to him.

“En, not bad, not bad!” Old Man Hua truly did not see anything that was outstanding about Han Li but he still spoke those words of praise.

But after a moment of thought, he remembered the rumors that were being spread about the youth. He hesitated for a moment before taking out a small white bottle with his wrinkled shriveled hands and offered it to Han Li.

“This is a Heart Protecting Pill that I meticulously refined! Although I don’t dare to say it will cure anything, common small illnesses and injuries will not be a problem. I will give this to Honorable Nephew Han to protect himself!”

When the words left the old man’s mouth, Han Li immediately felt the envy and jealousy of the Qin Clan members behind him. Hua Nan and Hua Fang also revealed an expression of shock. The fame of this ‘Heart Protecting Pill’ was obviously greatly renown!

Chapter 288: Enchanting Confrontation

Seeing that even the normally extremely steady Elder Hua behaved in such a hurried manner, Qin Yan finally made his decision.

Although he could tell Han Li’s disdain for this Immortal master from his tone, the other person was still a cultivator who was willing to accept disciples!

As for whether this immortal master’s cultivation layer was high or low, he did not have the time to worry about that too much.

Originally he had given thought to have his own juniors apprentice themselves to Han Li. However, in the time he spent in contact with Han Li, he realized that Han Li hadn’t the slightest interest in accepting disciples and was unable to pursue this matter.

His father had told him that when the first generation of the Qin Clan had grown wealthy, Immortal Master Li Huayuan made a trip to the Qin Clan to see if any of the children had Immortal karma. Unfortunately, not a single person had such luck, and Li Huayuan could only return with disappointment.

During Immortal Master Li’s next visit to the Qin Clan, the matter of accepting disciples wasn’t raised. According to the words of Immortal Master Li Huayuan, the Qin Clan’s Immortal karma had only appeared for a single generation and that the Qin Clan descendants wouldn’t have any destiny of becoming his disciples.

But now an opportunity for cultivation had appeared before his eyes; Qin Yan naturally had to give it a try.

With this thought, Qin Yan made his decision and called out for his several juniors to go over.

Han Li looked at the scene with a cool eye and didn’t say anything.

Since he already gave Qin Yan a brief explanation, he naturally wouldn’t further mettle with their business.

With that said, Han Li hadn’t paid attention to whether the young masters and young madams of the Qin Clan had any spiritual roots. Among the mortals of the secular world, perhaps only one in ten thousand had spiritual roots. It was truly a pitifully small few!

Just as Han Li thought this, he suddenly saw that of the crowd of Qin Clan juniors who went over to Immortal Master Wu, two of them unexpectedly turned their head towards him and sneered at him. They appeared proud and satisfied, as if they were mocking him.

After Han Li saw this, he blankly stared for an instant before immediately breaking out in silent involuntary laughter.

Obviously, when these few people saw that Qin Yan didn’t call for Han Li to see if he had immortal karma, they believed that their Lord Grandfather Qin actually truly loved and favored them the most. Thus they appeared extremely content.

After Han Li inwardly shook his head, he felt disinclined to pay more attention to them and instead looked around the hall.

At this moment, those who remained seated without moving were an extreme few, only six or seven. The majority of those who had previously chosen to cut themselves off were displaying complete regret at this moment.

The only thing that aroused Han Li’s attention was a senior and a youth sitting at the corner of the hall.

The elderly person was an azure robed old man over sixty years old with a head of gray hair. He appeared to be calmly tasting green tea, as if he wasn’t paying mind to the matter of Immortal karma before him. The youth was smooth-skinned with delicate features. He occasionally looked in Immortal Master Wu’s direction with disdain.

Although these two appeared to be sitting quite leisurely, when Han Li saw the two, he couldn’t help but reveal a slight smile.

This old-young duo were unexpectedly both cultivators. Furthermore, their cultivation wasn’t bad. The azure-robed old man appeared to have a cultivation base of the ninth layer while the youth cultivated to the sixth layer, not lower than that of Immortal Master Wu.

But what slightly shocked Han Li was that he didn’t know what technique they used. They were able to almost completely restrain their own Spiritual Qi. Were it not for Han Li’s greatly superior cultivation base, he truly wouldn’t have easily been able to make out that they were cultivators.

As for that Immortal Master Wu, he naturally didn’t have the ability to make out anything strange from the two.

This technique, capable of concealing one’s Spiritual Qi from similarly ranked cultivators, immediately caught Han Li’s interest.

If he could learn this method, then wouldn’t it give him decisive opportunities during battles with similarly ranked cultivators?

With this thought, Han Li took a careful look at the two.

As a result, Han Li discovered something strange.

The pretty youth was actually a disguised woman with delicate white ears and thin holes on her earlobes.

Han Li was slightly stunned. That youth accidentally saw Han Li blankly staring at her and couldn’t help but blush, returning a fierce glare back.

The movements of the young woman wearing men’s clothes aroused the attention of the old man by her side. He wrinkled his brow and turned his head, taking an expressionless glance toward Han Li.

When Han Li saw this, he smiled toward the old man.

The azure-robed old man felt greatly surprised!

He originally believed that it was some clan’s frivolous young master that had seen through his granddaughter’s disguise and was looking at her with an obscene gaze. But he didn’t expect that it was a completely unremarkable youth who was actually looking at her with a completely reckless and fearless manner.

The azure-robed old man grew a bit angry in his heart, and after muttering to himself for a moment, he softly closed his eyes.

This movement surprised Han Li for a moment, and he couldn’t help but immediately guess, ‘He closed his eyes... Could it be he wants to...”

Having yet to complete his thoughts, the old man’s following actions completely confirmed Han Li’s guess.

He saw the old man open his eyes and look at Han Li with a gaze filled with purple brilliance. He actually used a bewitchment type technique on Han Li; it seemed he wanted Han Li to make a fool of himself on the spot in order to teach him a small lesson.

When Han Li saw this, he found it a bit humorous.

An old man at the ninth layer of Qi Condensation actually wanted to use a bewitchment technique on a mid Foundation Establishment cultivator such as himself? Was he courting death?

By only striking back with a bit of magic power, he would certainly reverse the magic technique onto his opponent.

However, since Han Li was interested in obtaining the other party’s Qi restraining technique, he naturally didn’t want them to feel great animosity towards him.

Thus, he could only wear a slight smile on his face and look at the old man without the slightest appearance of anything strange.

This caused the azure-robed old man’s cold smile to slowly become an expression of shock, immediately exposing an appearance of amazement.

The old man inwardly yelled ‘Not good!’, but when he thought to move his eyes away, it was already too late.

The moment Han Li met the old man’s gaze, a faint yellow radiance flashed in his eyes. His gaze drew the old man like a magnet, causing the old man to be incapable of moving his eyes away.

The azure-robed old man became scared and shocked while simultaneously feeling great regret.

He hadn’t thought at all that this youth, who didn’t appear to have the slightest bit of magic power, was actually a cultivator! Furthermore, his cultivation was vastly greater than his own.

Had he known sooner, he wouldn’t have used the “Nightmare Technique” and allowed his consciousness to fall under the other party’s complete control, incapable of breaking free of his grasp.

The old man became increasingly fearful, and in an instant, his forehead was covered with beads of sweat the size of soybeans, his face ashen. However, his eyes were still rigidly staring at Han Li.

The young woman wearing male clothing at his side eventually saw that her senior wasn’t moving. She anxiously pulled on the old man’s sleeve with haste.

Surprisingly, this tore away at the azure-robed old man’s confinement, allowing the old man to easily break away from Han Li’s gaze and freeing him from the backlash of the Nightmare Technique.

Right now, the azure-robed old man felt that he had barely escaped from entering the cycle of reincarnation. During this time, his mind had lagged behind, and he couldn’t help but blankly stare for a moment. After a moment, he seemed to have woken up, and his consciousness returned to his body.

However, the back of his clothes had been thoroughly soaked with cold sweat.

At this moment, he hastily said a few words with a soft voice and a terrified expression to the young woman. Afterwards, he didn’t dare to look in Han Li’s direction again.

The azure-robed old man clearly understood that the young woman couldn’t have possibly broken his daze so easily, which meant that he must have been treated leniently by the other party.

Although he didn’t know why the other party had done so, it would be better for this grandparent-grandchild pair to go far far away from here.

The cultivation base of the youth with a common appearance was truly fearsome.

Furthermore, what puzzled him was that although he had used the Heaven’s Eye technique to examine him, he couldn’t see the slightest fluctuation of magic power on his body. Otherwise, he wouldn’t have rashly used the “Nightmare Technique”.

“Could it be this person’s person’s cultivation has reached...”

Once the azure-robed old man made his guess, his face grew green.

If it were as he guessed, then hadn’t he provoked a major power that should never be provoked?

With this thought, the sliver of consciousness that the old man had just recovered became turbulent.

Startled, the young woman in male clothing looked at the old man’s face as it changed between green and red. She felt great astonishment, seeing this.

In her mind, her grandfather, who was always calm and collected with an expression as steady as Mt. Tai, was actually dumbfounded! Could it be that the seemingly-ordinary youth was truly so fearsome?

With this thought, she couldn’t help but have the urge turn her head and study Han Li.

However, without waiting for her to move her head, the old man seemed to have seen through the young woman’s intent and suddenly whispered to her gravely, “Don’t provoke that youngster. If my guess isn’t wrong, then he’s likely to be a Foundation Establishment cultivator. You mustn’t provoke him no matter what!”

“What? A Foundation Establishment cultivator! Impossible, he’s only a youth!” The young woman covered her gasp of shock with her jade hands. She turned pale and didn’t dare to be too loud.

Chapter 289: Immortal’s Technique

Although the young lady’s charming face revealed doubt, she knew her grandfather wasn’t one to babble nonsense and became extremely shocked! She could only resist further looking in Han Li’s direction with some difficulty

Seeing that he taught the other party a small lesson without truly harming him, Han Li was fully satisfied.

At this moment, his lips slightly moved and transmitted his voice over.

Then the azure-robed old man immediately heard Han Li’s voice.

“After you leave the Prince Xin’s mansion, don’t hurry to depart. Wait for me at the mansion’s back gate. I have a few matters to ask you!”

Han Li’s voice was filled with the unquestionable tone of a command, stunning the old man and causing him to inwardly curse in his heart without end.

“Could it be this expert doesn’t want to let this grandparent-grandchild pair go? What plan does he have for these two in mind! Regardless, it’s fortunate for me that the other party doesn’t seem to be the merciless type. There shouldn’t be any danger! Furthermore, being able to form a relationship with a Foundation Establishment cultivator is an invigorating opportunity that’s hard to come by for a clan.”

The azure-robed old man could only think these comforting thoughts. However, his heart was a mess, and he was suffering internally without end!

When Han Li saw this, he faintly smiled and returned his attention to the old white-haired Daoist.

At this moment, Immortal Master Wu had already finished inspecting the majority of the crowd and still hadn’t found someone with Immortal karma.

The youngster who were declared to lack Immortal karma could only dejectedly return to their seats. Their seniors naturally didn’t have any pleased expressions.

“What’s Immortal karma? He’s clearly looking for people with spiritual roots. However, this old Daoist isn’t a completely ignorant and appears to truly be looking to accept disciples! Otherwise, he could just casually point to a few random people.” Han Li thought indifferently as he saw the old Daoist examining each of the youths for spiritual roots with extreme care.

However, Han Li felt that looking for disciples here was truly futile. Among these fifty to sixty people, the chances of finding someone with spiritual roots were truly too low!

Just as Han Li thought this, the old white-haired Daoist loudly shouted, “This child has Immortal karma. I can accept him as my disciple!”

When Han Li heard this, he blankly stared. He couldn’t help but look at this person with Immortal karma.

He only saw a simple and fat youth standing in front of Immortal Master Wu with a vacant expression, not knowing what to do.

A large pot-bellied middle-aged man wearing purple silk robes stood next to the boy He closely asked with an incredulous expression, “Immortal Master, my clan’s child Jing truly has Immortal karma? Are you mistaken!”

This man felt that a huge meat pie had truly fallen on his head and didn’t dare to believe it. For so many years, this son of his had never shown the slightest of talent or accomplished anything. But now, the youth who only ate and didn’t give back to society had unexpectedly caught the eye of this Immortal master. The youth’s father truly didn’t know if he was dreaming.

“Hehe, Benefactor, be at ease! This humble Daoist has already examined this boy many times. Your son truly has Immortal roots and can study Immortal techniques together with the prince’s son.” When Immortal Master Wu saw this, he twirled his white beard around his finger and smiled.

“Many thanks, Immortal Master! Many thanks! Although this one isn’t a wealthy and great noble, we still have a bit of meager land. Tomorrow, I will certainly prepare a great offering for accepting my son as your apprentice! Son! Quicky... Quicky kowtow to the Immortal Master!” After the middle-aged man verified this matter with certainty, he danced with joy and began speaking incoherently.

When the youngsters who hadn’t been chosen saw this, they were dumbfounded.

The person who entered Immortal Wu’s eyes was Fatty Tong, whom they had always regarded as useless!

This kind of useless person actually had Immortal roots. This was far too hard to believe!

Not only did the youngsters think this, but their seniors also couldn’t help but look at each other in dismay and feel that this was quite incredulous.

After all, this useless youth Tong Jing had been chosen instead of their own sons.

Han Li’s expression, on the other hand, wasn’t the slightest bit strange.

People who possess spiritual roots weren’t always handsome and confident or ravishly beautiful. Furthermore, there wasn’t the slightest relationship with their capacity for knowledge either. There was absolutely no pattern that could determine whether someone possessed spiritual roots.

Otherwise, cultivator clans wouldn’t have appeared, and cultivator sects wouldn’t have to go out and seek brilliant students either.

However, to actually find someone with spiritual roots in a small group was a bit surprising to Han Li. It seemed that the luck of this Daoist Priest wasn’t bad!

Naturally, the others in the hall didn’t understand this grain of truth that Han Li and the other cultivators clearly knew.

They all whispered to each other in soft voices.

There were a few shrewd individuals among them who started to doubt the authenticity of this Immortal Wu and were slightly hesitant to come forward to test themselves when they heard this.

As such, the old Daoist was met with a moment of awkward silence.

When Prince Xin saw this, he showed displeasure.

However, those in the hall had been his good friends for many years, so he couldn’t just say something unpleasant. He could only tactfully say to the old Daoist, “Immortal Master Wu, everyone here is but a common mortal. They have not yet witnessed Immortal techniques and magic. Could Immortal Master please reveal your power and broaden everyone’s horizons?”

Having heard Prince Xin’s words, everyone immediately grew quiet and waited to see what the Immortal Master would say.

The old white-haired Daoist muttered to himself for a moment and openly agreed. Then he called for everyone to follow him to the open area in front of the large hall.

Following the old Daoist’s words, everyone flowed out of the large hall. Han Li also followed them out, but he did so indifferently.

Surprisingly, that grandparent-grandchild pair didn’t move. It seemed they were deeply worried about Han Li’s appointment with them.

Outside the guest hall, the old Daoist stood while surrounded by the crowd and started to cast magic.

From the gestures his hands executed, his even stance, and his faint muttering of incantation in a low voice, his appearance grew even more mysterious.

As such, the spectators around him held their breath and rigidly stared at the old Daoist without moving.

But when Han Li heard this incantation, he inwardly rolled his eyes.

At this moment, the old Daoist joined his palms, and after he separated them, two roaring, fist-sized fireballs appeared in his hands. The nearby temperature suddenly rose, and the smell of flames filled the air.

This was none other than the “Fireball Technique” that all cultivators with fire spiritual roots knew!

But what was viewed as a common occurrence to cultivators immediately caused the nearby crowd to gasp in surprise. They felt it was truly inconceivable!

But the next scene not only caused these mortals to continue with their stupefaction, but it also greatly shocked Han Li.

That was because the old Daoist then changed his hand incantations and caused the roasting fireballs to gradually fuse and transform before the crowd’s eyes.

First, the combined flame gradually grew wings. Then a pointed beak, immediately followed by thin claws and a tail, transforming into a small and exquisite flame bird.

“Could it be the Firebird Technique!”

Having seen this, Han Li nerves tightened, not daring to believe his eyes in the slightest.

The “Firebird Technique” was a genuine mid-grade magic technique, one that Han Li himself was unable to grasp. However this mere Qi Condensation cultivator was unexpectedly able to use it on the spot. It was truly far too hard to believe! It was no wonder that Han Li wondered if he had seen incorrectly.

However, Han Li’s shock only lasted for a short moment.

Soon after the old Daoist casted his magic, Han Li discovered a huge discrepancy between this fire bird and the genuine “Firebird Technique”.

Although this small bird created from fireballs resembled the appearance of the firebird magic technique, the discrepancy in size was far too great.

When the firebird from the “Firebird Technique” spread its wings, it spanned over three meters. Instead, the firebird that this old Daoist created was only the size of a fist. It was fundamentally impossible to mention them on equal terms.

But what truly convinced Han Li that this was but a false firebird technique was the magnitude of its fluctuation of magic power.

The destructive power of the true Firebird Technique wasn’t something a Foundation Establishment cultivator dared to receive. However, the magic power fluctuations of this small and exquisite sparrow-like firebird were exactly the same as a fireball; it wasn’t greater in the least.

It seemed it was merely a change of shape!

After Han Li thought this through, he was in good spirits and found it quite funny!

He had nearly been tricked by this small trick. It truly caused one to lose face!

However, this person’s flame manipulation technique was truly astonishing! Han Li didn’t know whether he could match the fine control of flame that this Qi Condensation cultivator could accomplish.

This old Daoist piqued Han Li's interest!

In his next performance, the old Daoist thoroughly verified Han Li’s thoughts.

After seeing the small firebird spread its wings and soar, it immediately fell to the floor and transformed into a dog that cheerfully ran around the old Daoist.

Not long after, the small dog transformed into a fire snake, then transformed a small person...

This series of astonishing performances left these mortals dumbstruck and speechless with gaping mouths, having never seen magic techniques before.

Then the old Daoist suddenly pointed a finger from his hand and made the final transformation of the flame into a small horse. The new form charged towards a small cherry sapling to the side. In the blink of an eye, the flame combusted and turned the sapling into ash.

This was the end of the old Daoist’s show.

At this moment, the spectators woke from their daze and did their utmost to hail the old Daoist ‘Immortal Daoist’.

Their original doubts had long been cast away. How could they show the slightest bit of disbelief!

Chapter 290: Young Prince

Prince Xin looked at the cheering crowd with a smile, feeling content in his heart.

With regards to cultivators, they used to appear before great noble and influential clans. But for some unknown reason, they gradually stopped, not making much contact with the mortal world. As such, people such as the Immortal Master quickly became the stuff of folklore. Even as a kin of the royal family, this was the first cultivator Prince Xin had seen with his own eyes.

The shocking display of magic techniques that the old Daoist revealed naturally caused Prince Xin to feel great face.

Of course, Prince Xin did not know that during the period when cultivators still appeared in the secular world, the cultivation world had yet to establish the Great Immortal Ascension Assembly.

During those times, low-level rogue cultivators as well as those from cultivation clans with no hope for Foundation Establishment gave up their aspirations and wished to live out their lives in the mortal world in wealth and splendor. However, with the appearance of the Great Immortal Ascension Assembly, cultivators could fight for their hopes of reaching Foundation Establishment. With this assembly, why would they choose to appear in the mortal world ever again? Naturally, they would be bitterly cultivating in seclusion deep within the mountains.

Of course, those without the heart to cultivate like Yu Zhitong, who became a depraved cultivator in the secular world, were an exception, and their numbers were quite few. They would become honored guests of great, affluent noble clans and enter complete seclusion, not daring to allow outsiders to know of their presence.

After all, to become a guest of some mortal clan was a matter that would cause extreme loss of face in the cultivation world.

As such, although it wasn’t rare for cultivators to appear in the secular world, those willing to associate with influential nobles and become their esteemed guests were extremely few in number. Also, the cultivators who mingled with mortals kept all knowledge of their actions extremely concealed in order to prevent their fellow cultivators from looking down on them.

This crowd of guests truly hadn’t seen other cultivators before. Naturally, they drew the frightening conclusion that the old Daoist was a celestial being from his beautiful fire-manipulation technique.

Under everyone's gaze, the white-haired old man returned to the large hall with a proud appearance.

At this moment, these people couldn’t wait to be tested and impatiently called out to him as “Immortal Master”. They immediately crowded about him, wanting Immortal Master Wu to examine them for spiritual roots.

With vigorous spirit, the old white-haired Daoist looked through everyone who remained without refusing anyone.

Unfortunately, the juniors of the Hua Clan and the Qin Clan didn’t have any spiritual roots; they were only but common mortals.

This information dealt a heavy blow to those who stepped forward to be examined. They could only dejectedly leave the old Daoist’s side.

It seemed Immortal karma was truly not so easily come by!

As such, people began to look at that increasingly prominent young fatty “Tong Jing’s” rare spiritual roots with envious glares. This caused the father and son standing at the old Daoist’s side to smile widely, unable to contain their emotions.

Han Li’s expression remained the same as he saw Qin Yan bring back the dejected young masters and madams of the Qin Clan. When they looked at Han Li, they had a somewhat wretched appearance.

“I am still unconvinced! Why does that good for nothing have spiritual roots and we don’t? Aren’t we a hundred times better than him!” A dainty Qin Clan young madam mumbled to herself with disbelief.

“Enough, don’t speak nonsense! With the life you have now, what’s there to complain about?” Qin Yan’s expression darkened as he turned his head to rebuke the young woman before sitting down.

These words caused the Qin Clan’s well-known pungent loudmouth to pout; an unsatisfied expression still remained on her face.

At this moment, Old Man Hua brought his grandchildren over. Without saying a word, he sat at Qin Yan’s side.

After they looked at each other, they suddenly wore bitter smiles as if they were fellow brothers sharing a mutual pain.

“Dear Little Brother Qin, it seems that the Fatty Tong suddenly made it in this world!” Old Man Hua said jokingly.

“Sigh! This is quite normal. Anyone that has good children would’ve immediately become a patron of that Immortal master!” Qin Yan sighed again and said this with a begrudging tone.

“However...”

Old Man Hua and Qin Yan began to have a chat.

But while they were chatting with each other, they were also diverting their attention toward the actions of Immortal Master Wu and Prince Xin.

At this moment, Prince Xin was looking at the juniors being tested for Immortal roots. He then turned his head towards a young maid and whispered something to her.

The young maid immediately went out the side door to carry out the mysterious order given to her.

After that, Prince Xin turned his head around and coughed several times. He then leisurely said with a smile, “Following the celebration of my favored concubine’s recovery, my son Quanzi and Honorable Nephew Tong will be apprenticed to Immortal Master Wu. Everyone, please celebrate and give them your regards!”

With that said, Prince Xin extended his hands without the slightest of hesitation and fiercely clapped.

Clap! Clap!

Applause soon rang out as pairs of cleanly-dressed maids and servants walked in from outside the hall with trays of fine foods and wine in their hands.

Then with incomparable skill, they walked over to each table. Each winecup was filled to the brim with shining pink wine. The large hall was filled with the scent of dishes and alcohol in the blink of an eye.

“Come, this prince will raise the first cup!” Prince Xin loudly yelled, raising a winecup respectfully given to him by a servant over his head.

“Cheers to the Prince!”

……

Immediately after everyone drank a cup, the atmosphere of the hall surged.

Not long after, the many guests started toasting cups to one another.

The banquet had finally started!

Prince Xin and that Honorable Nephew he called Jing’er were talking and laughing during the feast, seemingly deepening their friendship. The expected arrogance of a prince wasn’t seen.

It was no wonder that Qin Yan and the others held such praise for Prince Xin!

That Immortal Master Wu didn’t take a seat. Instead, when Prince Xin raised his wine cup, he wordlessly left.

This caused many who thought to suck up to Immortal Master Wu during the banquet to feel greatly disappointed.

However, this kind of thinking was quite ordinary. How could a living Immortal drink, party and lavishly feast like a mortal!

After they thought it through, these people gave up. Letting go of their previous intentions, they went to feast with the others.

Halfway through the feast, Prince Xin called for a group of female dancers to perform an elegant and complicated palace dance to add to the enjoyment. This caused the atmosphere to soar to the climax.

At this moment, a white-clothed youth who appeared about twenty years old entered the hall. He appeared very cultured and had a tall, thin stature. Each and every one of his movements held an elegant poise. This was absolutely the image of an ideal lover that many young women held in their hearts.

“Ming’er, come and greet your uncles!!” When Prince Qin saw this youth, he immediately happily called out to him.

Fortunately, Prince Xin just happened to be at Qin Yan’s table. Thus, the refined youth walked over with a smile.

“It is good to see you again, uncles!” The youth courteously said.

“I don’t dare to be called that! The young prince is too polite.”

Qin Yan and Old Man Hua didn’t dare to overreach themselves and hastily stood to greet him.

“Ai! You two are his seniors. Ming’er should be greeting you with courtesy. Why do you act like outsiders?” Prince Xin interjected with some dissatisfaction.

When Qin Yan and Old Man Hua heard this, they looked at each other and appeared somewhat embarrassed.

Those words weren’t incorrect! However, how could these two treat a member of the royal family as their junior!

However, these two cunning old foxes changed the subject with a few quick words. Afterwards, they introduced the juniors behind them, allowing the exceptionally forthright prince to recognize them. This was a seldom opportunity for the juniors to make themselves known!

Naturally, Han Li was included among those introduced.

When Han Li was introduced, Prince Xin’s eyes brightened as he repeated sized up Han Li several times with great interest. His face wore a mysterious smile. It was clear this person knew a few details of the rumors surrounding Han Li.

This caused embarrassment to surge forth on his face again.

“Ming’er, come over here. Come meet this Honorable Brother Han!”

It was unknown what Prince Xin was thinking, but he unexpectedly had the young prince meet Han Li with a smile.

Having heard his father, the young prince walked over and politely called out “Elder Brother Han”. Then he cupped his hands toward Han Li, maintaining a gentle expression the entire time.

Somehow, each moment carried out by this elegant and graceful young prince enchanted the several nearby young madams of age, leaving them unable free themselves from his charm.

Han Li returned the salute with a lost and foolish appearance, as if he were too nervous. In his heart, however, he felt himself in perilous situation, preventing him from maintaining his calm.

When this young prince moved forward to salute Han Li, he unexpectedly gave him a feeling of danger similar to that of the mansion’s steward. Although it didn’t feel as strongly oppressive as that of the steward, it was undoubtedly the same feeling of danger.

“What’s the matter?”

Han Li became extremely shocked as his heart sank into bewilderment.

Chapter 291: Xiao Clan

This handsome young prince naturally didn’t know what Han Li was thinking. Instead, he said a few warm words of greetings to the previously acquainted Qin Clan juniors and chatted with them, causing two of the young madams to blush. Their affection appeared to surge.

When Han Li saw this, he coldly laughed inwardly.

This young prince was indeed questionable. If these Qin Clan madams truly threw themselves into his arms, there definitely wouldn’t be a good result.

Even if the young prince were to taste them and then leave them bare, Han Li wouldn’t find it strange at all!

After a short moment, Prince Xin said a few modest words to Qin Yan and brought the young prince away to socialize at another table. This caused the Qin Clan juniors as well as the Hua pair that was speaking the prince to feel disappointment.

Han Li took advantage of when nobody was paying attention and took a look at the back of the young prince, muttering under his breath as something flashed across his eyes.

After several hours later, the feast came to an end.

Once the guests were fully satisfied, they started to say their goodbyes to Prince Xin.

Qin Yan had also brought Han Li and his juniors say their goodbyes. They then departed from the front gate of Prince Xin’s residence.

Just as Lord Qin thought to have Han Li board the carriage with him, Han Li suddenly asked something, much to his surprise.

“Uncle Qin, could tell me who those two are? Do you know?”

Although Han Li’s words were polite, Lord Qin didn’t dare to slight him. He hastily turned his head to look and answered, “Honorable Nephew Han is talking about those two? Yi! That’s the lord of the Xiao Clan! He’s the owner of a famous restaurant in Yuejing, the Leisurely Cloud. Since he is a very low-profile character, I am not very familiar with him. As for the unfamiliar youngster by his side, he should be his grandson!”

After Qin Yan saw that Han Li was looking at this grandfather-grandchild pair, he wore an expression of surprise. He didn’t know why Han Li suddenly became interested in these two.

“Oh, so it's like that! Uncle Qin, you should leave first. I will return to the residence a bit later.” Han Li thoughtfully nodded his head and then replied.

Without waiting for Qin Yan’s reply, he slowly walked next to the small path around the residence’s wall.

Qin Yan blankly looked at Han Li’s back and then stealthily turned his gaze towards the Xiao Clan Lord, feeling a bit puzzled.

But after a bit of thought, Qin Yan decided to board the carriage and ordered his servant to drive away.

Thus, the Qin Clan carriages departed from the front gate of Prince Xin’s residence and returned to the Qin Residence in the east district.

Those Qin Clan young masters and madams simply didn’t discover Han Li’s disappearance. Instead, they were in the back two carriages discussing what had transpired at Prince Xin’s residence today.

They were incomparably excited! They felt that although they didn’t have Immortal karma, they had stories to later flaunt off to their friends once they returned.

...

After Han Li walked for the time it took to make a cup of tea, he eventually reached the back gate of the prince’s mansion after walking around the tall walls of Prince Xin’s estate.

At this moment, the tall back gates were securely closed. Not a single person was in sight.

Han Li smiled and felt this was just right. This way, he wouldn’t have to use any concealment magic techniques.

He arrogantly stood in front of the back gate and raised his head to look at the sky with idle boredom.

After a moment of time, Han Li became blankly lost in thought.

Suddenly, Han Li felt there were people approaching with cowered backs. He lowered his head and took a cold look.

The only people he saw were the Xiao Clan Lord and the young woman dressed in male clothing. They walked over from the other side of the residence’s gate. When the old man saw Han Li, his figure became sluggish and exposed an appearance of hesitation. On the other hand. the young woman by his side wore an extremely curious expression and didn’t hold the slightest appearance of fear.

The old man immediately realized something, and his expression immediately became tranquil. He walked forward in large strides, the young woman closely following after him.

“This junior Xiao Zhen greatly thanks Senior for the lenient treatment inside the prince’s mansion! If this one has offended you, Junior is willing to apologize.”

After walking in front of Han Li, this Lord Xiao was still unable to determine how deep Han Li’s cultivation was and became shocked. Feeling even more reverence toward Han Li, h e rushed to salute him and respectfully apologize.

Han Li’s expression didn’t change after receiving the salute. He then faintly said, “You aren’t bitterly cultivating in some secluded area with abundant Spiritual Qi. Why have you appeared in Yuejing? Could it be you were reluctant to depart from your worldly affairs and splendor? Were you unwilling to continue your cultivation?”

Regardless of the outcome, Han Li first accused the old man of an unwarranted charge in order to easily overwhelm the other party and impose his own will; this would allow later affairs to flow more smoothly.

“Senior misunderstands. Because this junior’s age is far too old, he no longer has a chance to reach Foundation Establishment. Thus, the clan appointed him as the steward in charge of our sources of revenue in the secular world. It isn’t about returning to the secular world and staying there.” When the azure-robed old man heard Han Li’s words, his heart relaxed, and he replied with a calm appearance.

“You are the disciple of a clan?” Han Li didn’t easily let them off and closely questioned this.

Han Li wanted to get a feeling on where this grandfather-grandchild pair stood. If they were from a few famous cultivation clan, Han Li would be unwilling to provoke them. However, the surname Xiao didn’t seem to be from a well-known clan!

After he heard Han Li’s question, the old man hesitated for a moment. He turned his head to the young woman by his side before sincerely replying:

“This Junior is from the Yun Province’s Feng River Mountain Stream’s Xiao Clan!”

“Feng River Mountain Stream’s Xiao Clan?” Han Li wrinkled his brow and carefully thought about it. He was certain he had never heard of such a name.

“Senior doesn’t need to think so much about it. The Xiao Clan this Junior belongs to is but a small clan. Having never heard of it is a normal matter.” Lord Xiao’s face sank as he said this mockingly.

Han Li was a bit surprised. After he sized up Lord Xiao several times, he calmly asked with his normal expression, “You speak quite straightforwardly. Are you not afraid that I would immediately exterminate you two?”

The old man didn’t react to Han Li’s words. However, that young woman appeared to be a small kitten that had her tail stepped on. Her expression tightened as she immediately put her hand on her waist. There was no question that the bulge she was grasping was a storage pouch.

But soon after, the young woman saw that neither her grandfather nor Han Li truly moved to act. With a red face, she put her hand away but was at a loss of where she should place it. She dilemma appeared extremely adorable!

When the old man saw this, he glanced at the young woman affectionately before turning his head to Han Li and saying with a bitter smile, “Although this one is incapable of seeing through the deepness of your esteemed self’s cultivation, he is certain you are a Foundation Establishment cultivator. This one clearly understands this.”

“Junior doesn’t believe that he has any magic tools, medicine pills, or any such treasures that a high-level cultivator would covet.”

“If Senior truly was such a person, Junior would be unable to do anything. With this one’s meager cultivation, running and resistance is futile. One may as well surrender and fulfill Senior’s wishes instead of having him take out his anger on this one’s entire clan! Junior only asks that Senior treat this one leniently and let this one’s granddaughter go. She is this Junior’s sole remaining descendant.”

The old man’s last few words were extremely dismal. This caused the young woman to become extremely frightened and angry. She hastily said with discontent, “Grandpa, you need not be afraid! If he truly wishes to act against you, we will fight together! Then we won’t need to fear him!”

When Han Li heard the words of Lord Xiao and the young woman, he stared blankly for a moment. But once he fully understood what the pair planned to do, he became amused.

Apart from this old man’s dreary words and appearance of selfless martyrdom, Han Li didn’t see the slightest sign that he was seeking death. In fact, his magic power fluctuations indicated he was storing power in preparation. There wasn’t the slightest intention of surrender!

If it was clear he wanted to kill them for treasures, they intended to stake it all in a fight.

That young woman was also quite amusing.

Although her words were indignant, whenever she wasn’t looking at Han Li with her black shining eyes, she was incessantly looking around, frequently exposing a crafty air.

However, this young woman didn’t know that ever since Han Li had completed the first layer of the “Great Development Technique”, his spiritual sense was far stronger than that of common cultivators. Her petty tricks had already fallen into Han Li’s grasp.

Han Li inwardly thought, ‘Perhaps this “Feng River Mountain Stream’s Xiao Clan” was something off the top of his minds. As for whether there is such a clan, even he doubts it!’

Thus, Han Li wore a mysterious smile on his face as he silently look at the two of them.

Since he neither said these two could leave nor did he make any hostile movements, the grandfather-grandchild pair stayed still for the time.

From the beginning, the old man and the young woman had preserved their solemn and grim appearance.

But after some time had passed, Han Li indifferent stared at them with a lazy appearance. The old man Xiao and the young woman eventually looked at each other in dismay.

“What does Senior intend to do?” The young woman was unable to endure in the end. Breaking past the old man’s restricting gaze, she jumped in front of Han Li and loudly asked, pointing at Han Li with an expression of grievance.

Chapter 293: Infiltration

Han Li was quite familiar with the obsessed expression the young woman revealed as she departed.

The very first time he saw Li Huayuan control that huge flood dragon, he also had this envious gaze.

With this thought, Han Li felt that this beautiful young woman was truly interesting.

After he slightly smiled, he silently disappeared from the tree. He reappeared within the tall walls of the prince’s mansion.

At this moment, not only did Han Li use the “Invisibility Technique” that would hide him from mortals, but he also used the “Qi Restraining Technique”, a Qi concealment technique that cultivators could use only after achieving Foundation Establishment.

He quickly flashed by the scurrying maids and servants within the prince’s residence without anyone noticing anything out of the ordinary.

After a moment, Han Li infiltrated into the back residence of the prince’s mansion. He secretly hid behind a pillar at some desolate corridor and watched everything nearby with a cold gaze.

Not long after, a somewhat pretty maid walked nearby. Han Li suddenly shot out a ball of yellow light the size of a fist from his finger, striking the maid’s head. The maid suddenly staggered as if she were about fall onto the floor.

Without waiting for her to fall, Han Li had already leaped out to grab her and flew back to hide behind the pillar.

With great skill, Han Li straightened the young maid’s weak body and arranged it so that she faced him. He then opened his mouth and spouted out azure Spiritual Qi, which entered her tightly closed eyes.

At this moment, the young maid’s eyelids started to move, and she slowly opened her eyes.

Just as the young maid was waking up, she saw a pair of gold yellow eyes staring at her coldly.

Just as she thought about yelling loudly and putting up a struggle, strange yellow streaks of light suddenly shot out from those eyes directly into her own.

The young maid immediately felt the world spin as her vision was filled with a golden yellow color. Then, with a tilted head, she lost consciousness.

Han Li took another look at the young maid who fainted and lightly sighed before lightly wiping away the sweat on her face.

Although he could only use the “Soul Controlling Technique” for a short among of time, it truly consumed far too much of his attention and felt quite strenuous. It was no wonder that this magic technique was classified as a worthless Foundation Establishment technique.

Although this magic technique would make the target obediently follow the caster as a slave for a short amount of time, it had great limitations. As such, the cultivators who practiced this magic technique were truly few in number!

First of all, this magic technique could only be used on mortals. It didn’t have the slightest effect on cultivators. Even if there was a great disparity in cultivation, so long as there was spiritual power coursing through their heads, other cultivators could easily counteract the technique’s bewitchment effect.

Next, not only must whoever wished to practice this technique be at Foundation Establishment, their spiritual sense must be far stronger than average. Thus. the overwhelming majority of Foundation Establishment cultivators weren’t able to practice this technique.

With these two restrictions, cultivators with interest in practicing this magic technique were pitifully few.

However, this was no problem for Han Li.

Han Li had originally been anxious that he would only be able to grasp a limited set of Foundation Establishment magic techniques. The last time he was in the Heaven’s Knowledge Pavilion, he had read the incantation of this magic technique and memorized it out of curiosity. Once he returned to his cave to cultivate it, he wasn’t met with the slightest resistance and was able to smoothly succeed. This greatly surprised Han Li.

He now attempted to use the magic technique on this girl, and as expected, he succeeded.

After taking a cautious glance in every direction, he softly extended his finger, and a small ball of milky white light emerged on his finger tip. Pressed against the maid’s head, the ball of light soon entered her forehead and disappeared.

The young maid woke up and immediately stood. She blankly looked at Han Li without speaking.

“What is the background of the steward? When did he enter the Prince’s residence? Where does he often like to go? Who does he often meet with outside the Prince’s residence?” Han Li looked at the young maid and rapidly shot out a series of questions.

He started off with this maid, the one dispatched by Prince Xin to find the young prince at the start of the banquet. It seemed the status of this servant wasn’t low. If he used her, Han Li might actually obtain a bit of reliable information.

“Which steward is Master asking about?” The young maid asked with an expressionless face.

“The Prince’s residence has more than one steward?” Puzzled, Han Li asked with slight surprise.

“The residence has many stewards in charge of taking care of the Prince’s affairs. For example, there is Steward Li, who is in charge of making purchases, and Steward Di, who is in charge of supervising the residence.” The young maid continued with blank eyes.

“Which steward was greeting guests at the residence’s gate?” Han Li softly asked after wrinkling his brow.

“That is Steward Wang; he has the greatest authority.”

“He is the one I am referring to!” Han Li added with a bit of anxiety.

He didn’t know how long he could use this magic technique to control her mind. Naturally, he had to hurry and ask about the important matters first. Otherwise, he would have to waste more effort after the young maid awakened.

“According to the seniors in the residence, Steward Wang grew up together with the Prince and accompanied him during his education. He eventually followed the prince for fifty to sixty years. Apart from a routine monthly trip in which he follows the Prince into the forbidden city, he normally doesn’t leave the Prince’s residence and won’t contact anybody outside. If he did meet anyone, it would be among the Prince’s good friends.”

“As for his relationship with the young prince, it’s a bit strange! I’ve heard from the young prince’s previous wet nurse that ten years ago, the young prince used to have a very violent temperament, and his relationship with Steward Wang was anything but good. He even slapped Steward Wang in public before. But throughout the past ten years, the young prince’s entire attitude changed dramatically. Not only did he become polite and refined, but he also became extremely respectful towards Steward Wang, even holding a ceremony to become his Junior. Prince Xin was greatly pleased by this, claiming that they had the gods’ blessings all along,” the young girl flatly said.

When Han Li heard this, his expression didn’t change. He coldly smiled in his heart.

Although it sounded like this Steward Wang didn’t seem suspicious in the least, the exceptional change in the young prince’s character was enough for Han Li to be certain there was some sort of hidden relationship between the two.

In addition, for these two to cause a Foundation Establishment cultivator to feel danger, they certainly weren’t common mortals.

As for the steward’s mysterious background, Han LI didn’t feel like investigating it too deeply.

He only wanted to make sure the steward wasn’t from the Devil Dao. He didn’t care whether the other party was righteous or evil or whatever secrets he held.

If he could do less, Han Li naturally wouldn’t go asking for trouble.

After this interrogation, Han Li figured it was most likely that the young prince and the steward had no relationship with the Devil Dao.

After all, the young prince had been exceptional from the beginning; there hadn’t been a sudden change in ability. If the Devil Dao truly started setting this up over ten years ago, Han Li could only remain speechless.

With this thought, Han Li sighed and commanded, “Where does Immortal Master Wu live? Lead me there.”

“As you wish, Master!”

The young maid obediently stood and walked. Han Li secretly followed her while continuing to conceal himself.

With the young girl’s guidance, Han Li passed through seven to eight large courtyards and arrived at a peaceful terrace. At that moment, the young girl then stopped.

Pa! Pa!

Suddenly, Han Li lightly patted the maid’s back two times using a palm filled with white light. Afterwards, his figure flashed and shot behind a large tree.

“Yi! Isn’t this the venerable Immortal Master’s residence? What am I doing here?”

The young maid then blinked two times with all her strength and suddenly yelped. The blankness in her eyes could no longer be seen.

“Who is causing a commotion outside? Didn’t this humble Daoist instruct not to let people come here and disturb his cultivation?!”

The old Daoist Priest’s annoyed voice came from a room in the courtyard.

When the young maid heard this, her face immediately turned white from fear. Without thinking about why she appeared at this location, she ran away, flustered.

Creak. The door opened.

With the appearance of stereotypical Daoist Immortal, the old white-haired Daoist walked out.

But after he saw there was nobody in the courtyard, his fac e revealed a sense of confusion .

“What’s going on! I clearly heard someone talking. I thought the prince had come to find me! Where did the unpleasant person who interrupted my cultivation run off to?”

The old man stood in the courtyard and looked in every direction before furiously returning to his room.

After he shut his door and faced the room, however, he was completely dumbfounded!

He only saw Han Li sitting at the table, silently looking at the old Daoist with a beaming smile. He appeared to hold great interest in him.

“Who are you?” The old Daoist quickly asked as his expression dramatically changed.

He then reflexively raised his hand and summoned a fireball.

“What I want is you. Don’t worry, I won’t act against you so casually.” Han Li smiled speaking as if hadn’t seen the old Daoist’s fireball. His words didn’t hold the slightest bit of hostility.

Chapter 294: Flame Handling Arts

“Humph! Your esteemed self infiltrated this room with great stealth, yet you still dare to mystify yourself! See if this humble Daoist doesn’t...” The old Daoist had long been accustomed to flattery from his recent days in the Prince’s residence and instinctively reacted, yelling with a stern voice.

However, after he used the Heaven’s Eye Technique to look at Han Li, his originally furious face immediately became frozen and turned white soon after.

“Your... your esteemed self is a Foundation Establishment Senior?”

The old man stuttered, unwilling to believe it.

“Didn’t you already determine that with your magic technique?” Han Li indifferently said this with a controlled smile on his face.

“Senior do not blame me! This Junior had never seen a Senior who had cultivated to Foundation Establishment before. The highest I have seen were Qi Condensation cultivators of the eleventh or twelfth layer. I was truly incapable of judging Senior’s cultivation! I only knew that Senior’s cultivation is unfathomably deep!” When the old Daoist heard him, he hastily extinguished his fireball as if he had woken from a dream. He stepped forward with a salute and repeatedly explained with a careful, apologetic smile on his face.

Han Li was surprised that the old Daoist hadn’t exposed fear like the old man Xiao had. Instead, he faintly revealed a sense of excitement.

But after some thought, Han Li clearly understood the other party’s thoughts.

This white-haired old Daoist was part the prime of his life but still lingering at the sixth layer. He was most likely a rogue cultivator with extremely poor aptitude. As such, he was unable to meet cultivators with profound magic power. Even if he weren’t a rogue cultivator, he only interacted with Daoist brothers with cultivation bases similar to his own.

Now that he saw such a high-level cultivator, he naturally regarded it as such a fortuitous encounter that was hard to come by. He mostly likely planned to fish up some benefits.

Having thought this, Han Li couldn’t help but smile. If the other party was able to satisfy him, he wouldn’t mind giving him a few benefits.

Han Li immediately turned his gaze to the old Daoist and leisurely said, “Your guess is correct. I really am a Foundation Establishment cultivator!”

When the old white-haired Daoist heard Han Li’s words, his expression became even more respectful. Naturally, the happiness in his eyes grew a bit stronger as well.

“I don’t know why Senior suddenly appeared here. Does Senior wish to command this Junior to take care of a certain matter ?” the old Daoist respectfully asked.

This person was on the right track. He knew that if he wanted to receive a few benefits from Han Li, he naturally had to do something in return.

When Han Li heard this, he expressed satisfaction, and with a faint smile, he said, “First let's talk about your origins. Today I saw your show at the Prince’s residence. Your fire-controlling technique was quite good!” Han Li gave a minor praise, but little did the Daoist know that it was actually sincere!

When the old Daoist heard Han Li’s words, an astonished expression flashed across his face.

He hadn’t thought that this Senior had seen his performance. He hastily replied with a humble tone, “It’s unfortunate that Senior had seen my poor performance! Junior only manipulated the flame technique. I would have taken something else out to show, but my other techniques are a mess! As for this Junior’s origins, it isn’t anything notable. When Junior was young, he unexpectedly obtained the 《Fierce Yang Arts》 from a cultivator on death’s door. It was at this moment that he entered the world of cultivation. However, it was unfortunate that Junior’s aptitude was too poor, and without any guidance, he could only barely cultivate to the sixth layer.”

“Your fire controlling technique was a technique from that book?” Han Li’s interest was stirred, and he asked this soon after.

“It isn’t. This fire controlling technique was something Junior had cultivated until he reached a bottleneck. Without any method to progress, he could only grudgingly polish and refine some small tricks. But after several tens of years of improvements and modifications, it has become Junior’s greatest accomplishment.”

“It was something you researched on your own?” Han Li was inwardly startled. He further examined the old white- haired man several more times, revealing a bit of amazement.

“That’s right, Senior! Junior took this meager magic of his and turned it into a book, the 《Flame Handling Arts》. If it isn’t beneath Senior, Junior can take it out and give a pointer or two!” The old Daoist saw that Han Li seemed interested in his fire control technique and was struck with inspiration. He hastily took out a thin book from his storage pouch and respectfully handed it to Han Li.

When Han Li saw this, he was slightly startled!

Truthfully speaking, although Han Li felt that this flame transformation technique was quite strange, he didn’t feel a great desire to obtain this technique.

He didn’t think that this small fire controlling technique would be of great use to his current self!

However, the old Daoist took the initiative to show it to him and caused him to feel surprised. Han Li easily received it and took a moment to browse through its contents.

At the start, Han Li perused the book with an indifferent attitude.

But as he looked through it, although his expression was as peaceful as ever, he gradually became shocked in his heart!

The minor knack of flame shape transformation mentioned at the start of the book held no great meaning to the current Han Li. It was merely flashy but hollow inside. But towards the end, the old Daoist mentioned a few vague concepts regarding flexibly applying magic techniques and some feasible practice methods, providing many insights for Han Li!

After a short moment, Han Li gently closed the book.

Now was not the time to research techniques. When he had free time, he would properly analyze the contents of this book!

He was confident that this meeting increased his understanding and usage of magic techniques by a whole level.

“This book, I will take it! I know that although you said would give me a pointer of two, I truly want this book to be gifted to me. As a Senior, I naturally won’t leave you empty-handed. I have a few books on Daoist magic, magic tools of every rank, and even a few medicine pills of great use to a Qi Condensation cultivator. You can choose one from the three options in exchange for this book. I’ll give you the time it takes to make a cup of tea to come to a decision.”

After Han Li took a deep look at the old Daoist, he said a few words that unceasingly excited the old man.

“Many thanks, Senior! Many thanks for Senior’s favor!” The old white-haired Daoist’s complexion flushed red. He even trembled a bit from excitement.

Han Li faintly smiled and didn’t say anything else. Instead, he closed his eyes, leaned against the chair, and rested.

The old Daoist started to anxiously pace in circles around the room, finding it extremely difficult to choose one over another.

“How is it? Have you made up your mind?”

After a moment passed, Han Li felt it was about time. He serenely asked this after having opened his eyes.

“Senior, I’ve decided. Junior only wants medicinal pills that will allow Qi Condensation cultivators to make a breakthrough.” After Han Li’s inquiry, the old Daoist eventually came to a decision and said this with certainty.

When Han Li heard this, he didn’t reveal the slightest of surprise. He reckoned that the other party would choose medicinal pills. After all, magic tools and Daoist books could be acquired after he made cultivation breakthroughs.

Thus, after giving a light nod, Han Li brushed his gown sleeve against the table and left behind two small jade bottles.

“These two bottles contain Yellow Dragon Pills. They are substantially effective on cultivators up to the tenth layer. Take them!” Han Li calmly said.

“Tenth layer of Qi Condensation... Many thanks for Senior’s great favor! Many thanks...” The old Daoist looked at those two bottles of medicinal pills with a fiery gaze. After repeatedly expressing his thanks, he excitedly took the two bottles into his hands.

He then impatiently opened the lid of the bottle. and after sniffing it two times, he had a completely satisfied appearance.

“I actually came to find you for another matter. After performing a task, I will naturally give you even more compensation!” After Han Li saw the other party carefully put away the medicine bottles, he calmly talked about the main reasons he came there.

With the heavy reward attached, Han Li was confident the other party would be tempted.

As a result, the old Daoist immediately beamed with joy after hearing this and said, “Senior, please do not hesitate to tell me of this matter. Junior will carry it out by any means!”

When Han Li heard this, he faintly smiled and responded, “It’s nothing major. For the next few months, I want you to pay attention to the whereabouts of your disciple, the young prince, and Steward Wang. If anything abnormal happens, all you have to do is tell me!”

Although Han Li deemphasized the matter, when the old Daoist heard this, he was stunned.

He truly didn’t think that this Senior would want him to monitor two mortals. Furthermore, one of them would be the beloved disciple he had just accepted.

Having remained perplexed despite much thought, the old Daoist took a careful at Han Li and asked with a probing tone, “Could Senior please illuminate this Junior? Could it be there is something amiss with these two?”

The old Daoist asked this very carefully, fearing he would offend this expert.

Han Li’s face didn’t show the slightest dissatisfaction. He didn’t immediately reply to the cultivator’s question. After a moment of deliberation, he said in a soft voice, “In truth, I am a cultivator from Yellow Maple Valley of the seven sects. The Devil Dao is currently invading our State of Yue; even a rogue cultivator like you should be aware of this! I suspect that these two have a relationship with the Devil Dao. Thus, I need to have someone help me pay attention to their whereabouts, just in case!”

Although Han Li believed Steward Wang and the young prince weren’t associated with the Devil Dao, it was better to be careful. He was unclear with about certain details of their background and felt in his heart that there was something greatly concerning about them. Thus, he sought this old Daoist in advance to monitor the pair’s actions.

However, he didn’t directly mention any of his actual concerns to the old Daoist and simply mentioned the Devil Dao as a convenient excuse.

After all, the feeling of danger that Han Li perceived from the two was purely instinctive, so he obviously couldn’t say this out loud.

Chapter 296: Formal Apprenticeship

“What, old monster? Nobody said those words!” With a greatly changed complexion, the young girl pushed this forward with a strong smile and hastily lowered her head, not daring to meet his gaze.

Han Li chuckled and didn’t bother with the young lady. Instead, he coldly looked at the old man.

The old man appeared to have lost his head from fear.

He truly didn’t know how much Han Li heard from the previous conversation, so he couldn’t help but inwardly complain without end. Now he didn’t dare to speak his originally prepared excuse.

“I didn’t think that Senior would arrive so quickly! This Junior believed Senior would arrive in a few hours at the very least! Let Junior take out that book for Senior.”

WIthout a choice, the old man could only cope with all his might against Han Li’s unfriendly appearance. In a quick-witted move, he immediately mentioned the Daoist book in hopes that he could calm Han Li’s anger.

“Fine, take it out!” After staring at the old man with a sword-like gaze, Han Li eventually said this with a cold tone.

This caused the old man to recover his wits. It seemed the other party wouldn’t immediately vent his anger.

The old man hastily agreed and walked to the neighboring room. When the young girl saw this, she moved her legs, also wanting to follow the old man, but the old man stopped her with his gaze.

What kind of joke was this!

If both people went to the neighboring room, then wouldn’t they be deliberately angering the other party! It would cause Han Li to believe they were thinking of playing some sort of trick. The old man completely threw these impractical thoughts out, fearing Han Li would have a misunderstanding.

The young girl could only remain in the room with a pout. She stood silently in her original place, keeping Han Li company.

The old man’s movements were very quick. In the blink of an eye, he walked over with a shabby wooden box that seemed to contain the Daoist book.

“Senior, the Qi restraining technique we use as well as the other teachings of the books are within. Please take a look and see whether it has any use to Senior.” The old man walked several steps toward Han Li and proclaimed this with a respectful appearance. He gently opened the wooden box, revealing a slightly blackened yellow leather book, and handed it over to Han Li.

From a look, one could tell this book came from an ancient era!

Han Li narrowed his eyes, and after looking at the book in the old man’s hands several times, he nodded his head and received it.

Although this book had changed color due to the passing of time, when Han Li touched the cover, it felt exquisitely smooth. Furthermore, it seemed extremely durable.

It appeared that this book wasn’t made from common materials and was instead made from the hide of some sort of demonic beast. Otherwise, it wouldn’t have been able to remain intact for such a long time.

Han Li lightly stroked the book for a moment, and after muttering to himself, he slowly flipped a page.

After a few general looks, Han Li wrinkled his brow.

When he opened this book, extremely unfamiliar and ancient characters entered his view. Han Li was certain he didn’t recognize the marking of these characters. He also hadn’t seen such markings from the collection at Yellow Maple Valley.

Although he didn’t recognize them, Han Li didn’t waste his time, and he quickly turned through the pages.

In the last two pages of the book, he discovered a set of nameless chants that appeared to have been added by someone. The characters used in this set of incantations were ancient characters more commonly used in the cultivation world, allowing him to easily read them.

Han Li knew in his heart that this was the Qi restraining technique, so he took the liberty to analyze it.

After the time it took to eat a meal, Han Li slowly closed the book, and his face wore a thoughtful expression.

Putong. Putong. The old man to the side felt his heart violently beat, but he didn’t dare to breath loudly. He knew this moment would decide the lives of him and his granddaughter since Han Li would be revealing how he intended to treat the two of them.

Han Li didn’t pay attention to the old man’s inwardly nervous attitude. Instead, he calmly took out a jade box from his storage pouch and properly put the book inside.

Then, he turned his face towards the old man and said indifferently, “I will take this book. Tell me right now what items you two want in exchange for it. No matter what, I will fulfill your requests to the best of my ability!”

Han Li’s voice wasn’t loud, but when the old man and the young girl heard those words, it was as if they heard the sweet sounds of nature.

At this moment, the two knew that not only were their lives saved, but there were also benefits to be had. They couldn’t help but reveal pleasant surprise!

“Senior, could you let us discuss it for a bit?” Now that the crisis had passed, the old man couldn’t help but want to maximize the benefits from this exchange and immediately asked Han Li with a smile.

Before Han Li arrived, the pair had been afraid they would be exterminated absolutely without any items being exchanged.

But now that they heard Han Li’s question, they were naturally caught unprepared!

Furthermore, now that he realized Han Li wasn’t a merciless, nasty character, the old man gathered the courage to ask that question.

“Do as you wish. But you mustn’t take too long!”

Because Han Li had acquired a set of very useful secret arts and a mysterious ancient book, he was in a good mood. He allowed them this chance to talk without paying much mind.

“Many thanks for Senior’s great favor! We will only take a short among of time,” the old man exclaimed with great joy.

He immediately brought the young woman outside the room, and the two started to mutter in soft voices.

When Han Li saw this, he faintly smiled.

Although he could easily exterminate the two, Han Li wasn’t such an evil and pointlessly vicious character. If he didn’t need to, he wouldn’t go back on his word.

After a short moment, the old man and the young woman walked over with strange expressions on their faces, as if they were a bit worried.

When Han Li saw them, he was a bit puzzled, but he still asked, “You two have decided?”

“Senior, we have finished discussing. This one’s granddaughter doesn’t want any worldly possessions. Instead, we wish for Senior to fulfill our bold request!” After a moment of hesitation, he said this with clenched teeth, slightly surprisingly Han Li.

“What’s this request?” Han Li wrinkled his brow and unhurriedly asked.

He didn’t know why, but at this moment, Han Li suddenly had a feeling that something troublesome was going to happen to him.

After some more hesitation, the old man revealed a helpless expression and continued vaguely:

“A... Actually, this one’s granddaughter greatly admires Senior’s deep and profound cultivation and techniques. She w... wishes to become Senior’s disciple and is willing to serve as Senior’s attendant. As the sincere wish of this small old man and his granddaughter, we hope Senior will be able to take her as a disciple.”

Just as the old man finished stuttering these words, the clever young girl immediately paid her respects in front of Han Li and kowtowed, knocking her head loudly on the floor. Han Li simply had not predicted this would happen; after a moment of great surprise, he didn’t know whether he should laugh or cry.

To have him accept a disciple, was this a joke? He was still trembling from fear in face of the cultivation world and was never sure whether he’d be able to defend himself. Now he had to bring something to weigh him down?!

He certainly couldn’t agree to this matter!

Regardless, Han Li had to return to the main topic on hand. He could tell that the girl’s aptitude shouldn’t be poor, even if he hadn’t carefully examined it yet. Otherwise, she shouldn’t have been able to reach the sixth layer at such a young age. When Han Li was at that age, the only reason he had reached that stage was because he had the assistance of an insane amount of medicine pills.

From this, it would be a pity for this young girl to spend her life muddling through starting line of the cultivation world. Although he couldn’t take this young girl as a disciple, he could still introduce her to a master. He actually found the rare mischievous streak in her quite agreeable.

He clearly remembered that the small old man, Senior Martial Brother Ma, had yet to take in a disciple.

Furthermore, Senior Martial Brother Ma had once angrily complained that ever since Han Li left the Hundred Medicine Garden, the old man had to personally look after the medicine garden when he could otherwise be taking care of more important tasks. Had the small old man known Han Li would leave the garden, he would’ve taken in an obedient disciple.

This young girl before him appeared exceptionally intelligent. If her aptitude truly wasn’t lacking, then there was no harm in introducing her to Senior Martial Brother Ma as a potential disciple. As for whether Senior Martial Brother Ma would be satisfied in taking in this young girl as a disciple, that had nothing to do with Han Li.

With this thought, Han Li revealed a thoughtful appearance and caused the old man and the young girl to believe he was truly thinking of whether to accept her as a disciple, leaving them with excitement.

“Come over here. Let me look at your spiritual roots.” After some contemplation, Han Li waved to the girl and calmly said this.

“Yes, Senior!”

The girl appeared extremely clever, and after respectfully answering, she nimbly walked in front of Han Li and took the initiative to hand over her slender, flawless white wrist, revealing a slight bit of shyness.

Han Li lightly grabbed the young girl’s jade wrist with his right hand and started to slowly circulate Spiritual Qi throughout her body. Not long after, he let go.

“Dual spiritual roots, truly good aptitude!” Han Li muttered as he stared at the young girl’s face.

When the young woman and the old man heard Han Li’s words, joy bubbled up from their faces and they believed that Han Li was about to accept her.

But Han Li continued, suddenly saying, “Unfortunately, I don’t take disciples! Otherwise, with your aptitude, I would definitely have accepted you.”

Han Li’s words caused the grandparent-grandchild pair to feel as if cold water was being poured over their heads. They couldn’t help but blankly stare.

Chapter 298: Captured Alive

“Could you tell this one where you intend to go?”

Without waiting for them to take out their flying magic tools, a cold voice suddenly came from the sky.

This ice cold voice chilled them to the bone, causing this masked group of four to become completely pale from fright. They all cast defensive magic almost simultaneously and then scattered, not daring to turn their head.

About a hundred meters up in the sky, Han Li was standing on his Divine Wind Boat with fluttering clothes. He was expressionlessly looking at them with a gaze containing a ghastly chill.

Their hearts similar sunk as they all thought the same thing. ‘When did this person return? Why didn’t we sense him in the slightest?’

“Scatter!” Their leader, the Eldest Brother, shouted without hesitation.

He then took the initiative to fiercely retreat. At the same time, he threw out a disk magic tool from his bosom and stepped on it, flying away.

The other three scattered in different directions and flew off.

These people clearly understood that they fundamentally couldn’t resist a Foundation Establishment cultivator and that it would be better to immediately fly off since their chances of survival would be a bit higher.

The young woman had the weakest magic power among them. Thus, even though she quickly flew on her flying magic tool, she couldn’t help but turn her head to look at Han Li in the sky.

As a result, she was surprised by what she saw.

Han Li was standing on the small boat without moving in the slightest. He didn’t appear to be taking any actions in pursuing the four. Along with the woman’s amazement, she was also secretly delighted to no end, thinking there should be a good chance at escaping unscathed.

But at this moment, she suddenly heard an extremely frigid and sharp hiss come from her front.

With alarm, the woman hastily turned her head around and saw a blinding red arrow of light shoot from the sk, heading aggressively straight toward her.

Aghast, the masked woman raised her hand and threw out an ice spear technique just in time.

When that lustrous ice spear touched the red light, it shattered into white mist. It was unexpectedly unable to obstructing the red arrow of light in the slightest, allowing it strike against the water-attribute barrier protecting her body.

Blue light and red light then filled her vision.

Her body vibrated and was forcibly pushed back by over ten meters, but seeing that her barrier remained intact, the woman sighed deeply from relief.

At this moment, she took a glance in front of her with fright and anger. Could it be the Foundation Establishment cultivator had comrades lying around in ambush for them?

After she clearly saw ‘who’ was in front of her, this masked girl‘s black eyes went blank as if she couldn’t believe what she saw.

In front of her were two floating soldier figurines dressed in armor. One of them held a large bow and was currently drawing back the bow with a red light arrow. The other one was holding a broad long saber emitting yellow light as it slowly flew toward her.

Although the woman was shocked by the fact that these rigid objects could attack her as true people could, she knew that if she didn’t deal with these figurines’ attacks, she wouldn’t be able to smoothly escape.

With this thought, she clenched her flawless teeth and took out a blue lustrous throwing knife from her storage pouch.

The high-grade magic tool she held in her hand had cost her all of her savings. Normally, she would absolutely hate to use it, but right now she had to urgently escape and didn’t have much choice.

“Go!”

The girl softly shouted. That throwing knife then turned into a streak of blue light and shot toward the figurine that was approaching her.

The blue throwing knife arrived in front of the figurine in the blink of an eye, fiercely chopping at its head without the slightest hesitation.

Against the masked woman’s expectations, a soft “Dang” sounded out. The figurine had raised its long saber with surprising speed and struck the blue throwing knife before continuing to fly mechanically towards the woman.

The masked woman’s expression greatly changed. Pointing to her magic tool, she commanded it to fly out for several meters and loop in a circle, striking the figurine on its return.

But what happened next left her dumbstruck. As if the figurine had eyes behind its head, it struck the magic tool approaching from behind.

This time, the woman was truly panicking!

Just as she thought to come up with something else, a sharp hiss could be heard as the bow figurine shot out an arrow.

With no better option, the masked woman hastily flew to the side, wanting to dodge the arrow.

But much to her surprise, this red streak of light seemed to be manipulated; it mimicked her movements and followed her, catching her off guard. She could only brace for another impact and hope her barrier could hold up once more.

It was at this moment that the saber-wielding figurine finally arrived in front of her and used its long saber to break through her barrier without resistance.

Unwilling to allow the enemy to succeed so smoothly, the masked woman hastily moved to escape.

Thus, the two figurines attacked her from both close range and from a distance. With the cultivation base of the masked woman repeatedly exhausted from her continuous retreats, any kind of escape was out of the question.

But when the sweat-drenched young woman commanded her throwing knife to block the figurine's attack with great difficulty, the figurine that was attacking her in close quarters leaped away from her. At the same time, the archer figurine lowered its bow and no longer attacked.

When the woman saw this, she couldn’t help but be shocked. Then she heard a sigh come from behind her, “Sigh! Fifth Sister, you must come back!”

Having heard this, she stopped and then slowly turned around.

She saw three masked men dejectedly standing behind her. Behind each of them were three or four figurines similar to those that were also next to her. Apart from the soldier figurines, there were also actually several tiger beast figurines among them as well.

As young woman swept her gaze past them with an appearance of despair, she was subconsciously compelled to return to her original position.

Her three elder brothers had spiritless gazes as if they were already under control.

The masked woman raised her head to look at Han Li in the sky and sadly tossed her throwing knife magic tool to the floor. She no longer put up any resistance.

When Han Li saw this, he raised his hands with no trace of politeness and sent several streaks of green light burrowing into her body, causing her to feel as if a ghost had possessed her. Her body’s true essence became obscure, and she could no longer move as she wished.

With this finished, Han Li didn’t make any inquiries. Instead, he waved his hand and pulled them onto the Divine Wind Boat he was sitting on.

He couldn’t stay at this place long. If he didn’t leave, it was likely he might encounter an expert, which would be greatly problematic.

He randomly chose a direction away from Yuejing. Then, Han Li and the four turned into a streak of white light and flew away.

Not long after, two people appeared where Han Li and the four had been. However, these people’s clothes were a concentrated red similar to the color of blood, causing anyone who would’ve seen it to feel uneasy.

The two took a look around before standing in front of a large hole where the large tree used to be.

After a moment of silence, one of the two suddenly sighed and said, “It seems those five friends from Meng were defeated!”

This person’s voice sounded a bit old. Upon hearing it, one would assume the speaker was not young at all.

“Humph, there are no remains! Not only did they fail, they must’ve also been captured alive. As there isn’t the slightest scent of blood here, it seems the newcomer was able to capture those four quite easily.” The other person said this with an appearance of disdain. This person didn’t seem old, appearing to be around twenty years old.

“This is a bit troublesome! The five friends of Meng Mountain aren’t the useless sort, else their lives wouldn’t have been spared and they would have already become blood sacrifices. I suppose they hadn’t been overwhelmed by a large number of Qi Condensation and were instead captured by a Foundation Establishment cultivator,” the first person said with a bit of concern.

“What? Are you afraid those people will reveal our secrets? They’re only a few cultivators that our school has recruited from nearby. They simply don’t know any of our school’s secrets. Furthermore, before I sent them on their assignment, I had already activated their seal in secret. They will only live half a day more at most.” The youth lightly laughed and said this without paying any mind.

“Oh! That’s good. If it's only half a day more, they won’t be able to leak anything. With their bodies having been subjected to the blood incantation restrictions, by the time they discover something is amiss, they will no longer be able to say anything,” the old man said after letting out a breath.

However, the old man changed the subject and said somewhat darkly, “However, why did this happen? Did we not discuss this? We were supposed to turn that old Daoist Wu into our puppet and have him act as your master so that you can slowly show your face in the cultivation world. In this way, our school will be able to carry out our plan and have the core disciples appear in the cultivation world with an open identity. Why would you suddenly barge into that old Daoist’s room and suck in his blood essence? You shouldn’t be lacking in any magic power supplements!”

After hearing the old man’s words, the masked youth bitterly laughed several times and couldn’t help but say, “You think I did it for a supplement? I had no other choice!”

Chapter 300: Blood Curse

"Hmph! As our senior, you have no need to humiliate us in this way. If you have any methods to torture us with, just use them!” The tall, skinny Second Brother of the Five Friends from Meng Mountain suddenly yelled at Han Li; he did not seem to be afraid that his life hung in Han Li’s hands.

This greatly shocked the other three! In their hearts, this second eldest brother was someone who would think before acting; he was not an impulsive person!

The thirty year-old youth, who felt that Han Li seemed somewhat familiar, thought for a moment; He suddenly seemed to recall something and immediately turned towards the tall, skinny man, yelling at him with anger and fright, “Second Brother, what are you trying to do? Are you trying to purposefully enrage this Senior and cause him to kill all of us in his anger?”

As soon as this sentence left his mouth, even Han Li was slightly shocked, not to mention the dark-faced elder and the young woman; he had no idea why this youth would say these things.

In an instant, the Second Brother’s face became incomparably pale and didn’t say anything to defend himself.

“Fourth Brother, you’re mad! How could Second Brother want us to die?” When the young woman heard this, she angrily defended the tall, thin man.

Then the woman turned her face toward the dark-faced old man to say something. However, she truly hadn’t thought the old man would look so gloomy.

“Second Brother, is it because Third Sister still remains in their grasp that you thought to have everyone die so that Third Sister may live!?” The dark-faced old man coldly asked.

“Forgive me, Eldest Brother, but you of all people should know his methods. From the hidden meaning behind his words, Third Sister will be certain to suffer a hundred torments under his hand and live a life worse than death. It would be better to have one’s soul fly away and be scattered than to suffer that fate!” The thin, tall Second Brother eventually explained with a face of shame.

When the young woman heard this, her face became incomparably pale. Her lips moved several times, but no words were able to come out.

“Humph, even if Third Sister is your Dao Companion, you actually have the nerve to use our three lives in exchange for her own?” The thirty year-old youth resentfully yelled at the second brother.

“Second Brother, although Fourth Brother speaks somewhat bluntly, he is not without reason! When we swore our oaths as sworn siblings that year, we promised that we would all live and die together. But now for your selfish ideas, you wanted to deliberately kill everyone. This is unjustifiable!” The dark-faced old man’s voice was filled with disappointment.

“Correct! I wanted everyone to die but what other method do I have? My own flesh and blood is within Third Sister’s stomach. I can’t have my Li Clan become extinct here! Otherwise, who else would take the initiative to seek death? A wretched life is preferable to a good death!”

As his expression alternated between red and white, the thin, tall man couldn’t help but yell this with gripped fists.

These words immediately caused the old man and the young woman to be slightly stunned and reveal shock. For a moment, they actually didn’t know what to say.

The woman had her mouth wide open with an expression of complete shock.

“Are you all finished? If you are, then I will speak!” Han Li, who had been detachedly observing from the start, suddenly said this in a cold voice.

When they heard this, the three were immediately startled, and they suddenly recalled that the one who was actually in charge of their lives was actually the Foundation Establishment cultivator before them.

Their resentment immediately disappeared without a trace, and they once again looked at each other in dismay.

“I don’t care if you are all seeking death or if you’re putting on a play! I only want information on those behind the scenes. If you truly want to die, you will only be able to do so after you tell me information. Did you still think that you had control over your life and death?” Han Li’s emotionless words caused the fours’ complexions to greatly change.

“We don’t know much of what you want. Furthermore, we have a blood curse restriction on our bodies. We aren’t able to leak any important affairs to outsiders, else we would immediately activate the restriction and our hearts would rupture.” The dark-faced old man gritted his teeth and then said this. He seemed to have already given up.

“Blood curse? That’s a bit interesting. Let me inspect it!” Han Li grew very curious and said this with some interest.

When the dark-faced old man heard this, his spirit slightly shook. After some hesitation, he took the initiative to walk forward and extend his arm, holding onto a thread of hope.

He had hopes that Han Li would be able to remove the calamity hidden within him. However, he felt these hopes weren’t very likely.

Those who put the blood curse on them were extraordinarily confident that no cultivator with a blood curse would divulge their secrets. Those who divulged secrets, regardless of whether it was deliberate or not, would die on the spot.

At this moment, Han Li grabbed his wrist and slowly circulated spiritual power through the old man’s body. At this moment, his expression changed and became incomparably respectful.

The other three of the Five Friends of Meng Mountain stared at the two with great attention. They hoped this expert Han Li would truly be able to remove the blood curse.

After the time it took to make a cup of tea, Han Li let go of the old man’s hand and lowered his head in contemplation.

After a short moment, he raised his head and asked the old man with an unchanged expression, “When they laid the curse on you, did they chant any strange incantations or say some strange words?”

Han Li’s question caused the four to all reveal an appearance of shock mixed with a trace of happiness.

“They said…they said a few strange words we didn’t understand. It seemed as if the incantation came from some sort of ancient dialect. We’re certain we’ve never heard those words before. Also, it was a Foundation Establishment cultivator who laid the curse on us.” Without waiting for the dark-faced old man to respond, the thin man excitedly replied first.

“Furthermore, after they finished these words, they took a bowl of some unknown black blood and put a few peculiar pattern on all our arms. It is incapable of being washed off.” The old man promptly added on. He then exposed his entire arm, revealing a strange black and indistinct symbol.

After Han Li stepped forward and took a careful look, he nodded his head. Then he again lowered his head in thought.

Not long after, Han Li suddenly raised his head and mysteriously smiled toward them, saying, “I was right! It seems I figured out what this blood curse is!”

“Are Senior’s words true?” The dark-faced old man said, trembling. The other three didn’t dare to believe Han Li’s words.

This blood curse was like a sharp blade at their necks. They had no choice but to follow the orders they were given. If Han Li could truly remove the great danger that resided within their hearts, they would be able to recover their freedom and wouldn’t need to obey their captors any further.

“This so-called blood curse is actually a kind of oral curse! What created the restriction should be that strange incantation. It has absolutely nothing to do with the black blood mark drawn on your upper arm; that was only a deception!” Han Li indifferently explained. It appeared as if he was greatly prepared.

However, he inwardly sighed from the fluke.

Fortunately, back when he was looking for information on the Greater Displacement Medallion, he had come across this oral curse technique in a very peculiar book. Otherwise, he wouldn’t have known the slightest thing about it.

“Is it possible for Senior to remove the curse?” The young woman couldn’t help but ask.

“I don’t know.”

Han Li’s cold reply caused everyone’s heart to drop. The wild happiness they previously revealed was instantly deflated.

“What is the meaning of Senior’s words?” The dark-faced old man hastily wore a smile and carefully asked this.

At this moment, with the curse removal lying in Han Li’s hands, he didn’t dare to offend Han Li in the slightest.

“There are two methods for removing an oral curse. One method is by knowing the curse’s dispel chant. So long as I have the chant in my hands, I can read it aloud with spiritual power and safely break it. The other method is to use my spiritual awareness to enter your spiritual awareness sea and forcefully wipe away traces of the oral curse. This method requires the spiritual awareness of the one removing it to be greater than the one who cast it. In this way, the imprint can be removed. But if I fail, the oral curse will be triggered. You should clearly know what would happen afterwards,” Han Li wrinkled his brow and said this harshly.

“What! It can activate on its own?” The young woman couldn’t help but cry out.

The person who placed the curse on them had used a living person to demonstrate what would happen after the blood curse was activated.

That scene she witnessed, seeing that person spit out chunks of his heart in a miserable fashion, was still fresh in her memory. It caused her to feel fear from the mere mention of the blood curse.

The other’s faces were also unsightly. How could they possibly gamble with their lives?

Han Li looked at them and then coldly laughed. When he thought to say something, the thin and tall Second Brother bravely raised his head and said, “Senior, please remove my curse! The same person put blood curses on all of us. If you can remove mine, then you are certain to remove all the others as well!”

These words caused the other three to open their eyes in surprise and blankly look at him.

“Second Brother, what are you doing? This is far too dangerous.” After the woman regained her bearing, she hastily persuaded them with anxiety.

Chapter 301: Poison Expulsion and Breaking Incantations

“Don’t say anything more, I’ve already decided!” The tall and thin Second Brother cried out in a resolute voice.

The young woman grew anxious and hastily turned her head toward the old man and the youth in a request for help.

After the two looked at each other, the youth remained silent. The old man sighed, saying, “Fifth sister, let Second Brother go! He is repenting for the previous matter! Only like this will he be able to feel more at ease!”

“However, Second Brother...” The woman still wanted to dispute it further but the Second Brother had already walked in front of Han Li said in a tranquil tone:

“Senior, please start! Use me as a test.”

These words were tragically moving. However, what happened next caused the four to feel dumbstruck as if cold water was being poured over their heads.

“Are you four misunderstanding something? When did I agree to remove the blood curse?”

Han Li said this with an icy bone chilling tone, causing the Five Friends of Meng Mountain to look at each other in dismay.

“If Senior didn’t intend to remove the blood curse, then why did you study the curse on Eldest Brother’s body!” Their second brother hastily asked after snapping out of his shock.

“Did I say that I would remove your blood curse after researching it? I was only curious!” Han Li expressionlessly said.

Seeing Han Li’s ice-cold appearance and hearing his ruthless words, this group was stunned!

“But doesn’t Senior wish to know about those people’s affairs? If you do not remove the blood curse, how can we reply to Senior’s questions?” the youth added with a bit of a stutter and a face filled with anxiousness. He absolutely did not his wish to see this opportunity escape from his very eyes.

After Han Li heard this, he gave him a slanted glance and then coldly laughed several times, wordlessly turning his head to the sky.

Being asked such an obvious question, Han Li felt it beneath him to answer.

“Fourth Brother, there is no need to ask. This Senior feels the information he can acquire from us is not worth exchanging for our lives. Thus, he is unwilling to act so easily!” The dark-faced old man proved his status as an elder with experience that was incomparable to the youth’s and dove straight to the core of the matter.

“What conditions does Senior want before he will take action? We only want the blood curse to be removed, so please list your demands. We definitely won’t object.” Soon after, the old man calmly continued.

“Good! Since you’ve said these words, there is no need to speak in circles.”

Han Li suddenly applauded with a slight laugh and then wore a beaming smile.

From the four’s gazes, they increasingly felt that Han Li was quite temperamental, causing the four to unconsciously feel more fearful towards him.

“My conditions are very simple! If you want to free yourselves from your ailment, not only will you have to tell me everything you know, you will also have to obey my commands for the time being and help me respond to this group’s attacks. I reckon that they won’t let me off so easily and will want to dispose of us all in the near future.”

“However, you don’t need to worry about being heavily outnumbered. I am a cultivator form Yellow Maple Valley; I only came to Yuejing to handle sect matters. So long as you help me for this period of time, I will be able to request reinforcements. At that time, you won’t need to be afraid of these scoundrels.”

Han Li listed his conditions in an amiable manner and hoisted the banner of his sect with no trace of politeness. With just this, he caused them to become steadfast.

“Senior is a cultivator from Yellow Maple Valley!”

Although the old man had long guessed that Han Li was probably a cultivator from the seven sects, hearing him acknowledge this from his own mouth caused his face to reveal a smile.

“Alright. In accordance with what Senior has said, we cannot stay uninvolved. After all, once our blood curse is removed, we will certainly become a target of their pursuit. We will be a bit safer by Senior’s side!” the dark-faced old man answered very frankly.

When the youth and woman heard the old man’s words, they smiled without refusing! Clearly they agreed with the old man’s actions.

The seven sects were much more powerful than the ones who had placed the blood curse restrictions. Naturally, they could be relied on.

That thin and tall Second Brother had a face of hesitation, however. He seemed to want to say something but hesitated once more.

“If Senior is truly capable of removing our blood curse, we still have another request. I hope Senior will agree.” After the dark-faced old man looked at the Second Brother, he suddenly raised this request with a respectful tone.

Han Li had been expecting this, so he indifferently said, “What is it? So long as it isn’t too troublesome, I will do my utmost to fulfill it.”

At this moment, Han Li seemed exceptionally easy to deal with from his words.

“This one’s Third Sister was left behind in a house in Yuejing. Since we’ve been captured by Senior, we don't know if something will happen to her. We hope Senior will go and save her when the time comes,” the old man said with a solemn appearance.

“Eldest Brother!”

When the tall and thin Second Brother heard these words, his face held a grateful expression.

“Fine. Since you all are following me for the time being, I will naturally save your companion. But I must urgently remove the severe poison that is within your bodies! Else, in less than an hour, your lives will be forfeit and there will be no curse left to break!”

After Han Li agreed, he changed the topic and said something that caused the four to become scared witless.

“What severe poison? We should only have the blood curse on our bodies!” The youth’s expression greatly changed as he asked this with panic and doubt.

When Han Li saw the youth doubt his words, he didn’t get angry. Instead he explained this with a stiff face, “When I examined the blood curse, I discovered that in addition to the blood curse, your Eldest Brother is harboring a severe poison. Not only is this poison’s extremely toxic, but it’s also very unstable. I reckon it will break out rather quickly. Fortunately, this one has quite of bit of experience in the Dao of detoxification and will only take slight effort in removing it. You don’t need to worry much about it. Naturally, if you don’t believe me, you only have to wait an hour more and see whether there truly is poison in your bodies!”

After Han Li said this, the four were convinced for the most part.

“So it was like that. That must be why the person who gives us our commands suddenly appeared and told us to drink a cup of wine with him. It turned out the wine was laced with poison. We believed that since we already had the blood curse on our bodies, they wouldn’t further act against us. Who would have thought their methods are truly so cruel!” The Second Brother’s expression became extremely unsightly as he said this.

As the youth and the young woman came to a sudden realization, the old man’s face darkened. It seemed he had thought of this matter earlier.

Since Han Li had already decided to rope in the Five Friends of Meng Mountain to become his assistants, he naturally did not delay and have their poison flare out. He immediately took out a white and an azure porcelain bottle from his storage pouch and tossed them to the dark-faced old man.

“The medicine pills in each of the bottles can disperse a majority of the poison. The rest of the poison can be destroyed if you slowly circulate your Qi,” Han Li said very simply. The dark-faced old man immediately acted in accordance to his words and split the medicine pills with the other three. Then, without the slightest hesitation, he took the initiative to bite down on the medicine pills.

It seemed the old man clearly understood that if Han Li truly wanted to act against him, he simply wouldn’t trick them with an antidote. Knowing this, he swallowed it without worry.

Not long after they all took Han Li’s medicine pills, the group felt an intense stomach ache.

After the young woman’s face became red, she suddenly stamped her foot and flew to a small hill, barely able to fly on her magic tool. However, she was still within Han Li’s control as her flying speed was truly not fast.

When the other three saw this, they all awkwardly went to find a concealed location, their bodies wanting badly to excrete the poison from their bodies.

After a moment, the trio’s faces returned to Han Li’s side with embarrassed expressions.

That woman also returned with a trace of crimson still remaining on her face.

“Alright. Now I will start to remove the blood curse! Whose first?” Han Li didn’t delay and directly said this.

“Naturally, it’d be...”

Just as the Second Brother was about to say something, an incomparably shriveled hand pulled on his arm!

“Second Brother, you still have Third Sister! Since my old and weary body has no method to enter Foundation Establishment and I won’t live for much longer, I should go first. After all, Third Sister has a small child in her belly and needs someone to help her look after the child!” the dark-faced old man said serenely.

“Eldest Brother! This won’t do! How could I let...”

The tall and thin second elder brother appeared emotionally moved and shook his head as if he were beating a drum with it, wanting to disagree.

When the youth and the young woman saw this, they wanted to open their mouths and request that they first braved the danger!

“Don’t argue. I’ll have your Eldest Brother be first. After all, I tested his body just a moment ago, so I’ll have a slightly higher chance with him!”

Although the four had displayed a touching scene with their affections as sworn siblings, this was of no concern to Han Li, and he was disinclined from taking this to heart. As of now, he was impatiently wondering whether or not he could break the blood curse. If he couldn’t, everything he had just done would have been a waste and he would have to create another plan.

Once Han Li said this, the four didn’t have anything to further argue over. The old man walked over to Han Li with a solemn expression.

After the other three exchanged a mutual glance, they could only look on at the old man with a worried gaze.

Peng... Peng... A series of six or seven sounds rang out.

Han Li waved his hand, and several human-sized puppet soldiers wielding weapons appeared by Han Li’s side in a flash of white light.

“As I am breaking the blood curse, I won’t be able to meet an attack. These puppets are only a precaution. They will take the initiative to attack anyone who approaches within thirty meters of me! You had best go a bit farther away!” Without the slightest trace of politeness, Han Li indicated that he held absolutely no trust in them, causing the three to helplessly fall back.

Chapter 302: Countermeasures

In the evening, Qin Yan was repeatedly pacing back and forth in the Qin Residence’s guest hall; his face was somewhat anxious.

Earlier that day, the servant who was assigned to bring Han Li a meal reported that he wasn’t present. It seemed Han Li hadn’t returned during the night.

This caused this rarely worried person to become worried, not out of concern for Han Li’s safety but rather because his bodyguard suddenly disappeared without saying anything. How would his Qin Clan respond to any harm done by the Devil Dao?

“Qin Ping, please go and see whether Young Master Han has returned. Once there’s any news, please immediately come and tell me!” Qin Yan commanded somewhat anxiously.

“Yes, Lord.” Qin Ping responded with secret delight. Then, he ran out of the hall in an instant.

From his perspective, it seemed Qin Yan had become increasingly concerned for Young Master Han, further proving that he hadn’t chosen incorrectly. It seemed that his position was soon about to rise in the Qin Residence.

“But Lord, youths occasionally going out is a very ordinary matter. There is no need to be so worried or anxious!” Within the hall, although Qin Yan’s most favored Third Wife said a few exonerating words about Han Li, her voice contained an obviously sour tone.

This was no surprise. Ever since Han Li had arrived at the Qin Residence, Qin Yan had always kept Han Li close at his side. The Qin Clan young masters and madams who were originally doted on were no longer supported. The Third Wife’s children were also among them; she couldn’t help but feel greatly jealous.

“Humph. Woman, what do you know?” Naturally, Qin Yan heard the meaning in his third wife’s words. However, he was worrying about the life and death of his own clan while this woman was occupied with this small matter of jealousy. After he glared at her, he didn’t pay any further attention to her.

Qin Yan’s attitude naturally caused the Third Wife to feel wronged, but she knew that what her lord husband hated the most was a woman’s shrew bickering. She could only resist her urge to vent her complaints with difficulty. She said nothing further, worried she would become even more resentful toward Han Li.

But not long after, Qin Ping suddenly ran back with a delighted expression. Furthermore, once he entered, he loudly yelled, “Lord, Young Master Han has returned. Furthermore, he has brought back a few guests. Young Master Han hopes Lord will be able to arrange them a residence near his own.”

When Qin Yan heard this, his heart had finally relaxed. So long as this great Immortal didn’t suddenly disappear without word, even if he brought back ten, several tens, or even a hundred friends back, he wouldn’t have any complaints.

“Since it’s Honorable Nephew Han’s request, have them stay at the Clear Sound Courtyard. Also, do not neglect Han Li’s guests,” Qin Yan said without taking the time to think.This caused his third wife’s complexion to become increasingly unsightly.

“Yes, this one will carry this out!” Qin Ping energetically ran out again with a completely enthusiastic appearance.

“Lord, this is somewhat improper! Our Qin Residence is a great clan. To have these strangers suddenly come in, isn’t it a bit too imprudent?” The third wife couldn’t help but carefully mention this.

Her words weren’t aimed at Han Li at all. Rather, she was currently feeling uneasy.

When Qin Yan heard this, he was slightly surprised, but after a moment of hesitation, he waved his hand and said, “This is of no importance. Friends of Honorable Nephew Han will not prove to be any problem.”

Upon hearing Qin Yan speak such favorable words toward Han Li, the third wife was left speechless.

……

At this moment, Han Li was sitting in a chair at his residence. Five people were sitting in front of him, the Five Friends of Meng Mountain.

The youth in their ranks was currently talking nonstop about something. Occasionally, the others would add in a few comments. Han Li, on the other hand, revealed a somewhat thoughtful expression.

In the wilderness outside of Yuejing, Han Li was actually capable of using his formidable spiritual sense to erasing the blood curse previously placed on the four. Soon after, he brought these people to infiltrate where a single middle-aged woman was staying.

Surprisingly, this matter was carried out without the slightest difficulty.

Although the smoothness of the operation was unexpected, Han Li still broke her blood curse and brought them all back to the Qin Residence.

In truth, having these people find a different residence was acceptable, but Han Li didn’t fully trust them.

If they weren’t under his watchful eye, he didn’t dare to guarantee that these Five Friends of Meng Mountains would truly and sincerely fight this great enemy alongside him, even with the favor of breaking their curse.

People’s hearts were truly hard to fathom!

Although they may be grateful to him today and were willing to risk their lives for him, tomorrow they might feel like their lives were worth more, becoming despicable and ungrateful. This was truly baffling to Han Li!

Furthermore, he didn’t share a part of their sworn brotherhood. It was quite likely that they would value their own lives more!

Naturally, if he were to make use of his own restrictions and poison, he would have absolute control over them. But if he did so, in their eyes he would be no different from their previous slave masters. Over a long period of time, he would be certain to suffer repercussions.

If he left them with a vile impression, Han Li wouldn’t be able to use them any further. Deep in his heart, Han Li had some other ideas in plan.

If the Seven Sects were truly able to withstand the invasion of the Devil Dao, he would be able to resume his previous life of cultivation and have these people help him with pill recipes and medicinal ingredients. As such, he wouldn’t need to toil away, needlessly travelling to fetch materials. He could instead use that time for bitter cultivation; his pace of cultivation was certain to greatly increase this way.

Furthermore, while the cultivation of these Five Friends of Meng Mountain wasn’t too weak, it wasn’t very large either; they were the ideal choice. Thus, Han Li didn’t use such shameful methods in order to control them by force.

However, Han Li also knew from experience that unless there were enough benefits, low-level cultivators wouldn’t continuously performs errands. Furthermore, he was unsure of their temperament, so he would have to spend more time with them in order to be sure. He would come to a decision once all of this had been concluded.

“... We are truly ashamed! Until now, apart from recognizing a few cultivators that had also been seized, we haven’t seen the true appearance of the two who gave us our orders! We truly don’t know much about them!” After the youth said all of this, he bitterly smiled.

“It’s nothing. I already know that the other party is from an evil school called the Black Fiend School. Furthermore, the primary reason why they abduct others is to cultivate evil techniques. That alone is enough.” After Han Li heard this, he indifferently smiled.

“Senior Han! How about we stay here and wait for reinforcements before acting?” The recently-rescued middle-aged woman suddenly asked a probing question.

When the other four heard this, they also looked at Han Li with concerned expressions, wanting to see how Han Li would answer.

When Han Li heard this, he coldly smiled in his heart. It seemed these people were quite eager to halt any interactions with the Black Fiend School. However, how could there be any reinforcements from the Seven Sects! The entirety of the Seven Sects was currently in a war with the Devil Dao. Any forces stationed back at the sects were truly lacking. If he were to go and make a report, he was certain that no one would come.

But fortunately, on his return a moment ago, he had sent a request to Li Huayuan for help through some Yellow Maple Valley contacts within Yuejing.

The Seven Sects wouldn’t be bothered by this matter, but it was impossible for his master to ignore him. For the purpose of fulfilling Li Huayuan’s task, Han Li had to provoke such a great problem, and he had no choice but to remain! Otherwise, why wouldn’t he run from an insufferable problem? If he could, he would have already made his escape!

But in the end, Han Li truly did not know how many reinforcements would come. He reckoned he would be given a few Senior Martial Brothers.

With this thought, Han Li answered with a relaxed expression, “Naturally, this is out of the question. At the very least, we should clearly scout the other party’s stronghold and their major figures before reinforcements arrive. This way, we will be able to capture them in a net. To vainly wait at the Qin Residence is far too passive, since doing so will only give them time to track us down, leaving us at a disadvantage. We absolutely cannot allow them to so calmly put everything into order!”

Hearing Han Li’s words, the Five Friends of Meng Mountain looked at each other in dismay. The dark-faced old man stoked his beard and said with a deep voice, “Senior does make sense. However, with the mere clues we have on hand, we will be unable to grab onto their tail! The stronghold we originally stayed at is certain to have been abandoned. We have nowhere to start!”

The Second Brother silently nodded his head and expressed agreement.

“Be at ease. From your description of those two Black Fiend School followers, I’ve already discovered their identities. So long as they are captured alive, it’s likely we’ll eventually understand the circumstances of the Black Fiend School."

Han Li seemed to have already predicted this as he calmly replied.

These words startled the five at first, but soon after, they revealed pleasant surprise. They felt that Han Li had become even more profoundly mysterious!

“Good! Since Senior Han already has a plan, we will listen to Senior’s commands.” The dark-faced old man pledged resolutely.

When Han Li heard this, he nodded his head with satisfaction.

“We will move tonight. Only by quickly taking action will the enemy be caught off guard.” Han Li narrowed his eyes and coldly said this.

“Tonight?” The Five Friends of Meng Mountain couldn’t help but reveal amazement.

Chapter 303: Astonishment

Although the Five Friends of Meng Mountain were greatly surprised by Han Li’s decision, they felt that his words were reasonable, and so they didn’t oppose him.

However, when the middle-aged woman asked Han Li about the true identity of the two from the Black Fiend School, she was met with a tactful refusal from Han Li. Han Li only faintly smiled and said everyone would naturally come to know this once they made their move.

This caused the middle-aged woman to cease further pursuing the matter and reveal an appearance of indifference.

Not long after, Qin Ping passed on Qin Yan’s commands and arranged a nearby courtyard for the Five Friends of Meng Mountain.

As Han Li saw them move farther away, an odd expression flashed in his eyes, and he suddenly muttered something to himself that no one else could clearly hear.

At night, after everyone ate dinner, the Five Friends of Meng Mountain gathered together in the guest hall of the Clear Sound Courtyard. They were preparing to move late at night as Han Li had instructed.

“This is baffling! I can’t seem to remember!” The fourth brother, a thirty year-old youth, incessantly racked his brains around with a confused appearance.

“Fourth Brother! You still don’t remember?”

The youngest of them, the fifth sister, asked this with a mysterious smile as she lazily sat in her chair.

“Fourth Brother, you’ve always said that Senior Han appeared familiar and that you had seen his face somewhere. However, you haven’t been able to remember when or where. This doesn’t sound very convincing to your youngster sister. Did you want to have a favorable relationship with Senior Han so badly that this mistook his identity?!”

It was clear that this young woman’s words were filled with ridicule.

“En, that’s very possible. After all, this Senior’s appearance is quite common, so it’s normal for Fourth Brother to be familiar with him!” The second brother teased as he tasted some tea.

However, his eyes didn’t leave the middle-aged woman at his side for a moment. He was continuously looking at her still attractive appearance and continued to glance at her belly with a sense of happiness.

However, this third sister, the middle-aged woman, saw the fourth’s brother distraught appearance and couldn’t help but make a scornful face with all her strength, causing him to laugh uncontrollably; his normally shrewd and profoundly strong appearance was nowhere to be found at the moment.

“Humph! You’re all talking drivel. I’m certain I’ve seen him before, but it doesn’t seem to have been recent. It should’ve been quite a few years back, else I wouldn’t have forgotten about it,” the youth said with unwillingless as he unhappily glared at the young woman and the tall, thin man.

“A few years back? Fourth Brother, several years ago we were bitterly cultivating and didn’t leave seclusion. How could you have seen Senior Han? Could it be that you saw him when you were still wearing diapers?” The middle-aged woman chuckled as she made fun of the youth.

“Third Sister, you...” The youth cried out angrily to the middle-aged woman with an embarrassed expression.

“Several years ago, Fourth Brother hadn’t always been in secluded cultivation. Could it be you’ve forgotten? Before we met Fifth Sister, we participated in the Immortal Ascension Assembly. After the two to three month journey, we unfortunately returned with failed ambitions, but luckily, we didn’t receive any serious injuries!” The dark-faced old man indifferently interrupted with these words.

“What! Everyone participated in the Immortal Ascension Assembly!?” The fifth sister blinked several times and revealed a very curious expression. On the other hand, her Second Brother and the middle-aged woman looked at each other with bitter smiles.

“There is nothing to say. That was the first time we truly knew the meaning of ‘viewing the sky from the bottom of the well’!” The middle-aged woman sighed.

"What? Fourth Brother, at that time you said to me.... Yi!”

The young woman turned her head with great curiosity to see what her second brother was going to say about the Immortal Ascension Assembly, but she saw that he had a face filled with shock.

“Fourth Brother, what’s going on?”

The others also saw that the youth’s expression was rather queer, so they asked this with astonishment.

“Second Brother, do you remember that day at the Immortal Ascension Assembly when Eldest Brother and Third Sister separated from us? I was feeling gluttonous at the time and privately went to a restaurant at Jia Yuan City to sneak in a meal.” The youth didn’t answer the other party’s suspicions and suddenly mentioned an old affair from the time. This caused the tall, thin man to feel indescribably strange.

“Of course I remember. At that time, although I concealed this matter for you, Eldest Brother still found out and fiercely rebuked you!” The second brother answered with slight confusion.

“That’s right. At the time, didn’t I see a young cultivator there who I suspected wanted to participate in the Immortal Ascension Assembly? His cultivation was only of the seventh or eighth layer, so we felt that he was overestimating himself,” the youth added with a bitter smile.

“It was too long ago. I don’t remember it very clearly. Why are you talking about this?!” the second brother asked, hesitant.

He truly did not know why his fourth brother was suddenly talking about this matter.

The others also heard their puzzling words and felt greatly baffled.

“The young cultivator I saw that year is precisely the current Senior Han!” the youth said with a dry voice, causing all those present to become dumbstruck.[1]

“What? Senior Han was the young lowly cultivator?” The thin, tall man jumped up from his chair with an unconvinced expression.

“What’s this all about? Speak clearly!” After recovering from astonishment, the dark-faced old man wrinkled his brow and asked this.

“It’s like this, Eldest Brother!” The thin, tall man hastily gave a general description of what happened that year. When the others heard this, they felt it was inconceivable.

“Fourth Brother, are you saying Senior Han was that seventh layer Qi Condensation cultivator from back then?” The young woman gulped her saliva as she said this. Soon after, she realized her bearing was graceless and couldn’t help but blush.

As the others were shocked, none of them paid attention to this minor action of hers.

“Is Fourth Brother mistaken? After all, that matter occurred over ten years ago, and Senior Han’s appearance shouldn’t completely match his age.”

“No, that person was certainly Senior Han! His appearance is exactly the same at that time. Apart from his age, his appearance is completely similar.” The youth was shocked at first, but after some thoughts, he became more certain.

Hearing this youth’s decisive and resolute words, the others looked at each other in dismay.

In a brief ten years, this person with such low cultivation was actually able to become a Foundation Establishment cultivator. These people couldn’t help but feel pain in their heart from this fact.

For a brief moment, nobody had the thought to further speak.

“Enough. Regardless of whether Senior Han was the person from that year, he’s currently a genuine Foundation Establishment cultivator, and we have to treat him as such. Don’t ask him anything you shouldn’t, understood?” After the old man muttered to himself for a moment, he became the first to speak.

“I understand.” The youth hesitated for a moment before sincerely replying. His expression eventually returned to normal.

“Alright. Everyone, return to your rooms and refine Qi! Be sure to make your preparations.”

After hearing these words, everyone gave each other a mutual glance before returning to their rooms.

Immediately after, the Clear Sound Courtyard became silent.

About an hour later, the sky grew completely dark.

A person suddenly walked out from a side room in the Clear Sound Courtyard.

This person opened the room door with careful secrecy and took a look in every direction. Then that person silently walked out of the small courtyard.

This person took advantage of the pitch black night to walk to the corner of some faraway place. After some hesitation flashed through her eyes, this person immediately became resolute.

This person took out a small box from her bosom with some nervousness and thought to open it.

Suddenly, this person heard a sigh come from behind them, causing her figure to tremble. This person almost dropped the box she held in hand from fright. This was because the voice sounded much like Han Li’s.

“Why are you doing this?” She heard an additional familiar voice almost at the same time; it seemed to be filled with sorrow.

Then this person clearly saw several individuals come out from nearby with bright moonstones in hand. Underneath the dim moonlight, they appeared to have an expression of disbelief.

“Why are you doing this?” The dark-faced man asked with much lament.

“Why what? I’m only testing out a magic tool!” This person’s incomparably pale expression gradually returned to normal. She unexpectedly said this as if nothing had happened.

“Hand over whatever’s in your hands and let me see what it is!” From the pitch-black darkness, Han Li descended from the sky like a feather and commanded her with a normal expression.

“That’s improper! Why do I have to let an outsider look at my magic tool! I naturally won’t! Right, Fourth Brother?”

This suspicious figure was actually the young woman among the Five Friends of Meng Mountain.

At this moment, although she was trying her hardest to preserve her ordinary appearance, she firmly held the small box protectively, absolutely unwilling to let it go.

“Fifth Sister, give that item of yours to Senior Han!” The dark-faced old man grimly ordered with an ice-cold tone.

[1]. The Second Brother and the Fourth Brother saw Han Li for the first time back in Chapter 106: Blue-Clothed Man.

[Back]

Chapter 309: Demonic Transformation

“You can’t withstand it! Quickly, dodge!”

Resisting sharp pain, Steward Wang loudly shouted while in Han Li’s grasp in an attempt to warn the young prince.

Obviously, his warning came too late.

Hearing this, the young prince subconsciously leaned to the side, wanting to dodge the point of the huge azure sword. However, the sword suddenly changed its cleave to a slice, softly sweeping past his legs. The black Qi protecting his body scattered from the attack and didn’t have the slightest of effect.

As a result, the sword sliced through his two calves with great ease. The young prince loudly shouted, fainting on the scene.

This person who had lived a life of luxury since birth, though he may be exceptionally shrewd, had never experienced such sufferings before. Naturally, he wasn’t able to bear the pain of lacerated legs.

However, this scene scared Han Li; because he hadn’t used the azure essence sword streak in so long, he believed that he had accidentally killed him!

After figuring out what just happened, Han Li happily laughed as he picked this person up and flew back to the Four Friends of Meng Mountain.

Han Li grew very cheerful from his decisive victory, but at the same time, he felt somewhat puzzled.

From the feeling of danger the young prince and Steward Wang gave him, these two should’ve been far more dangerous. However, he was able to capture them alive very easily. Could it be that his mysterious intuition had started to fail him?

Han Li shook his head and felt something was strange.

At this moment, the black-clothed men lingering around had witnessed this scene and knew that remaining there any longer would be unfavorable. After exchanging mutual glances, they started to scatter and escape in the blink of an eye, leaving behind no traces of them ever being there.

Han Li had no intention of chasing after them. There were only foreign elements, much like the Four Friends of Meng Mountain. They were fundamentally unworthy of a strenuous pursuit.

As he thought this, he flew back to the Four Friends of Meng Mountain and casually threw down his two captives, saying indifferently, “Treat their injuries. We still need to interrogate them!”

The youth and the second brother immediately acted, catching the two. They didn’t dare to show the slightest negligence.

At this moment, not only did the Four Friends of Meng Mountain appear respectful, but their hearts were also filled with reverence toward him. Han Li’s recent display of great and profound power left them with an unforgettable impression.

“Senior’s cultivation is truly profound. It has greatly broadened these juniors’ perspective,” the dark-faced old man said with complete respect.

“It was nothing but minor skill!”

When Han Li saw the four friends’ expressions of reverence, he couldn’t help but feel somewhat proud. However, he put on an appearance that such a thing wasn’t worth mentioning, causing the four to feel that Senior Han was profoundly mysterious!

Dang! Dang! At this moment, these loud bangs caused Han Li’s complexion to slightly change.

The four friends hastily looked over. After the middle-aged woman took a clear look, she pointed with a panicked appearance and shouted to Han Li, “Senior, quickly look! Your magic tool!”

Han Li had already turned his head over to look at the “Heaven Shrouding Cup” trapping the large bald man. Startlingly loud noises rang from within, accompanied by unimaginable deformations appearing on its exterior.

With each following sound, the wall of the Heaven Shrouding Cup protruded even more. After over ten more large sounds, the cup was no longer recognizable, and slightest resemblance to its original shape could not be seen.

But what was even worse was that the cup’s yellow light had grown far duller. It seemed that the large bald man could break through the cup at any moment.

Han Li was overwhelmed with shock!

Although he didn’t know why this inconceivable scene occurred, it was obvious that this Heaven Shrouding Cup couldn’t contain him. His only choice at the moment was to take other actions.

With this thought, Han Li retrieved the many magic tools that were orbiting above him and took out seven to eight puppet beasts. He had the four puppets he had originally taken out form a line in front of Han Li and the four friends, creating a barrier.

Just as this was accomplished, the sound of a huge explosion could be heard as the “Heaven Shrouding Cup” magic tool shattered into multiple pieces. Then, an inhuman monster flew out from its remains.

“What is that?”

When the middle-aged woman saw this, she involuntarily cried out. The complexions of the three at her side also turned green with disbelief.

Even Han Li was astonished at what he saw.

The large bald man who had leap out completely resembled a demon in both appearance and physique.

His height was now over six meters. His teeth were sharp and wild. Two black horns protruded from his head. A long, scaled iron tail dragged behind him. But what was most astonishing were the black and red demonic patterns covering his entire body. A majority of his bare body had been concealed by an unspeakably fiendish Qi.

The large bald man’s original appearance could faintly be made out from his face, but his eyes were glowing with a green ominous light, completely filled with the desire for blood and slaughter. The slightest of humanity no longer remained. He looked toward Han Li and the others with an ice-cold glance and crouched down, like a drawn arrow ready to be shot.

When the Four Friends of Meng Mountain saw this, they dreaded disaster. But just as they were at a loss as to what to do, they suddenly heard Han Li’s voice.

“Release your magic tools!”

Following Han Li’s command, over ten puppets in front of them simultaneously opened their mouths and shot out over ten beams of light, striking the transformed demon like lightning. The unguarded opponent was sent tumbling to the ground.

Seeing this, the Four Friends of Meng Mountain couldn’t help but be greatly joyous and impulsively released their magic tools, attacking the large man from every direction. They wished to quickly dispatch of this frightening monster.

Unfortunately, their beautiful dream only lasted for a fleeting moment before a stream of fiendish Qi shot toward the sky from the large man as he furiously jumped up. Regardless of what magic tool was attacking him, there wasn’t the slightest of injury. This caused the four friends’ eyes to open wide from shock.

The transformed demon madly roared to the sky and suddenly started to wildly flourish his arms like windmills, striking at the magic tools that surrounded him. In an instant, his incredibly sharp fingers thoroughly sliced them to bits and turned them into scrap metal fragments.

Without waiting for the four friends to recover from their shock, the transformed demon’s eyes glowed with jade light and his body shook several times, appearing in front the barrier protecting Han Li and the others. It extended its claws and fiercely swung.

Crash.

The dark-faced old man quickly acted and activated the shield blocking the attack just in time. However, five deep claw marks remained on the shield. Furthermore, the old man’s complexion turned extremely pale in an instant; it was obvious his magic power was not enough to maintain the shield against the onslaught.

Seeing this, the large man laughed evilly and used his other claw to strike the shield at the speed of lightning.

However, his expression immediately changed. He abruptly withdrew his claw and pulled back his arms, forming a cross in front of his body.

At this moment, the second wave of light beams came from his front, harshly striking him once more.

However, this time the transformed demon wasn’t knocked down by the attack. He was only forcibly pushed back by the wave of attacks by about a hundred meters. This caused the dark-faced old man, who received the first claw attack, to finally let out a long breath. He wiped the cold sweat from his forehead and nervously said to the other three, “His attacks are too ferocious. A single person’s magic power won’t last against his strikes. Everyone, gather your strength to power the shield!”

Hearing the words of their eldest brother, the remaining three friends reached out without hesitation and placed their hands on the old man’s shoulders, frenziedly pouring spiritual power into his body.

In an instant, color returned to dark-faced old man’s complexion.

The second attack had no effect on the man transformed into a demon, which appeared to become even more violent. As soon as the puppet beasts’ light beams faded away, it immediately charged forward again, brandishing its fangs and claws. But as it was about to strike the white scale shield, another wave of light beams struck it back to its original location.

Seeing this, Han Li tensely wrinkled his brow.

Since this monster was able to break through the “Heaven Shrouding Cup” and its body could resist the puppet beasts’ light beam attacks, it was clear that common top-grade magic tools wouldn’t have any effects. Only treasure talismans would do any damage.

With this thought, Han Li didn’t hesitate any further and commanded the Four Friends of Meng Mountain, “Keep it busy with the puppet beasts. I need some time to cast my magic!”

With that said, Han Li did not wait for their response. He took out the azure mist talisman from his storage pouch and solemnly sat down with his eyes closed, the talisman in his hands.

Han Li didn’t tell them about the matter of the treasure talisman because he understood that as loose cultivators, they most likely would not have known of such a thing, More importantly, now was not the time to explain.

His neat and incisive methods illustrated that Han Li simply did not tolerate opposition from the Four Friends of Meng Mountain. These four friends also clearly understood this. After they mutually glanced at each other, the dark-faced old man could only gather his courage and agree.

After that, the transformed demon threw itself forward seven to eight more times in successive attacks, but each attack was met with dejected failure.

Although that white scale shield was riddled with traces of damage from the opponent’s claws, under the control of the four friends, it was able to obstruct his incisive jade-shattering claws. They were even able to repel it a certain distance away with the additional aid of the puppet beasts’ light beam attacks. Without an immediate succession of attacks from the transformed demon, the four friends were able to somewhat catch their breath.

Chapter 312: Reinforcements and Peace

“Ice Demon, it isn't because you find this guy displeasing to the eye but rather that you want me to pick a fight with Ye She!” The large bald man coldly said, glaring at the ice demon.

“Heehee! That could be true! Regardless, don’t you want to go see the school master? It would be best to go now. The school master has yet to start refining Qi from his latest blood sacrifice!” The white silhouette addressed the worry on the large man’s mind, changing the subject without care.

The large bald man clearly understood that the other party’s words were a slight towards him, but he simply snorted and walked into the darkness with large strides.

After turning several corners and walking through six or seven courtyards, the large man arrived at an extremely remote but expansive rock garden. At the sight of it, an expression of reverence had appeared on his face.

“Subordinate Tie pays respects to School Master!” The large man loudly greeted with a bow.

“So it’s Tie Luo! How were you wounded?”

A middle-aged man’s magnetic distant voice came from the rock garden where the Black Fiend School Master had secluded himself. It was likely that this was completely unthinkable to Han Li and the others.

“Many thanks for School Master’s concern, but this subordinate simply used the demon transformation technique. There is only a bit of damage to my vitality.” When the large bald man heard the school master’s words, he gave a careful reply.

For a moment, the school master didn’t immediately give a reply. After a long while, he faintly said, “From what I can see, this mission was a failure! Otherwise, my in-name disciple should have followed you back for the mission debriefing.”

“Please forgive me, School Master. This subordinate didn’t do his best to protect the young master and Protector Wang, both of whom fell into the enemy’s hands. This subordinate willingly receives the School Master’s strict punishment!” The large man gritted his teeth and said this with an appearance of shame.

“Punishment? Why would I punish you? Since you’ve already used the demon transformation technique, it clearly shows that this enemy was truly too strong. It wasn’t because you didn’t try your best. Besides, they were only a disciple and a protector, so losing them isn’t anything too terrible. If you, on the other hand, were to fall into the enemy’s hands, then I truly would have a headache!”

“Many thanks for School Master’s forgiveness. This subordinate will certainly do his utmost for School Master in order to make up for this failure!”

The Black Fiend School Master had skillfully won over his subordinate’s heart, stirring up emotions from the large bald man with his words. In response, the bald man immediately made a great display of loyalty.

“En, very good! But before anything else, tell me about the fight that occurred. I want to know which sect this cultivator came from. He is unexpectedly so fierce!” The Black Fiend School Master was clearly very satisfied with the large man’s words, but he still asked about Han Li with great curiosity.

“As you bid!” The large man hastily agreed.

“The techniques of the Foundation Establishment cultivator who we wanted to capture were extremely peculiar. He was unexpectedly able to control mechanical beast-like figurines. Furthermore, his strength was not lacking. At the time....” The large bald man thoroughly narrated the events of his fight with Han Li and how he used the demonic transformation technique when the situation turned sour.

After the large man finished, the rock garden was quiet for a moment. The Black Fiend School Master seemed to be thinking of something.

After a while, a clear and cold voice spoke.

“Based on the description of this cultivator’s control of figurines, this should be the puppet technique of the Thousand Bamboo School, and thus, he is likely a cultivator from this school. I heard earlier that a few Thousand Bamboo School cultivators had appeared within the borders of Yuan Wu. He is probably one of them. However, your intuition to immediately flee after your demon transformation was a very wise decision. Otherwise, you wouldn’t be speaking here with me now,” the Black Fiend School Master said indifferently.

“That can’t be! Although I am not confident that my transformed demonic body would be able to truly withstand his treasure talisman, were it not for the fact that I was unable to control my own body after the demonic transformation, I would have actually wanted to fight him! Even if I wasn’t his match, I would’ve completely been able to flee without harm,” the large man replied with some refusal.

“Tie Luo, I know that you were able to withstand a treasure talisman once before and came out unscathed. However, talisman treasures greatly differ in power from one another. Even if two treasure talismans were refined from the same magic treasure, their strength wouldn’t necessarily be the same. Also, with this treasure talisman’s strange appearance, I can conclude that you wouldn’t be able to endure his attacks even with your fiend demon transformation. If it were Qing Wen’s wood devil transformation, there may have been some chance of victory.” The Black Fiend Sect Master smiled warmly and gave the large man an explanation.

“Many thanks for School Master’s advice!” Still somewhat unconvinced, the large man still expressed his thanks with acknowledgment.

“School Master, how should we respond to this cultivator? Since the opponent isn’t a cultivator from the Seven Sects, should us four Blood Servants be dispatched to capture him alive and present him for School Master’s cultivation?” the large bald man eagerly asked. It was obvious he planned to find Han Li and settle the score.

“There’s no need! It was only a guess that he was a Thousand Bamboo School cultivator. I’m not completely certain, and he may have other helpers. Also, I am at a crucial point of my secluded cultivation and do not wish to provoke any great enemies. Confine all the disciples within the capital in the coming days and have them all remain at the Imperial Palace. These matters will be put off until I reach great success stage in my cultivation. Even if there are no Foundation Establishment cultivators to serve as blood sacrifices, it will only delay my progress by a few months. At that time, apart from Core Formation cultivators, no Foundation Establishment cultivator will be my match.” As the Black Fiend School Master said this, his originally flat tone became filled with excitement.

The Black Fiend School Master’s thoughts happened to be just as Han Li had anticipated.

“This subordinate wishes good fortune for School Master’s cultivation breakthrough to the great-success stage. This one will immediately arrange for the school disciples at the Imperial Palace to fortify the number of guards. We won’t allow them to disturb the School Master in the slightest,” the large man loudly declared with tact.

“Good, carry out the arrangements!”

After the Black Fiend School Master finished saying this, he seemed to be somewhat tired and didn’t say anything further. Thus, the large bald man respectfully took several steps back, turned around, and departed.

This location once again became an unremarkable corner of the cold palace.

……

Time passed by quickly. It was half a month since Han Li passed on the newly acquired intelligence.

At this moment, the Black Fiend School and Han Li had taken the same action and withdrew.

Since the Black Fiend School didn’t dispatch their troops to search wide for the Han Li's hideout, Han Li didn’t dare to break down the stalemate and rush into the Imperial City, showing his usual calm restraint. It appeared that nothing happened to both sides during this time.

It would be reasonable to say that the Devil Dao should have already shown themselves, but no information of them had appeared, causing Han Li to let out a great sigh of relief.

Han Li’s most feared scenario where the Black Fiend School and the Devil Dao would collaborate together and simultaneously stir up vile trouble did not occur. Han Li couldn’t help but secretly rejoice from this.

According to Han Li’s calculations, even if Li Huayuan sent people over, they would arrive in about ten days at the earliest. Thus, he calmly cultivated every day and didn't rashly go out. At Han Li’s suggestion, Qin Yan had also stayed in at the Residence for the past recent days and evaded invitations to go out, claiming that he wanted to deepen and enjoy familial ties.

But on the morning of this very day, as Han Li was meditating and refining Qi on his bed, He suddenly opened his eyes, exposing a trace of cold light.

“Which fellow Daoists have come to visit? There’s no need to be so secretive. Come out!”

After Han Li coldly said this, he patted his storage pouch and immediately took out the white scale shield, blocking his front. At the same time, his other hand grasped a fire cloud talisman. He appeared as if he were facing a great enemy.

What caused Han Li to act so seriously was the feeling of shock in response to the appearance of three to four Foundation Establishment cultivators lingering outside the door. Although they used Qi concealment magic techniques, Han Li, who cultivated the nameless chant, could faintly feel their presence.

Han Li thought to himself with astonishment, ‘Could it be that the four great Blood Servants of the Black Fiend School have all come?’

When this thought raced through his mind, Han Li endlessly complained to himself and immediately planned his escape. As for the Four Friends of Meng Mountain and those from the Qin Residence, Han Li couldn’t do anything for them; he could only leave them to find their own luck.

While Han Li’s mind was filled with these distracting thoughts, not a single magic tool or Daoist technique came from outside as Han Li had expected. Instead, he heard a bright and cheerful voice.

“Hehe! How about it? I said you wouldn’t be able to conceal yourselves from Junior Martial Brother! Young Junior Martial Brother has already entered mid Foundation Establishment. Don’t show off your mere skill in front of Junior Martial Brother Han.”

This was an extremely familiar voice to Han Li. His mind stirred as he loudly answered, “Could it be that Senior Martial Brother Song has arrived? Let Junior Martial Brother give you his greetings!”

Han Li’s words were filled with pleasant surprise.

“Junior Martial Brother, you’ve guessed correctly!” After the voice’s owner said this, he opened the door and strut into Han Li’s room; it was Han Li’s Fourth Senior Martial Brother, Song Meng.

Two men and a woman stood behind him. Apart from the serious appearance of a young handsome man, the other two looked at Han Li with a smile.

Among them, a man with a scholarly appearance said with a smile, “Eighth Junior Martial Brother, I’ve heard your name from Master. It’s unfortunate that Seventh Junior Martial Sister and I haven’t had a chance to meet you yet! Now that we’ve finally seen you in person, we’re astounded that you’ve cultivated so quickly and had already reached mid Foundation Establishment! I truly have no words to say.” The man clicked his tongue.

When that elegant woman standing by his side heard this, she concealed a chuckle and brightly sized up Han Li with curiosity.

Han Li took another glance at the man and woman, but he still didn’t recognize who they were. He immediately stood up from the bed and said with a respectful expression, “So it’s Third Senior Martial Brother and Seventh Senior Martial Sister! Junior Martial Brother has long heard of Senior Martial Brother and Sister’s great reputations. Unfortunately, I also haven’t had the chance to meet you. As for cultivation, Senior Martial Brother had entered mid Foundation Establishment far before me. How could this Junior Martial Brother compare?”

Han Li’s words were sincere and left a good impression on his Third Martial Brother.

Chapter 314: Meeting Together

When Han Li said this, Zhong Weiniang beamed with joy and couldn’t help but praise Han Li. Liu Jing also revealed a grateful expression.

As for Song Meng, he stepped forward and firmly patted Han Li on the shoulder two times. With a large smile, he said, “If I hadn’t already met you and you were actually unwilling to go, I certainly would have had a falling out with you. However, I already know Junior Martial Brother is a valiant figure!”

With that said, Song Meng glared coldly at Wu Xuan. It seemed that Wu Xuan truly did not have a good relationship with his fellow martial brothers!

When Wu Xuan saw this, he snorted and said, “Since it is like this, I will find a peaceful place and won’t disturb your grand event. I will tell Master everything that happened and hope that he doesn’t blame you!” Having said this, Wu Xuan expressionlessly walked out of the room and left the Qin Residence on his flying magic tool.

“Sixth Senior Martial Brother is truly outrageous. He actually ran away as soon as a battle approached. It’s unfortunate that he is my Senior Martial Brother!” Zhong Weiniang grumbled with great dissatisfaction.

“Enough. Everyone has their own ambitions, so don’t force him! We must make our plans and arrangements as soon as possible. The faster we move, the safer we will be. After all, who knows if the Black Fiend School Master is able to leave seclusion earlier than we originally thought,” Liu Jing solemnly added.

“Senior Martial Brother has much experience in exterminating degenerate cultivators.You plan it! We will act as you say. In any case, when the time comes, I am fine so long as I take part in the fighting!” Song Meng exclaimed with an excited appearance.

“Junior Martial Brother Song, you—!”

Liu Jing was rendered speechless by Song Meng’s complete lack of plans and was left not knowing whether to laugh or to cry.

Zhong Weiniang’s eyes became crescent moons as she smiled sweetly.

Han Li also faintly smiled and did not speak.

“Seventh Junior Martial Sister, you are quite familiar with Martial Senior Huiming’s disciple, Junior Martial Sister Chen. As such, it would be better if you were the one to go. Right now, she is at South Crow City. Please go and request their assistance!” After Liu Jing regained his composure, he calmly asked this of Zhong Weiniang.

“Junior Martial Sister Chen is also here? I haven’t seen her for some time. However, we have quite a good relationship. There should be no question about her assistance,” Zhong Weiniang replied with complete confidence.

When Han Li heard the words “Junior Martial Sister Chen”, his heart shook. He thought to himself in confusion, ‘What a coincidence! Is it really her?’

While Han Li was in doubt, he heard Liu Jing say something to him.

“Junior Martial Brother Han, I fear we will have to stay at the Qin Residence for a while longer. We will require you to contact the members of the Qin Residence and arrange a quiet residence for us, allowing for peaceful cultivation.” The Third Senior Martial Brother spoke calmly.

Han Li naturally agreed.

“Then what should I do?” Song Meng couldn’t help but impatiently ask.

“You will remain here and properly take care of the Qin Residence in case the Black Fiend School suddenly launches an attack. I will go to the streets from time to time and look for any movements from the Black Fiend School. Since Junior Martial Brother Han has already revealed their faces, it’ll be harder for us to find them in public,” Liu Ming answered indifferently.

“I understand!” When he heard this, Song Meng dispiritedly agreed.

The following days were extremely peaceful.

Apart from Zhong Weiniang departing for Nanwu City to request assistance, the others generally remained at the Qin Residence and cultivated. As for Third Martial Brother Liu Jing, he went out several times in accordance with his previous words. However, he didn’t acquire any useful information; it seemed as if all the Black Fiend School disciples had completely withdrawn themselves and went into hiding.

Wu Xuan was staying at an inn in Yuejing. Nobody knew what he wrote in his letter to Li Huayuan, but once he sent the letter, he casually and leisurely strolled through the bustling, lively parts of Yuejing without any thought of returning to the Qin Residence.

Nanwu City wasn’t very far from Yuejing, so in less than three days, Senior Martial Sister Zhong returned with three men and two women in tow.

Among these was an exceptionally cool and elegant woman whom Han Li recognized to be “Junior Martial Sister Chen”, Chen Qiaoqian. This caused Han Li’s heart to be on edge.

When Chen Qiaoqian saw Han Li, she revealed slight shock, but she didn’t say anything.

Even if they hadn’t spoken to one another, she was unable to consider Han Li to be a stranger.

The other three men and one woman were Chen Qiaoqian’s fellow apprentices. Two were at mid Foundation Establishment and two were at early Foundation Establishment. When they saw Liu Jing, they appeared very cordial. It seemed they all recognized him.

Zhong Weiniang introduced Han Li to everyone present as her newly accepted Junior Apprentice Brother. But after hearing Han Li’s name, the new arrivals apart from Chen Qiaoqian revealed expressions of amazement.

“You are Junior Martial Brother Han? You truly are quite young! We’ve all heard of Junior Martial Brother Han’s great reputation. A single person at the frontlines was able to kill over ten Foundation Establishment cultivators from the Devil Dao. Truly amazing!” Chen Qiaoqian’s Senior Apprentice Sister shouted with a sweet smile.

This beautiful twenty-seven year old woman appeared to greatly admire Han Li.

When these words left her lips, Liu Jing and Zhong Weiniang were greatly shocked.

These two had been earlier dispatched on assignments and didn’t participate in the second campaign between the Seven Sects and the Devil Dao. Naturally, they hadn’t heard of Han Li’s “great acts” in the slightest.

Now that they heard their acquaintances say this, they felt greatly shocked.

It should be known that although Third Senior Martial Brother had killed countless degenerate cultivators, he only killed two or three Foundation Establishment cultivators, each time being a bitter and long struggle for victory.

However, Han Li had unexpectedly accomplished the “great act” of killing over ten such Foundation Establishment cultivators, causing these two to feel astonished. They couldn’t help but size up this unremarkable Junior Martial Brother Han once more and feel far more respect toward him.

“Fourth Senior Martial Brother, we didn’t know about Junior Martial Brother Han’s accomplishments. Could you clearly explain why you never told me this?” After she recovered her shock, Zhong Weiniang suddenly thought of something and loudly scolded Song Meng, who was standing to the side, concealing his laughter with his sleeve. It was a rather harsh criticism!

“Junior Martial Sister, you never asked me. You only asked about Junior Martial Brother’s cultivation. I believed that Junior Martial Sister already knew about this,” Song Meng proudly huffed.

He had long since anticipated seeing the flabbergasted faces of his two fellow apprentices upon discovering this. As he expected, it was quite the view.

How could Zhong Weiniang not hear the half-heartedness contained in those words? She gave him a fierce glance. Even though she was unwilling to let the matter drop, Liu Jing stepped in and said with a large smile, “Good! I didn’t think that Junior Martial Brother Han was so exceptional! Like this, we should be able to handle the Black Fiend School Master with greater certainty.”

When he spoke these words, his face appeared overjoyed. However, Han Li felt a chill down his back. With great apprehension, he couldn’t help but think to himself, ‘Surely this Third Senior Martial Brother doesn’t want to have me duel the Black Fiend School Master by myself?’

Han Li immediately mocked himself for thinking such a ridiculous thought and threw it to the back of his mind.

Following that, Han Li and his Senior Martial Brothers feasted with Junior Martial Sister Chen and her fellow apprentices. Although they all had similar cultivation bases and could abstain from eating for long periods of time, they were now in the mortal world. Naturally, they would enjoy their present circumstances and satisfy their desire for good food.

After they finished eating, Han Li called for Qin Residence servants to clean up the feast. The group then started to discuss how to deal with the Black Fiend School and how to charge into the Imperial City.

Liu Jing immediately made it clear that he was willing to assume complete responsibility for violating the Seven Sects’ prohibition. Thus, Junior Martial Sister Chen and the others were relieved of their misgivings and agreed to go along with them.

Based on the intelligence Han Li acquired, apart from the four so-called Great Blood Servants, the odds of the other Altar Masters being present at the Imperial Palace were quite low since they were stationed in various parts of the State of Yue where they managed school affairs.

Thus, Liu Jing believed that with their current manpower, they were more than enough to handle the Black Fiend School, but they should nonetheless strike as soon as possible to prevent any future mishaps from emerging.

The others that heard this felt this was reasonable and proceeded to cultivate the entire following day as they were weary from travel. On the night of the second day, taking advantage of the mortals’ need to sleep, they would infiltrate the Imperial Palace in their plan to purge evil.

At this moment, Han Li looked at everyone talking excitedly with a smile on his face, but he couldn’t help but sneer in his heart.

These people truly believed the Black Fiend School was feeble and weak! How could this possibly end well!

After this great battle was concluded, it was hard to say how many of these people would still be left alive!

Were it not for the secrets he obtained from the young prince and the usefulness it would have toward his chances of entering Core Formation in the future, he absolutely wouldn’t make such a dangerous charge into the Imperial Palace. After all, he had no grudges against those who used the evil blood sacrifice technique to cultivate. All he had to do was leak information to the victims’ clans and friends; in turn, they would take revenge and completely settle this matter.

As for the principles of punishing the wicked, exterminating evil, and upholding justice, Han Li had always believed that acting in accordance to one’s capabilities was enough.

If there was no danger and he wouldn’t have to waste too much energy, he would be happy to act. But if his opponents were too strong and they had nothing to do with him, to risk his own life to handle someone else’s affairs made absolutely no sense!

Although the actions of his Sixth Senior Martial Brother Wu Xuan invited loathing from others, they weren’t disagreeable. Leaving aside his methods, his decision was truly wise. Else, one may act with hot-blooded passion and recklessly brave terrible dangers.

This time, Han Li had forced himself to agree to their charge into the Black Fiend School’s nest, violating his own principle of self-preservation. However, Han Li felt that this danger was worth braving.

Because Han Li’s spiritual roots were truly inferior, so long as there was something he could do to increase his chances of entering Core Formation, he was unwilling to let such a boon slip by his fingers. Furthermore, he was somewhat certain of his safe return.

This is because he had prepared a special trump card that could guarantee his own well-being. Otherwise, with Han Li’s meticulous caution, how else could he possibly agree?!

Chapter 318: Qing Wen’s Reappearance

“As expected, Han Li is far beyond ordinary, being able to find a hole so quickly. What is its weakness?” Liu Jing praised Han Li and amiably asked.

Han Li faintly smiled and suddenly handed the crystal ball over.

“Senior Martial Brother, look into this Violet Light Orb and you’ll understand.” Han Li pointed in the direction he had just looked at.

When Liu Jing heard this, he took the magic tool with great curiosity and carefully looked into it.

After he took a glance, Liu Jing revealed astonishment. After a short moment, he passed the crystal ball back to Han Li and lowered his head, muttering to himself.

Another moment passed by before he raised his head and anxiously said to the others, “Han Li’s words are true. For some unknown reason, the Spiritual Qi fluctuations in that direction appears much thinner. It seems that this formation was laid out in a hurry and exposed an unintentional flaw.” Liu Jing’s voice grew louder as if he were brimming with confidence.

“Then what does Senior Martial Brother Liu intend to do?” Chen Qiaoqian’s Senior Martial Sister couldn’t help but ask.

“Concentrate all of our attacks at the weak point. I am confident we will be able to break this formation without expending much magic power.” Liu Jing said with certainty.

“Since it is like that, we should act quickly!” When Song Meng heard this, he could no longer wait. He immediately raised his hand and released his “Blue Threaded Sword”, causing it to spin above his head.

The others wore expressions of eagerness after hearing Liu Jing’s words.

When Liu Jing saw this, he no longer hesitated and immediately exclaimed, “Good! Let’s break through this formation and give our enemies a show.”

After this was said, over ten magic tools emitted a dazzling radiance and fiercely shot toward the formation’s flaw.

……

Outside of the formation, the Ice Demon felt extremely anxious while commanding the school disciples to take up an encirclement formation.

Ever since the Black Fiend School Master had requested the four great Blood Servants to remain within the palace, they should have been taking turns to guard in pairs.

But Xie She, who was originally supposed to be on guard with him, had recently reached the Great Success stage in his cultivation. Using the excuse of wanting to immediately enter mid Foundation Establishment, he stealthily ran off to the blood prison to cultivate. As the Ice Demon was unwilling to offend the brilliant rising talent in the four Blood Servants, he had tacitly turned a blind eye.

However, that moment of neglect had left him alone while guarding the entrance against an invasion of so many strong enemies.

However, it was fortunate that he was quick-witted!

He first used this “Four Divisions Formation” to trap the enemy, and then dispatched disciples to the blood prison and the rear palace to quickly fetch the other three Blood Servants without delay.

He clearly understood that these few Qi Condensation disciples were no match against these strong enemies. But luckily, the enemy had been trapped within the Four Divisions Formation, buying quite a bit of time!

So long as he could stall for a bit of time, his three comrades would be certain to promptly arrive.

With the four great Blood Servants acting together, the Ice Demon would have nothing to be afraid of.

Just as he was thinking this, a loud rumbling vibration could be heard from within the Four Divisions Formation.

The thick white fog that filled the formation was then fiercely blown away, appearing as if the formation was about to be destroyed.

“What is this? It is impossible for the Four Symbols Formation to break so quickly. Something must’ve went wrong!” When the Ice Demon saw this, his pale face concealed by the cold Qi had turned somewhat green.

“Sir Ice Demon, the enemies had struck far too quickly. A few of the disciples that were in charge of the formation had died in the attack, causing the Four Symbols Formation to be insufficiently manned. It is possible that the enemy saw through the gap.” When a nearby Black Fiend School Disciple saw this, he carefully gave an explanation.

When the Ice Demon heard this, he became alarmed and furious. Just as he was about to loudly rebuke him, he heard a gentle voice from behind him.

“Ice Demon, what happened? The Four Symbols Formation had actually activated but it appears unable to hold the enemy.”

When the Ice Demon heard this, he immediately felt relieved.

“Qing Wen, it’s good that you’ve quickly arrived!” The Ice Demon couldn’t conceal his happiness and hastily turned his head to look at him.[1]

At an unknown time, two people had appeared about fifteen meters behind him.

One of them appeared thirty years old with a beardless and unremarkable face. He was wearing an azure Daoist robe and looked at the Four Symbol Formation’s strange condition with a solemn expression.

“Who is invading us? And where is that youngster, Xie She?” Tie Luo stroked his bald head with an expression of bloodlust.

“Right now, Xie She is...”

A huge rumbling from the Four Symbols Formation interrupted the Ice Demon. The Four Symbols Formation’s dense fog ruptured and completely disappeared, revealing the silhouettes of Han Li’s group.

After clearly seeing the number and cultivation of these invaders, Qing Wen’s complexion slightly darkened and Tie Luo appeared greatly astonished.

“Haha! You evil cultivators believed that a broken formation was able to trap us Yellow Maple Valley cultivators? That’s just wishful thinking!” After Song Meng appeared once more before the cold palace, he couldn’t help but loudly yell this with excitement.

“Yellow Maple Valley?”

Qing Wen and the other two were slightly startled. However, after a short moment of thought, they quickly recovered. Apart from the Seven Great Sects, who else could dispatch so many Foundation Establishment cultivators in the State of Yue?

“Why have you stormed the Imperial palace in the night? Could it be you are unafraid of violating the prohibition?” Without waiting for Liu Jing and company to speak, Qing Wen calmly asked.

He knew about the Seven Sects’ ban and hoped he could use this to cause Liu Jing’s group to become fearful of the consequences.

Liu Jing coldly snorted, and before he could open mouth, he heard an alarmed cry from the bald man.

“It’s you! Aren’t you from the Thousand Bamboo School? How are you together with the Yellow Maple Valley cultivators?” As the large bald man, Tie Luo, swept his gaze across them, he discovered Han Li among them and couldn’t help but loudly ask this with amazement and confusion.

These words left both enemies and allies stunned. In a flash, all eyes gathered upon Han Li.

At this moment, Daoist Priest Qing We had clearly recognized Han Li and couldn’t help but twitch his face. Disbelief could be seen in his eyes.

“When have I ever said that I was someone from the Thousand Bamboo School?” Han Li coldly gazed at the large bald man and then turned his glance toward Daoist Priest Qing Wen.

That year at the Great South Meeting, Qing Wen had urged Han Li to travel together with him. Surprisingly, Han Li now found him here.

As a result of this, he was able to answer the lingering questions from back then; namely, why Qing Wen made such great efforts to journey together with low grade cultivators and why that yellow-clothed man had pursued and attempted to kill Han Li.

Now understanding the entire story, Han Li was furious and felt an intense desire to kill to Qing Wen.

“Nonsense. If you aren’t from the Thousand Bamboo School, then why can you use puppet techniques?” The large bald man retorted, refusing to let the matter drop.

“Are we required to tell you the techniques that Junior Martial Brother Han is able to use? Everyone, attack! These people are deliberately stalling for time. Do not fulfill their wishes!” Liu Jing’s expression darkened before suddenly saying this with a stern voice.

With that said, he extended his arm and a streak of silver light directly attacked the Ice Demon in front.

Upon hearing this, the Yellow Maple Valley disciples suddenly realized and inwardly cursed the enemy’s craftiness. They then released their magic tools without restraint, and immediately joined the fight.

As Han Li had been staring at Daoist Priest Qing Wen earlier, he immediately performed a pincer attack with Chen Qiaoqian’s Senior Martial Brother Wang, in an attempt to trap Qing Wen.

Without speaking further, Han Li patted the storage pouch at his waist, causing over ten streaks of red, black, and golden light to simultaneous soar out. After they hovered above Han Li for a moment, they shot toward the enemy with the sound of a faint explosion.

Han Li didn’t bother speaking to Qing Wen as he didn’t have the slightest intention to reminisce about old times.

When Qing Wen and that Senior Martial Brother Wang saw Han Li’s display of immense strength, both of their expressions changed significantly.

Senior Martial Brother Wang revealed pleasant surprise, while inwardly praising Han Li. ‘As expected, Han Li’s reputation as an expert that had previously killed many Foundation Establishment cultivators was well-earned; he is truly outstanding!’

Daoist Priest Qing Wen revealed a cautious appearance and faintly shrouded his body in a layer of azure Qi. Upon seeing Han Li’s vicious actions, he knew Han Li intended to kill him. Naturally, he wouldn’t just wait for death like a sitting duck.

In turn, he also didn’t speak any rubbish before suddenly extending his hand toward the attacking magic tools.

Five azure bead magic tools flew from his hand and formed a pentagon around him in an instant.

Then, with a flash of azure light, Daoist Priest Qing Wen was enveloped in a cloud of azure mist as a pentagonal prism barrier appeared around him out of thin air, closely protecting him.

Han Li’s Golden Swarm Blades, Black Dragon’s Grasps, and Blazing Chain Tridents simultaneously struck Qing Wen’s pentagonal prism barrier, producing an explosion of blinding light. Bursts of radiance flew in every direction, yet the strange barrier was left unscathed from the attack.

“Han Li, my Azurewood True Barrier can only be broken by Core Formation cultivators. Foundation Establishment cultivators like yourself aren’t able to damage it in the slightest. You had best give up!” Qing Wen suddenly said this with a slight smile, speaking to Han Li in a very intimate manner.

[1]. Han Li previously met Qing Wen at the Great South Trade Assembly in Chapter 130: Becoming a Member.

[Back]

Chapter 320: Broken Cocoon

When the Yellow Maple Valley cultivators saw this, they were reminded of what Han Li had told them about the Blood Servants’ Demonic Transformation. They all knew that during their transformation, the Blood Servants would become easy, stationary targets. Thus, they launched magic tools and techniques, assaulting the four cocoons of light without restraint. Naturally, they wouldn’t let go of an opportunity like this to subdue the enemy.

Unfortunately, as Han Li had said, the light spheres were incredibly hard. Despite the violent storm of attacks, the cocoons remained intact. They didn’t appear to be even slightly damaged, causing the faces of the Yellow Maple Valley cultivators to become unsightly.

“Everyone, if you have any last resorts, use them! Do not hold back! If you don’t use them now, we will be in dire straits when they emerge from their cocoons!”

With that said, Liu Jing immediately withdrew his magic tools and solemnly took out a golden talisman, pressing it between his two hands. He started muttering a mysterious incantation, causing the talisman to radiate with inceasingly dazzling golden light.

Although Han Li didn’t know what grade that talisman was, he grew alarmed upon seeing it. Since Liu Jing, a mid Foundation Establishment cultivator, required an incantation to activate it, it meant that this talisman was no common item.

When the others saw this, they looked at each other and then revealed their hidden capabilities.

The most eye-catching among them were Song Meng and Chen Qiaoqian’s Senior Martial Sister. They both took out an inscribed treasure talisman and then immediately sat down to activate them. Blue and grey radiance emitted from their treasure talismans, causing those who looked on to feel envious.

Treasure talismans aren’t easy to acquire for Foundation Establishment cultivators, even with the backing of a large clan. Only those who were looked upon with great affection by their seniors would be granted them. Otherwise, with merely their own wealth and status, how could they possibly acquire such a treasure?

The others were unwilling to be outdone and made a display of their own. They either strenuously used impressive magic techniques or brought out wondrous magic tools for their attacks. Brilliance immediately filled the sky as their magic tools and techniques were chaotically flourished.

Han Li used neither his talisman treasures nor his astonishingly powerful “Giant Sword Technique”. Instead, he chose to use his most energy-efficient method. With a wave of his hands, several heavy objects fell to the ground in front of him, four of his puppet beasts.

The puppet beasts opened their ice-cold eyes and their bloodthirsty maws, fiercely shooting out several beams of light in a well practiced manner. Han Li stood behind them, taking advantage of the situation to restore the magic power used during the previous fight.

As he had yet to encounter that Black Fiend School Master, he wasn’t willing to use the entirety of his strength and prematurely exhaust his magic power.

Han Li intended to preserve his magic power in preparation for any contingencies in the upcoming battle. He had a few more hidden cards, but he wouldn’t reveal them until the time came.

The appearance of the puppet beasts had somewhat surprised the others, but they immediately went back to focusing on their own matters.

After all, the techniques one used and the magic arts one cultivated were one’s own secrets; nobody would be so tactless as to ask about them.

Those who knew the origin of the “Puppet Technique” would believe that Han Li had acquired it from Li Huayuan. As a Core Formation cultivator, it wasn’t difficult to imagine that he had killed several Thousand Bamboo School cultivators and acquired a few of their school’s magic arts along the way!

Thus, the others only felt at most great curiosity toward Han Li’s puppet beasts.

At this moment, Liu Jing’s golden talisman finished activating. Trembling lightly, it transformed into a streak of golden light before flying toward the blood-red light cocoons.

An explosion rang out as a burst of golden light created a snowstorm of luminous floating specks that filled the entire sky. The dazzling scene was as fantastical as a dream.

However, this beautiful marvel concealed an extremely sorrowful desire to kill. During this dazzling scene, Liu Jing formed an incantation gesture, causing the luminous specks in the sky to undergo a strange transformation. Gradually shrinking and expanding, they finally assumed shape of small golden swords. Although the swords were only an inch long, each one possessed a threateningly cold and incomparably incisive air.

“Thousand Blades Technique.”

Liu Jing said softly, revealing the name of his metal attribute magic technique.

Everyone who saw this scene, aside from the two who were focusing on activating their treasure talismans, was left stunned.

Metal attribute magic techniques were the rarest among the five elements, most commonly taking the form of defensive auxiliary magic techniques such as the “Golden Armor Technique” or the “Iron Skin Technique”. Liu Jing’s offensive metal attribute area magic technique exceeded expectations, leaving Han Li and the others dumbfounded. They all slowed their actions, wanting to witness the entirety of this marvelous spell.

Thousands of shining, sharp golden swords were suspended above the cocoons of light, emitting a frightening pressure.

Liu Jing then chanted the activation incantation, causing the small golden swords to hail down and stab into the spheres of blood-red light.

Pupu. Everyone heard a series of muffled stabs as the golden lights entered the blood-red spheres. Brilliance scattered in every direction like a dense storm of fireworks.

Under the other’s attacks, the light cocoons had displayed no change. But under this fierce attack, the cocoons began to gradually swell as if knowing the fearsomeness of this attack and responded by taking the initiative to reinforce the blood-red light as increasingly intense waves of light swords struck down.

When Liu Jing saw this, he felt neither joy nor worry. Since his attacks pressured the light cocoons to change, they were shown to be effective. So long as he increased the power of his attacks, he would be able to break through the blood-red light.

But at this moment, more than half of the small swords had already fallen and the light cocoons still appeared as red as they were at the start, looking as if they had handled the attacks with ease.

“Senior Martial Brother Liu, allow me to lend a hand!”

Song Meng shouted loudly.

The grey talisman in his hand transformed into a meter-long, gray spear that emitted a strange grey Qi.

“Let’s get rid of the Blood Servant on the left first; do not scatter our attacks.” Seeing that Song Meng had condensed the true form of his treasure talisman, Liu Jing said this with unsuppressed joy.

Soon after, he pointed at the small swords that had yet to fall.

Suddenly, the gold swords started falling in a dense barrage toward the cocoon of leftmost blood servant, the Ice Demon.

Following the rumbling sounds of impact, the cocoon of blood-red light seemed to have shriveled significantly.

Having seen this, the others joined in, using magic techniques and magic tools in a simultaneous attack. Song Meng followed with his grey spear, causing it to release a sharp chilling wail as it shot forth.

As the “Thousand Blades Techniques” and the others’ instantaneous attacks whittled away at the remaining thin layer of the previously invulnerable blood cocoon, the silhouette within could vaguely be seen.

The grey spear was able to finally penetrate the cocoon, causing a furious, deafening roar to echo in everyone’s ears. Two sharp, white crystal claws suddenly emerged from the blood-red light, immediately tearing away at the remaining shreds of the blood cocoon with ferocity and revealing the true appearance of the silhouette within.

It was a half demon-transformed, white monster.

At first glance, this person appeared to be an incomparably beautiful and refined youth. However, two small white horns protruded from the top of his head and a foot-long pure white tail sprouted out from behind him, each covered with faintly sparkling, white scales. In addition to his two extremely sharp claws, his entire body exhibited layers upon layers of demonic properties.

Two bowl-sized bloody holes were present on his shoulders. The flesh around them continuously squirmed and contracted, causing onlookers to feel their blood run cold. But in the blink of an eye, the bloody holes completely healed.

“You’re all courting death!” The half-transformed Ice Demon yelled fiercely. Clearly, he had retained enough of his mind to be able to speak.

Although he didn’t finish his demon transformation, he believed that with the demonic characteristics of his current body, he would be able to buy time for his companions to finish their transformations.

The complexions of Liu Jing and the others, who had yet to see the demonic transformation, paled after seeing this frightening appearance. Although they had previously heard Han Li mention the strange appearance of the Blood Servants’ demonform, they became extremely shocked and apprehensive upon seeing it with their own eyes.

Suddenly, several beams of white light struck the Ice Demon’s bare body and immediately sent it tumbling, causing it to appear quite battered.

Unwilling to hear the enemy’s rubbish, Han Li had immediately ordered his puppet beasts to attack.

When the others saw this, they came to their senses and madly resumed their barrage of attacks.

However, the Ice Demon that fell to the floor released a cold mist from its entire body. As the mist spread, he disappeared from his original location.

This left the others shocked, hastily looking in every direction.

According to their previous experiences, when such a scene occurred, the opponent had used an evasion technique and quickly escaped. However, such a technique wouldn’t have allowed them to flee far.

Not a single person could be seen near the three remaining light cocoons. The ordinary Black Fiend School Sect disciples had long fled as they weren’t foolish enough to remain.

When Han Li saw this, his heart trembled as he suddenly thought of something. He hastily patted his storage pouch, taking out his white scale shield and tortoise shell magic tools. He hurriedly had them revolve around his body as he loudly yelled, “Everyone, be careful! He concealed himself!”

Just as Han Li said this, a woman’s miserable shriek could be heard, causing everyone to hastily look in the direction of the scream in alarm.

They saw that Junior Martial Sister Chen’s Senior Martial Sister, who was originally sitting down activating the talisman treasure, was now lying on her back. A large hole had appeared on her chest as if someone had reached in and torn out her heart.

As she laid in a pool of her own blood, her beautiful appearance became slightly twisted as her limbs continuously thrashed about. Her eyes were filled with an incredulous fear before turning into unreconciled denial as her life slipped away.

Chapter 322: Liu Jing’s “Treasure Seal”

Han Li felt furious!

His anger wasn’t due to the fact that he had saved Senior Martial Brother Wang in a moment of benevolence, or even because he had to fully utilize his Shifting Smoke Steps. Han Li’s anger was due to the fact that Liu Jing and the others were squandering this opportunity to eliminate the three transforming Blood Servants. Once the three Blood Servants finished transforming, a huge dilemma would await them.

Han Li was reminded of Senior Martial Brother Wang’s kind assistance during his fight with Qing Wen, and thus, when Han Li noticed that Senior Martial Brother Wang was on the verge of falling in the Ice Demon’s scheme, he instantly flashed forward into order to save him.

Enraged from Han Li’s intervention, the Ice Demon immediately pursued him, forcing Han Li to deal with him. But soon after, Han Li felt that this Ice Demon would prove extremely troublesome for his fellow sect members and decided it would be better for him to take care of it alone. After all, if even more of his fellow sect members died, they would be lacking in numbers for the upcoming battle.

However, during his fight with the Ice Demon, he didn’t expect that the others would just stare blankly. They were actually squandering this great opportunity to attack the three remaining light cocoons!

Even so, Han Li had a faint feeling that the others didn’t even know this opportunity existed due to their fear of the Ice Demon’s ambush. Although they realized that having to deal with the fully transformed Blood Servants would be even more troublesome, they were still hesitant and slightly desired to retreat.

In reality, Han Li didn’t come here in order to eradicate the Black Fiend School but rather for another predetermined objective. As such, he was unable to run away in a rash manner. Ever since the half-transformed Ice Demon left his cocoon, he had been trying to kill Han Li. But Han Li found that so long as he was a bit careful, the demon did not pose much of threat to him. In fact, he felt that the large bald man was significantly harder to handle in comparison to the demon.

Following the transformation, the Ice Demon acquired a transparent body, exceptional speed, and some control over cold Qi. Thus, he was now able to utilise his speed to create an illusion of invisibility similar to that of the Shifting Smoke Steps. But due to the Ice Demon’s transparent body, he became even harder to detect.

Since this strange movement technique could only be displayed on land, as long as they were above ground, they could force the Ice Demon to reveal itself by using large scale magic techniques. After all, his high speed movements were only deadly within a short distance. It was unable to keep up with a cultivator’s flying magic tool.

Because Liu Jing and company had never experienced this kind of close combat, they felt that their opponent was extremely monstrous and difficult to engage. Fortunately, Han Li had often fought in this manner and naturally held greater experience in fighting such battles.

With that in mind, Han Li suddenly repelled the demon’s sharp claws with a wave of his silver sword, buying himself a short moment. He then stood still to become visible and he loudly yelled, “Everyone, fly to the skies and continue to attack the other three Blood Servants. I will prevent this demon from attacking you!” Following these instructions, Han Li’s figure suddenly flickered, disappearing from sight once more.

It was not surprising for Han Li that the silver sword — which had been looted during the Trial by Blood and Fire — was able to withstand the demon’s sharp claws. The fact that caused Han Li to become astonished was that the claws were also undamaged.

When Liu Jing heard Han Li’s instructions, he immediately understood what Han Li intended. Even so, he remained hesitant and felt extremely conflicted.

Although Liu Jing originated from a large cultivation clan, he had been captured by evil cultivators during his childhood. During that time, he suffered from extreme, agonizing torment to the extent where he had almost lost his life. It was only afterwards that he was rescued by his clan and was apprenticed to Li Huayuan.

Due to the trauma he had experienced in his childhood, Liu Jing held deep hatred toward evil cultivators. As a result, he followed an iron-blooded policy to kill all evil cultivators on sight, refusing to allow any evil cultivator from escaping his grasp, regardless of what freakish techniques they practiced.

Much to his delight, these actions rewarded him with great popularity among other cultivators, even causing a few Seven Sect cultivators with higher cultivation than him to look at him with a trace of admiration.

Although Liu Jing continued to appear unfazed on the outside, his heart gradually began to indulge in these feelings of admiration. In fact, he later took the initiative to root out evil cultivators from every direction mostly for the sake of seeing others gaze upon him with admiration.

Naturally, Liu Jing hid this fact in the depths of his heart with extreme care and conducted himself as though he were a moral paragon. Thus, Liu Jing became known as an enemy of evil, the “iron-blooded” Senior Martial Brother Liu.

Now that another evil known as the Black Fiend School had appeared, he was compelled to eliminate it. However, they were the strongest evil cultivators he had ever encountered. He wasn’t completely confident that he would be able to rely on his normal magic tools to eliminate the three remaining blood servants. His attack power was lacking and would only serve to end their transformations earlier, resulting in three more half-demons to fight.

One half-transformed demon was already very difficult to handle. They did not know if they could handle additional half-demons or if they would just be throwing their lives away.

But if they were to retreat now, they would have just scared the Black Fiend School away, resulting in the complete failure of their mission. If they allowed the Black Fiend School to disappear without a trace and conceal themselves once more, Liu Jing’s painfully nurtured reputation would be thoroughly and irrevocably destroyed.

The thought of others looking upon him with contempt caused Liu Jing to feel winded and extremely depressed.

Han Li’s exhortation had forced him to make a choice.

“Senior Martial Brother Liu, should we retreat?! The Black Fiend School is far stronger than we’ve imagined. If we’re going to retreat, we must do it now or else it will be too late!” Senior Martial Brother Wang softly said after approaching hesitantly.

Liu Jing could clearly see cowardice from Martial Brother Wang’s shifting gaze.

‘Retreat? If I retreat now, then I’ll appear just as cowardly!’ Liu Jing thought with a bitter smile.

“Everyone, fly to the skies and protect me as I cast my magic. Let me deal with the three Blood Servants!” Liu Jing instructed.

At the same time, he thought, ‘It seems I’ll have to use my life-saving measure in this fight! Otherwise, I won’t be able to win and preserve my reputation!’

“Senior Martial Brother Liu, you want to deal with the Blood Servants by yourself?”

However, when the others heard Liu Jing’s words, they all looked at him in disbelief, causing Liu Jing to feel a bottomless ache in his heart. But still, his appearance remained calm. Without speaking, he flew directly to the sky on a magic tool as he solemnly retrieved a fire-red jade box from his storage pouch.

At this moment, Liu Jing had completely recovered his calmness as if he were in complete control. When the surrounding disciples saw this, they glanced at each other and felt slightly more confident as they followed after him.

A reluctant look covered Liu Jing's face as he stared at the jade box in his hand. But soon after, his expression became resolved and he placed his hands on the box.

In an instant, the jade box shattered apart into miniscule pieces, revealing a peculiar talisman covered in red light.

A fire-red flame bird was inscribed on the talisman; it incessantly flapped its wings as though it was flying freely like a real bird. The bird’s glowing blue eyes even occasionally shifted.

The most astonishing fact was the scorching Qi the talisman emitted; it caused the temperature within thirty meters to abruptly rise, leaving his allies parched from the scorching heat.

Song Meng and the others approached and saw the astonishing scene of the talisman unfold.

“Treasure talisman!” Song Meng exclaimed upon seeing the talisman.

“No, this isn’t a common treasure talisman. This is.... a Treasure Seal!” After seeing the talisman’s strange appearance, Senior Martial Brother Wang cried out as if he had just seen a ghost.

Those who knew of this “Treasure Seal” were dumbstruck.

While this so-called “Treasure Seal” was considered a treasure talisman, it was completely different from common treasure talismans.

First of all, common treasure talismans only contained a tenth of the original magic treasure’s might at most. However, a Treasure Seal defied this convention, allowing it to contain a third of a magic treasure’s might!

Secondly, treasure seals could only be refined with the bloodline of the magic treasure’s master. As a result, only descendants of this specific bloodline would be able to activate and make use of this talisman. If someone else were to attempt to use it, the talisman would destroy itself.

With such great benefits, there naturally had to be some significant disadvantages; otherwise, all the elders would leave their later generations with only treasure seals.

While treasure seals contained several times more power than a ordinary treasure talismans, its greatest flaw was that it could only be used once. This single use would display the entirety of its might without restraint and leave no second use. As a result, it was far less practical than common treasure talismans.

Additionally, there was another reason as to why so few treasure seals were passed down.

After a magic treasure went through the process of bloodline refinement in order to produce a treasure seal, the magic treasure would suffer permanent and irrecoverable loss in strength. After knowing these restrictions, elder cultivators felt it would be far better to leave behind several ordinary treasure talismans for their descendants rather than ruining their own magic treasures which were as precious to them as their own lives.

Thus, many cultivators joked that there were several times more magic treasures in the cultivation world than treasure seals. Although these words were slightly exaggerated, they weren’t far from the truth!

Chapter 324: The Black Fiend School Master

The blazing fire-bird flew over twenty meters into the air and pecked at Qing Wen with its huge beak, turning him into a huge, plummeting fireball. When he landed on the ground, he only managed to wretchedly scream twice before turning into a pile of ash without the slightest resistance.

As Han Li watched on in complete astonishment, the huge fire-bird sharply cried out. Turning its head toward the two remaining light cocoons, it fiercely charged toward them. As a result, a huge pillar of fire erupted into the sky from the location of the cocoons. The two nearly-transformed Blood Servants were instantly engulfed in an ocean of fire.

The light cocoons were only able to bitterly resist the raging flames for a short moment before completely disappearing. The defenseless Blood Servants then silently swayed for several steps before completely turning to ash.

The blazing flame appeared extraordinary. Its unexpected ferociousness greatly shocked Han Li, leaving him with another memory of a Core Formation cultivator’s magic treasure’s might.

Apart from Han Li, his fellow cultivators all had expressions of pleasant surprise.

“That treasure seal was incredibly powerful!”

“We were able to eradicate this evil school all because of Liu Jing!”

……

The others excitedly spoke to each other in great excitement.

From their point of view, with the Blood Servants eliminated, all they had left to deal with was the Black Fiend School Master. As a group of many Foundation Establishment cultivators, there was no reason to believe that they wouldn’t be able deal with a lone evil schoolmaster.

As Liu Jing saw the fire-bird’s raging flames gradually disappear, he greatly lamented; but after hearing the other’s praises, his spirits were raised!

“We’ve wasted quite a bit of time. Let’s enter and exterminate the Black Fiend School Master!” Liu Jing waved his arm with a mighty, heroic air.

The others nodded in agreement and followed after him.

Han Li faintly smiled but as he was about to follow after them, he spotted Senior Martial Brother Wang blankly staring in some direction with a strange expression.

This somewhat surprised Han Li and he couldn’t help but follow Wang’s gaze. Aside from the white ash of the transformed Blood Servants and the pitifully arranged remains of Xue Hong, what else could he be looking at?

“Senior Martial Brother Wang, did you discover something?” Han Li couldn’t help but doubtfully ask.

“No, no I didn’t discover anything. Junior Martial Brother Han, you are being overly suspicious!” When Senior Martial Brother Wang heard Han Li’s question, he immediately shifted his gaze before answering.

When Han Li saw this, how couldn’t he tell that something was strange? This person had certainly discovered something important but didn’t want to tell the others. Why else would he act like this?

Han Li became somewhat depressed but with a slight smile, he said, “Since it is nothing, let’s quickly descend. Everyone wishes to go in!” Pointing in the direction of the cold palace, Han Li wordlessly descended, leaving Senior Martial Brother Wang to be the last one remaining in the sky. Uncertainty and doubt fluctuating on his face, he eventually stomped his foot and helplessly followed after them.

As Han Li landed on the ground, he heard a lovely voice from the sky.

“Senior Martial Brother Liu, Junior Martial Brother Han, wait for us!”

After a moment of surprise, Han Li slowly turned his head toward the sky. When the others heard this, they stopped and looked in the direction of the voice with happy expressions.

Underneath the soft moonlight, Zhong Weiniang and Chen Qiaoqian were slowly descending from the sky with an extremely pale middle aged man in tow, suspended by his collar on the flying magic tool.

The middle aged man wore golden clothes and had a deathly pale complexion. When he saw Han Li and the others, he appeared to become even more panicked.

When Liu Jing saw them, he welcomed them with a slight smile.

“It seems that you two were able to smoothly succeed! So this is the Emperor of Yue!” After the two female cultivators landed, Liu Jing turned his gaze to the middle aged man and asked without paying much mind.

“That’s right! This guy was in meeting with a few officials in some hall. After Senior Martial Sister and I knocked out the officials and grabbed the Emperor, two Qi Condensation disciples rushed out in an attempt to stop us, but we were able to easily dispatch them. Senior Martial Brother Liu, it seems you haven’t encountered any problems either. That’s great!”

When Zhong Weiniang saw Liu Jing was completely unharmed, she incessantly chattered, expressing unmistakable concern for him. This caused Liu Jing to appear embarrassed, much to the entertainment of Han Li.

“Junior Martial Sister Chen, are you also alright?” Two of Chen Qiaoqian's Senior Martial Brothers asked cordially.

With an indifferent expression, Chen Qiaoqian confirmed this and swept her gaze past the group. When she saw Han Li, she stared at him for a moment before turning away with a complicated expression.

“Where is Senior Martial Sister Xue Hong?” Chen Qiaoqian wrinkled her delicate brow and asked with a feeling of foreboding.

When those words were asked, everyone’s faces sank, revealing a heavy expression.

“We lost Xue Hong in the battle.” With great difficulty, Senior Martial Sister Xue Hong’s Dao Companion said this with a voice full of sorrow.

As soon as they heard this, Chen Qiaoqian and Zhong Weiniang’s expressions instantly became unsightly.

Zhong Weiniang immediately became furious, saying, “How could you...”

However, she was only able to say half of that sentence before she was interrupted by a miserable cry.

Han Li and the others were frightened and immediately looked in the direction of the scream with great vigilance.

A blue-robed man had appeared near them at an unknown time. They saw his hand flicker with red light as he withdrew it from Senior Martial Brother Wang’s chest. In the following moment, Martial Brother Wang’s lifeless corpse then fell to the ground.

“I originally hadn’t thought to kill you. However, children really shouldn’t take what isn’t theirs!” The blue-robed man said with a beaming smile. He appeared about forty years old and had a very fair complexion. With his slight wrinkles at the corner of his eye, he had a rather benevolent appearance.

With that said, he bent over and picked up a thumb-sized azure bead from the corpse, causing his smile to grow even larger.

After they saw this person, Liu Jing and Han Li’s faces sunk at the same time, revealing expressions of extreme caution.

“Your esteemed self must be the Black Fiend School Master!” Liu Jing probingly asked with a thoughtful expression.

“Hehe, how smart! I truly am the founder of the Black Fiend School. So, you must be the leader!” The old man chuckled.

When they all heard that this person was supposed to be the Black Fiend School Master, even Han Li couldn’t help but appear shocked. Each of the Yellow Maple Valley cultivators then took out their magic tools as they faced this great enemy.

After Liu Jing’s expression sunk, he deeply exhaled and suppressed the panic in his heart.

Soon after, he stealthily made a careful gesture to the others and coldly asked, “Correct. I am Liu Jing, the leader of this mission! I’ve come to exterminate your evil Black Fiend School. Even now that you are alone, you still dare to violently kill. You are truly courageous!”

Liu Jing said this awe-inspiring, righteous speech in a fearless display. Although he was very satisfied with his own performance, he became even more imposing as he continued.

So long as he eliminated this evil school’s master, his name would reach even greater heights among the Seven Sects. In turn, others would look upon him with even greater reverence and admiration.

With that thought, Liu Jing’s mind gradually became drunk with fervor, and he took out two silver hooks along with a ring.

Without waiting for the opposition to act, the Black Fiend School Master suddenly flashed a strange smile to him and softly whispered to Liu Jing in a voice only he could hear, “Then you can die!”

At that moment, Liu Jing felt a pain from the center of his chest. Without knowing what had happened, a blood-drenched arm had already pierced through his chest, revealing a round squirming object in its hand.

‘What is this?’ Liu Jing couldn’t help but think this in amazement. Perhaps he truly understood what happened, but he was unwilling to believe it.

Soon after, he felt the world spin around him and his vision turned black. He could still hear several shrieks and the mourning cries from his unrequited admirer, Zhong Weiniang. However, those sounds became increasingly unfamiliar and distant as time passed.

‘Sigh, this young girl really loves to cry!’ Liu Jing had one last, anguished thought before sinking into eternal darkness.

Han Li’s expression became very unsightly. Before the battle even started, the enemy had already killed two mid Foundation Establishment cultivators. Even Liu Jing, the leader of the group, had actually died so easily.

With hands stabbed through the corpses of Liu Jing and Senior Martial Brother Wang, Liu Jing’s attacker flashed toward the Black Fiend School Master’s side and flashed an evil grin toward them. This had happened so fast that Han Li had been unable to react.

After Liu Jing died, Zhong Weiniang was thoroughly stunned and was only able to release heart-wrenching screams. When Chen Qiaoqian saw this, she hastily pulled Zhong Weiniang behind her in an attempt to protect her. She then looked at the attacker with a face filled with fury and remorse.

Chapter 326: Blood Spirit Drill

Han Li didn’t look at the Emperor of Yue’s resentful gaze. Instead, he looked at the darkened bloody light that remained on his body.

A golden ruler, a pair of jagged purple blades, and a blue longsword floated within the bloody light. They were the magic tools of Song Meng and company.

At this moment, they were motionless within the bloody light. It seemed they had completely lost their spirit.

Han Li’s eyes flashed with thoughtfulness; it seemed the devilish light protecting the Emperor of Yue’s body was capable of corrupting common magic tools. The only item Han Li currently had on hand that could resist this evil technique was the Black Dragon’s Grasps.

Until now, the only person to appear from the cloud of debris was the Emperor of Yue. It appeared as though the blue-robed man, who had claimed to be the Black Fiend School Master, had truly died from the Heavenly Lightning Seed.

With that thought, even though Han Li’s heart relaxed, he had no intention of giving the enemy an opportunity to catch his breath. Han Li immediately issued a mental order to his puppets to start their attack, launching an unending barrage of light beams and arrows toward the enemy.

Now fearful of losing even more of their magic tools, the group of Yellow Maple Valley Cultivators chanted incantations and formed hand seals instead, continuously throwing down magic techniques and talismans alongside Han Li’s attack. They all understood that the only way to free themselves from this nightmare would be to strike with all their might. Otherwise, even more of them would suffer tragic ends.

When the Emperor of Yue saw this, he expressionlessly swept his arm in front of him. A huge shield of blood-red light appeared, easily blocking the oncoming attacks. However, the bloody light emitted from his body was becoming increasingly weaker and gave the impression that it might fail at any time. This caused Han Li and company to attack with even more fury.

The Emperor of Yue coldly snorted as he wordlessly took out a small dark green bottle from his bosom.

He nimbly tossed out a scarlet, longan-sized pill from the bottle that reeked of blood. It didn’t appear to be any sort of good medicine, but he still threw it into his mouth without the slightest hesitation and threw the bottle away; it actually only held a single medicine pill.

Once the scarlet pill reached the Emperor of Yue’s stomach, Han Li witnessed a shocking scene. The Emperor of Yue’s expression shook and his bloody light became brilliant once more. In addition, his wounds were healing at a speed visible to the eye. In that short moment, Han Li watched as the enemy recovered all of his magic power and healed all of the wounds he received from the Heavenly Lightning Seed.

“Damn it! How could such a thing happen!” When Song Meng saw this, he muttered in disbelief, forgetting to throw out his tens of already prepared ice spikes.

Han Li also couldn’t believe his eyes. He didn’t know what pill the opponent took but it had heaven-defying effects.

He had read all sorts of ancient books, but none of them had mentioned something like this!

“He used a Cultivation Essence Pill. A life saving medicine pill that can only be refined after cultivating several particular devilish arts and by harming one’s own cultivation. This pill can only be used by its creator as it is fatal for anyone else who takes it.” A clear, cold voice came from Chen Qiaoqian’s side, leaving Han Li stunned. Even Chen Qiaoqian turned around with a faceful of surprise.

“Senior Martial Sister Zhong, you’re alright!”

“I’m fine! However, the demon that killed Senior Martial Brother Liu is before my eyes and I must kill him!” Zhong Weiniang had finally come to her senses. She smiled with great difficulty at Chen Qiaoqian, before saying this with a cold expression.

“We all wish to kill him. But the problem is that he wishes to do the same to us!” Han Li indifferently replied without turning his head.

Zhong Weiniang turned and looked below in surprise. What she saw suddenly caused her expression to become unsightly.

As they were talking, the Emperor of Yue, who was below them, withdrew his shield of light. The bloody light that surrounded his body surged and expanded until it was about ten meters thick. The magic tools that were trapped within the bloody light had then started to gradually melt away.

The radiance protecting his body was now several times larger and his cultivation was far greater than it was previously. As such, the bloody light on his body was now able to easily resist the assault of magic techniques and puppet attacks.

The Emperor of Yue raised his head to stare solely at Han Li with ice-cold eyes. He abruptly reached his hand out from behind him and grabbed at the air. A fire-red bead then suddenly flew out from somewhere and accurately dropped into his hand.

Seeing this, Han Li’s eyes flashed with surprise as he thought of the blue-robed man that had died from his Heavenly Lightning Seed. It seems that this bead was from his remains and now the “Five Elements Blood Cores” could be considered complete. So long as Han Li could kill this fiend, he would be able to acquire this treasure that would greatly benefit his Core Formation.

“Boy, do you have any more Heavenly Lightning Seeds? If you have them, then I’ll stand right here and receive them. I want to see whether your Heavenly Lightning Seeds or my protective devilish art is greater.” The Emperor of Yue carefully put the bead away and said this to Han Li in a cold voice.

Once those words left his mouth, the Yellow Maple Valley cultivators were startled and couldn’t help but look at Han Li.

Han Li’s expression didn’t change, but he inwardly snorted. He calmly replied, “This one is also quite curious whether you are the Black Fiend School Sect Master, or if that other person was. Furthermore, it appears from the current circumstances that your esteemed self had previously absorbed over half of his cultivation before you were interrupted! I am quite puzzled as there are rarely such people willing to act as a sacrifice in this world.”

Han Li didn’t answer his question but asked a question in return. He returned derision with derision!

When the Emperor of Yue heard this, he revealed a strange expression that resembled both regret and mockery. But soon after, for some unknown reason, his face appeared increasingly menacing as his eyebrows became downward slanted.

Han Li’s heart trembled and he opened his mouth slightly, quietly sending the four remaining Yellow Maple Valley cultivators a sound transmission that left them shocked.

Having finished that, Han Li then indifferently said, “Whether or not you believe my words is up to you!”

Han Li didn’t use sound transmission for that last sentence, allowing the Emperor of Yue to clearly hear him. The Emperor’s face grew cold, and he suddenly pointed a finger at Han Li, shooting a beam of red light as thick as a thumb toward him in an instant.

Although the red beam of light was astonishingly quick, Han Li was still barely able to cause both his white scale shield and tortoise shell to superimpose in front of him. Soon after, a barrier of blue light covered his body. Han Li didn’t dare to be careless against this unknown attack.

Pupu . When Han Li heard this, he unconsciously leaned to his side, before feeling heat in his right shoulder, followed by acute pain.

After seeing a bleeding, finger-sized hole in his shoulder, Han Li’s face became unsightly.

He licked his dry lips and turned his gaze toward his two magic tools with disbelief.

A similar, small hole appeared on the superimposed white scale shield and the tortoise shell; the red light had penetrated both of them without resistance. As for the Azure Essence Sword Shield on his body, it didn’t have the slightest of effect. Upon contact with the attack, it completely dissolved without a trace.

What Han Li saw caused his heart to drop!

If his body wasn’t nimble from his long practice with the Shifting Smoke Steps, then his heart would’ve been struck and he would’ve died immediately. A single moment of carelessness like this could cause anyone to lose their life!

The more Han Li thought of this, the greater the fear he felt.

Although he knew that the Emperor of Yue had absorbed a majority of the blue-robed man’s magic power, the Emperor’s drastic increase in strength was far beyond his expectations.

However, Han Li didn’t know that as he was stricken by fear from his near death experience, the Emperor of Yue was even more amazed that Han Li had survived his strike.

Although it appeared that his last move appeared effortless to use, this “Blood Spirit Drill” was actually a single use move. Only after compressing one’s true essence by several tens of times would one be able to unleash this surprise killing move.

This was one of the devilish arts’ killing moves that he cultivated. Not only was the preparation for this unbearably painful, it also required far too much time.

When the Emperor had previously used this technique, not a single cultivator had managed to survive it. But now, Han Li was merely lightly injured from it; how could he not be shocked!

Only one Blood Spirit Drill remained within his body. He hesitated, unsure whether or not to use it on Han Li once more.

When the Yellow Maple Valley cultivators saw that Han Li was injured from the recent attack, their expressions vastly changed.

Unconsciously, Han Li had already become their pillar of support. For him to be injured so unexpectedly greatly alarmed them.

“Go!” Han Li spit this out without the slightest hesitation after he shifted his gaze away from his wound.

He madly poured magic power into his Divine Wind Boat and swiftly flew off to the side.

When Song Meng and the others heard this, they gave each other a mutual glance before following Han Li’s orders to flee.

When the Emperor of Yue saw this, he was initially surprised, but then sneered soon after.

He flashed forward into the air, wanting to chase after Han Li. However, he now saw that over ten uniquely shaped puppets had surrounded him.

Chapter 329: Exterminating the Enemy

When Song Meng and company saw the Emperor of Yue attack the cross-legged Han Li, their hearts grew shocked. Although they were aware of their inability to affect the saber’s attack, Song Meng and company still raised their arms in defiance. In hopes of slowing down the attack, they unleashed a torrent of fireballs and threw eight talismans which transformed into huge stones.

Unfortunately, their attacks were of no effect; with a light swing, they were easily swept away by the saber’s huge radiance and had completely vanished without a trace.

The saber streak changed direction once more and fiercely chopped down with vicious intent.

As Han Li saw the sharp saber streak about to strike him, his expression didn’t change except for forming a slight sneer.

When the Emperor of Yue saw that Han Li was so calm, he was startled for a moment. Without thinking much more, he continued chopping down with the saber streak.

The Emperor struck at thin air, as Han Li had suddenly disappeared.

He discovered that he had returned to his original position at an unknown time, about a hundred meters above the barrier of rainbow light.

The Emperor of Yue’s appearance became extremely unsightly, and he struck at the rainbow light while clenching his teeth. As the Emperor split open a hole and charged in, he saw Han Li indifferently gazing at him while still seated in his original position.

This time, the Emperor of Yue didn’t impulsively charge down. Instead, his entire body trembled, shooting out a huge beam of bloody light with astonishing momentum. He immediately followed this up with a black saber streak.

Since the Emperor of Yue had prepared himself, he was able to clearly observe what followed.

When the bloody light was about three meters away from Han Li’s head, it disappeared without a trace as if it had been swallowed by something. At that same moment, he felt his devilish light suddenly return to its original location above him.

The Emperor of Yue was astonished. Naturally, his following strike wasn’t effective in the slightest. Once again, he was outside and high above the rainbow light.

The Emperor’s face turned pale, revealing panic for the first time.

He no longer charged downward and instead continuously waved the demonic Black Blood Saber. Endless streaks of crescent saber light flew in every direction in an attempt to break through the formation.

Not long after the saber streaks flew off, a flash of white light caused the attacks to shoot back towards their original location. He was flustered for a moment before furiously continuing his incisive attacks.

If the Emperor of Yue had been able to escape formation, he would have believed it contained a mere illusion technique and wouldn’t have felt so anxious. If this were the case, he could easily break through this minor formation by relying on his devilish arts. But now that he was being teleported and his formidable attacks were being bounced back, he felt his heart plummet!

Only great formation spells known as the “Great Unbreakable Formations” would have this type of restriction.

Already perturbed by this abysmal turn of events, the Emperor of Yue felt a powerful surge of Spiritual Qi from the rainbow light barrier below him, causing his heart to tremble. He tightened his grip on the black saber and his bloody light hastily revolved around him, enveloping him in an impenetrable, blood-red whirlwind.

Another two equivalently powerful spiritual pressures surged from within the rainbow light. Soon after, the rainbow light hummed for a moment and opened a three meter wide passage.

A dense cloud of small azure rods swarmed through the passage and rushed toward the Emperor of Yue in a grand torrent. These rods were from the azure rod treasure talisman Han Li had just activated.

Closely following the cloud of rods, a small blazing sword and a yellow crystal ball flew out.

After the two exited the passage, they underwent a strange transformation. The small red sword grew incredibly large, and the crystal ball emitted a blinding yellow light.

Under Chen Qiaoqian’s and Zhong Weiniang’s control, the two treasure talismans silently split into different directions, attempting to flank the Emperor.

As he watched these events unfold, the Emperor’s face grew ashen. He madly flourished the Black Blood Saber in his hand and shot out eight huge saber streaks from within the whirlwind. With a sharp crackle of explosions, a majority of the small rods smashed into pieces upon meeting the attack.

Han Li’s face turned slightly white. Because his mind was connected to the rods created by the treasure talisman, he had suffered damage from the strikes.

This blood saber was powerful beyond expectation. But fortunately for Han Li, he didn’t have to forcefully defend against its blows.

As for the Emperor of Yue, he was currently making his last stand.

Even with the obstruction of the saber streaks, the small red sword, the yellow crystal ball, and the remaining swarm of azure rods were able to seize an opportunity to charge into the bloody wind.

A storm of sharp whistles immediately rose from within the whirlwind as countless bursts of azure, red and yellow radiance surged against the black streak in confrontation. It was clear that the struggle within was incomparably intense!

Suddenly, an abrupt yell of fury burst forth, accompanied by the sound of an explosion. The black, red, and yellow streaks of light all violently flashed for a moment before completely disappearing from the blood-red whirlwind. At that same moment, the complexions of Chen Qiaoqian and Zhong Weiniang paled and their eyes became spiritless.

“Seventh Junior Martial Sister, are you alright?” When Song Meng saw this, he hastily asked with concern.

“It’s nothing; his blood saber is just truly demonic. It was actually able to take down my and Zhong Weiniang’s treasure talismans in mutual destruction. Now we will have to see whether or not Junior Martial Brother Han’s treasure talisman will be able to kill him.” Chen Qiaoqian softly said. She took out two blue medicine pills, swallowing one and handing the other to Zhong Weiniang.

“Your treasure talismans were destroyed?” When the other Yellow Maple Valley Cultivators heard this, their expressions became astonished. In their minds, only magic treasures should be able to contest with treasure talismans.

“Impressive! I suspect our enemy’s demonic saber is actually a ruined fragment of some kind of magic treasure.” After Zhong Weiniang swallowed the pill, her face became flushed and her lips reddened.

“The ruined fragment of a magic treasure? How is that possible?” Chen Qiaoqing asked with astonishment.

A series of earth trembling booms suddenly rang out from above them, causing them to hastily look up in surprise.

Separated by a thin layer of rainbow light, a great battle consisting of dazzling, chaotic bursts of azure and blood-red light was occurring above them.

After a short moment, the bloody light greatly lessened and was thoroughly overwhelmed by the azure light.

Afterwards, all traces of light had gradually disappeared, revealing the Emperor of Yue standing upright.

His face had a vacant expression and his lips were trembling much like a piece of porcelain about to collapse. The Emperor fell straight from the sky without resistance, and softly landed on the rainbow light above them; his body nothing more than a pile of crushed flesh.

Having seen this, all of Han Li’s fellow sect members were rapt with joy. Song Meng even went over to Han Li and excitedly yelled, “Junior Martial Brother Han! You’ve killed that monster! I knew you could do it!”

“I released the entirety of my treasure talisman’s strength in a single instance to break through his bloody light. Otherwise, it might’ve taken quite a while.” Han Li faintly smiled and spoke with a content tone.

Being able to draw out such a great amount of an treasure talisman’s might in a single instance wasn’t something that everyone could do. Only after using and seeing so many distinct treasure talismans did Han Li receive the experience to do this.

Although such an incisive method to take down the enemy greatly decreased the number of uses for a treasure talisman, its power would explosively increase. Such a method proved extremely effective against powerful enemies!

Han Li had just comprehended this method a few days ago and was able to use this technique when it was least expected. As a result, he was able to deal the finishing blow to his heavily injured enemy.

Naturally, this treasure talisman was fully consumed in the process and turned to ash.

At this moment, those “Fire Elements Blood Cores” were at the forefront of his mind. After saying a few words to Song Meng, he released two puppet beasts without any hesitation and had them directly head over to the Emperor of Yue’s corpse.

When the others saw this, they didn’t mind in the least. After all, the death of this enemy was almost entirely due to Han Li; naturally, no one would fight Han Li over the spoils.

Zhong Weiniang unexpectedly appeared somewhat pleased after seeing her sweetheart avenged and repeatedly expressed her thanks to Han Li.

She also said that when the fallen hear of this in the underworld, they would certainly be grateful that Han Li had avenged them!

Those words caused Han Li, who had come here with another objective in mind, to feel a bit embarrassed.

He hastily changed the subject and suggested that the others hurriedly search other areas of the Imperial Palace for any Black School Fiend Disciples that remained hidden. He also said that he had to stay behind and attend to a few matters, such as withdrawing the great formation.

Hearing Han Li’s words, how could the Yellow Maple Valley cultivators not understand what he had meant? He was clearly giving them the opportunity to loot the remains of the Black Fiend School’s nest.

Song Meng beamed with happiness while the others found it somewhat embarrassing. Han Li then said, “Let’s rendezvous after I finish putting everything in order. As for the Black Fiend School Master, he should have enough high quality items on his body to satisfy me!”

The others felt this was reasonable and did not further refuse. After all, everyone had suffered quite a bit from today’s great battle.

Thus, after Han Li withdrew the great formation, the others flew away on their magic tools.

Only when the others could no longer be seen did Han Li feel reassured enough to wave his two puppet beasts over. They flew back toward Han Li with the results of their search.

Chapter 330: Fiend Core

When Han Li saw that the “Five Element Blood Cores” were among the Emperor’s items, he was jubilant.

He immediately took them from the puppet beast’s mouth and closely examined them.

From the great spiritual power contained in the cores, Han Li verified that their medicinal properties were genuine. Relieved, Han Li took out an exquisite jade box from his storage pouch and carefully placed the five Blood Cores inside.

Han Li didn’t know the specific effects of the “Five Elements Blood Cores” mentioned by the young prince Xin. But from how urgently the Emperor of Yue had collected these items, their usefulness toward Core Formation should most likely be true.

Han Li then shifted his attention to the other items: a pitch-black alms bowl, an awl with an inch-long, blood-red spike, and a jade slip emitting a light-grey Qi.

Upon seeing these items, Han Li felt somewhat fearful of them.

These kinds of magic tools were commonly used by devilish and evil cultivators. It was likely that such items would have restrictions or curses placed on them, so he wasn’t in any hurry to fiddle with them. Instead, he took in a deep breath and covered his hands in a layer of faint azure light.

With this protection, Han Li was able to pick up the jade slip with his heart at ease, and carefully examine it.

Apart from releasing a strange aura, the jade slip didn’t have any sort of obvious restrictions. Han Li let out a sigh of relief and slowly submerged his spiritual sense into the slip.

As his spiritual sense entered the jade slip, Han Li stood motionless. However, his expression underwent strange changes. First, he appeared pleasantly surprised, then dismayed and finally, extremely cautious with a slight trace of fear.

After the time it took to make a cup of tea, Han Li withdrew his spiritual sense and found himself in a daze.

The jade slip’s contents went far beyond Han Li’s expectations.

It contained information on all of the Black Fiend School’s cultivation arts such as the young prince’s “Black Fiend Asura Art”, the four Blood Servant’s “Fiend Demon Art”, the Emperor of Yue’s “Divine Blood Light” and so on.

Han Li was shocked to discover that all of these cultivation arts mentioned a book called the “Profound Yin Scriptures”; it seemed to be the origin of all these arts. This greatly piqued Han Li’s curiosity.

But as Han Li hurriedly scoured the jade slip, he was unable to find anything related to the whereabouts of the scripture.

With no other choice, Han Li could only bury his desire to find the scripture in his heart and focus his attention to some of the strange secret techniques.

A few of these greatly pleased Han Li. Not only did they resolve some of his long held doubts, but they also mentioned the true use of the “Five Elements Blood Cores”.

Han Li calmed himself and carefully examined the passage.

It turned out that the “Five Elements Blood Cores” were formed within the bodies of cultivators who practiced the “Fiend Demon Art”, much like how a demonic beast condense a core within their body. It was the most important aspect of the “Fiend Demon Art”.

The reason as to why they were able to turn into fiend demons and didn’t need to use Foundation Establishment Pills to enter Foundation Establishment was because of the formation of this core.

Although this “Fiend Demon Art” didn’t require the use of blood sacrifices, it still greatly increased the speed of cultivation. However, Foundation Establishment was the highest layer this cultivation art could achieve; there would be no hope of reaching Core Formation.

In fact, the rest of these cultivation techniques were more or less the same and held the fatal flaw of being incapable of reaching Core Formation.

Of course, their speed of cultivation left others astonished through the additional assistance of blood sacrifices.

It seems these “Five Elements Blood Cores” were supposed to be a solution to the defects of these kinds of cultivation arts.

The jade slip also mentioned a secret technique called the “Fiend Core Technique”.

According to what was stated by the secret technique, even if one were a late Foundation Establishment cultivator with poor aptitude, so long as they consumed the “Five Elements Blood Cores” in accordance with the technique, there was a one-third chance of forming a “Fiend Core” . This “False Gold Core” would be similar to a genuine Core Formation cultivator’s gold core.

With the successful formation of a Fiend Core, while one’s strength would be inferior to a genuine Core Formation cultivator, the difference wouldn’t be that great. In addition, it would have the wondrous effect of extending one’s lifespan similar to genuine Core Formation.

When Han Li read this, his heart nearly jumped out of his chest. A one-third chance of forming a core? The “Five Elements Blood Core” was truly heaven-defying!

He immediately felt an urge to set everything else aside and consume the Five Elements Blood Cores!

However, a flaw later mentioned in the description of the secret technique had left Han Li astonished.

Since the “Fiend Core” was an artificial Golden Core, there was no possibility of further improvement. This implied that for the rest of one’s lifetime, there would be no way to further one’s cultivation and progress past early Core Formation Stage.

If it were only this, Han Li still wouldn’t allow such an opportunity to pass him by.

This was because the method the “Three Essence Revolutions Technique” used to form a core was truly unpredictable and unreliable. Even if he were able to scatter his cultivation three times, Han Li wasn’t confident it would work.

After all, this cultivation method was something created from the mere conjectures of the founder of the “Azure Essence Sword Art”! No one had ever successfully cultivated it before.

On the other hand, from the tone of this text, the “Fiend Core Technique” was certain to have previously been used.

A one-third possibility of Core Formation was extremely enticing to Han Li!

As for the inability to reach Nascent Soul Stage after forming a Fiend core, this matter was too far removed from Han Li’s current situation for him to consider.

“Nascent Soul Stage” was still something Han Li could only dream about.

At the moment, being able to achieve Core Formation was his highest objective. As for whether or not he could extravagantly hope to condense a Nascent Soul, he would only think about it after he reached Core Formation.

But the following details of the “Fiend Core Technique” left Han Li dumbstruck.

It said that after the “Fiend Core” was formed in one’s body, Fiend Demon Qi would be continuously released for a long period, and it would be capable of gradually eroding a cultivator’s mind.

Although the erosion wouldn’t leave one completely without mind or memories, decreased mental acuity along with gradually reduced intellect were unavoidable.

This caused Han Li’s heart to tremble without end.

What Han Li was most confident of was his mind and quick-wittedness. These were the main reasons that he had been able to remain so free and unfettered in the cultivation world until now.

Thus, when he read that passage, Han Li had only a moment of internal struggle before completely severing any intentions of using the “Five Elements Blood Cores”.

After reading about the drawback, Han Li was extremely vexed. He had done so much to acquire the “Five Elements Blood Cores”, but it proved to be of absolutely no use to him.

After a moment of further consideration, Han Li felt that something was amiss.

If the drawback was so severe, then why would the Emperor of Yue specially cultivate these cores? That cunning old fox certainly wasn’t going to directly consume it.

With that thought, Han Li looked through the secret techniques once more and his attention was caught by a very interesting secret technique — “External Reincarnation”.

This was a renowned top grade secret technique of the Devilish Dao; Han Li had heard about it long ago.

Although there were many techniques called “Reincarnation” techniques, the specific cultivation method and effectiveness of these techniques were exceedingly strange and varied. Regardless of the “reincarnation” technique, to a Devil Dao cultivator, they were all as precious as their own lives. They were all fundamentally the greatest secrets of each sect.

The Seven Sects of Yue had previously attempted to collect all the cultivation arts related to reincarnation but ultimately ended up empty-handed!

Han Li quickly read through this technique several times and grew rapt with joy. He had found a use for these “Five Elements Blood Cores” after all.

If he had guessed correctly, the Emperor of Yue must have had the same plan in mind. Thus, he had painstakingly cultivated those blood servants in order to condense those “Five Elements Blood Cores”.

As for the blue-robed man, the self-proclaimed Black Fiend School Master who had died from the Heavenly Lightning Seed, that was an incarnation he had refined.

Only that would explain why the blue-robed man was completely willing to allow his cultivation to be absorbed without the slightest resistance.

The distracting thoughts that Han Li had pushed to the back of his mind resurfaced as he read through the secret technique.

As for secret techniques such as the “Cultivation Essence Pill” and methods of blood sacrifice, since Han Li didn’t cultivate Devilish Arts, he had little interest in them.

Only the condensation method of the “Blood Spirit Drill” caught Han Li’s eye as he read on. He read through it several times and memorized it.

After Han Li withdrew his consciousness from the jade slip, he properly digested the information before moving on to the next two items.

The blood-red awl was the solidified form of the Blood Spirit Drill after leaving the body. It should be quite a useful magic tool.

As for the pitch-black alms bowl, it must have been the rarely seen magic tool, the “Soul Congregation Bowl”. It was specialized in holding the souls of cultivators. Any soul that entered this magic tool would gradually lose its intelligence and become a feral, common soul suitable for refinement or control.

After only briefly examining this “Soul Congregation Bowl”, the dark, cold Qi that the bowl contained caused Han Li to shiver and he hastily deposited it into his storage pouch.The magic tool’s dark, cold Qi gave an impression that countless cultivators’ souls must have been ruined within. The more he made contact with this bowl, the more ill he felt! Han Li clearly understood that without cultivating these kinds of dark arts, he would have no use for this magic tool.

The more he made contact with this bowl, the more ill he felt!

Chapter 332: A Once Familiar Place

Immediately after Han Li agreed to accompany Chen Qianqiao, he felt slight regret.

He had previously came to a clear decision to no longer be tangled with this woman. But now, he had agreed to accompany her for some unknown reason. It seemed he wasn’t as determined as he had thought!

Han Li inwardly shook his head and replied, “Alright. Then how about Senior Martial Sister ride with me in my Divine Wind Boat. We’ll be able to arrive there much faster!”

With that said, Han Li took out his spotless white Divine Wind Boat and invited Chen Qianqiao to ride with him.

When Chen Qiaoqian saw this gesture, she smiled sweetly and entered the boat without any objections.

After a moment of flight, Han Li brought Chen Qiaoqian to the Yuejing’s famed White Chrysanthemum Mountain.

The mountain was covered with all sorts of chrysanthemums, a majority being white. The scene was truly mesmerizing.

Contrary to Han Li’s expectations, Chen Qiaoqian didn’t speak to him after arriving on the mountain. They merely walked along the small mountain path minding their own business. Only when they occasionally saw a particularly breathtaking scene would they stop for a moment.

Han Li did not speak as he followed behind her, dispassionately gazing at her charming body without the slightest shame.

After two hours, Chen Qiaoqian had climbed to the mountaintop and stood on a small pavilion with Han Li to the side.

At that moment, no one was on the mountaintop aside from the two; not even a single traveler. As the two were unwilling to speak, it was extremely quiet.

It was unknown how long this subtle mood continued before Chen Qiaoqian broke it with a few faint words.

“Junior Martial Brother Han, after the great battle is concluded, I fear that I am going to be married off!”

Upon hearing those words, Han Li couldn’t help but tilt his head and reveal an expression of astonishment.

“The groom is a direct lineage disciple of the great Qin cultivator clan, a disciple of Heavenly Imperial Fortress and a cultivator that has just reached Foundation Establishment! I’ve seen him several times and he seems decent. If nothing unexpected occurs, then he will marry into my Chen Clan and become my Dao Companion.” Chen Qiaoqian spoke calmly and turned a blind eye to Han Li’s appearance of amazement.

After a moment, Han Li’s astonishment gradually waned, and with some hesitation, he politely said, “Then I must congratulate Senior Martial Sister Chen on finding a suitable marriage partner! Junior Martial Brother will certainly prepare a gift for you later....!”

It became clear as Han Li started to speak, that Chen Qiaoqian had no intention of listening to his words; those were not the words she had wanted to hear. She trembled for a moment before releasing a disk shaped flying magic tool and flying off with a cold face.

After seeing Chen Qiaoqian disappear into the distance, Han Li motionlessly stood in place with a cold expression. After a long while, he let out a long breath and dispiritedly flew off.

Although Han Li had already made his decision about Chen Qiaoqian, he still felt at a loss when confronted with her interest to marry him.

This was perhaps a common flaw that all men possessed! Even if they were called cultivators, they had the same emotions as mortals.

Han Li mocked himself as he flew back to the Qin Residence.

After returning to the residence, Han Li learned from the others that Chen Qiaoqian had already departed, starting her journey early.

When Han Li heard this, he bitterly smiled in his heart. It seemed that he had greatly disappointed Chen Qiaoqian, and now, she was preparing her heart to marry someone else.

Although he was a tad depressed, Han Li wasn’t of the normal sort. With an ordinary expression, he nodded his head and joked around with the others for a while longer.

Like that, the morning of the second day had arrived and the others left the Qin Residence. Han Li was the last cultivator to remain.

Before setting off on his journey, he went to secretly pay a visit to Mo Fengwu. After all, they were acquaintances and he wanted to bid her farewell.

But when he arrived outside her home, Han Li spotted Mo Fengwu through a window, causing him to change his mind.

This was because Mo Fengwu was accompanying an old woman of about fifty years old that was reading scriptures out loud. She appeared completely at peace.

After Han Li silently looked on for a moment, he ultimately decided not to disturb her. He turned around and quietly left.

Toward this particular girl, it may be better if he didn’t meet her!

‘Perhaps living a peaceful life without being reminded of those painful memories is best for her!’ Han Li thought with melancholy.

Han Li then left Yuejing and first made a trip to Jia Yuan City. Since he had promised to avenge the Mo Estate, he figured that he may as well pay a visit and take a look.

Although the Devil Dao hadn’t come to stir trouble, he reckoned that Jia Yuan City didn’t currently contain any high level cultivators due to the upcoming great battle. He only had to secretly get rid of the Rainbow Sect’s Sect Master. Even if he angered a few Spirit Beast Mountain disciples, they wouldn’t be able to find out it was him.

In addition to causing trouble for the Rainbow Sect, he thought he’d take a look to see how Sun Ergou was managing the Fourth Level Gang.

He had left behind this back up plan several years ago, and now, he wanted to see if it still held any use.

With that in mind, Han Li rushed toward Jia Yuan City on his Divine Wind Boat.

The last time he was in Jia Yuan City was over ten years ago. However, many of the memories remained vivid in his mind and left a deep impression on him.

……

Five days later, a youth appeared in front of a long established restaurant in Jia Yuan City. This person stood on the side of the street and looked at the restaurant's sign with squinted eyes.

The person with the strange expression was Han Li, who had just entered the city. After standing there for a moment, he sighed and calmly walked in.

He went to the second floor and saw that the table by the window where he had sat at all those years ago happened to be empty.

Han Li happily walked over to it without the slightest hesitation.

Just as he sat down, a waiter politely wiped down his table and asked Han Li what he would like to order.

Han Li faintly smiled and ordered a few delicious appetizers, sending the waiter off to deliver his order. However, he did not come here just to satisfy his desire for delicious food.

With that in mind, Han Li turned his gaze outside the window.

The Mo Estate’s huge residence still remained and it still had a burly man standing outside its gates. However, the huge sign on the gate no longer read “Mo Residence” but instead read “Li Residence” in large, golden words.

Looking at the “Li Residence” sign shining under the sunlight, Han Li unconsciously wrinkled his brow.

From what he had heard, the Rainbow Sect Master seemed to be surnamed “Li”. It seems they now occupied their defeated enemy’s nest.

Not knowing why, Han Li felt particularly bothered when he saw the sign saying “Li Residence”. He found the previous “Mo Residence” sign somewhat more pleasing to the eye.

As Han Li was lost in thought, his dishes were brought by the waiter and simultaneously the sounds of banter were heard on the floor below. Several youths wearing embroidered silk clothes walked up the stairs followed by their burly guards; they appeared to be the young masters of a noble family.

Among these young masters was a man so thin he might blow away in the wind. He casually swept his gaze over the floor and impolitely beckoned to the waiter.

The waiter complacently ran over and hastily said with an enchanting smile, “Young Master Xia, do you have any instructions?”

“Call for the shopkeeper. Today, we’re inviting an esteemed guest to dine with us. Have everyone on the third floor leave. We will pay for the damages.” This skinny man spoke quite arrogantly.

The waiter didn’t reveal the slightest bit of dissatisfaction, repeatedly nodding his head, before hurrying off to inform the shopkeeper.

After a short moment, a forty year old man arrived. Once he saw the thin man, he immediately agreed to his request with a smile. He then brought the waiter to the third floor to apologize to the customers who were already there.

It was unknown whether this shopkeeper was naturally so quick and efficient or whether this young master had a truly great background.

Not long after, all of the customers on the third floor had paid their bills and left. Not a single one of them had dared to complain.

Han Li lazily looked over before he returned his gaze to the bustling streets outside the window.

The newcomer was only a young master among mortals, an arrogant person only relying on the might of his clan, commonly found at all places. Han Li had absolutely no interest in him.

At that moment, the youth in charge, Young Master Xia, then nodded with satisfaction and descended to the ground floor.

Later, the sound of footsteps came up from below. This time, Han Li was startled and couldn’t help but turn his head around and stare.

This was because among those heavy footsteps, feather-light footsteps could be faintly discerned. Only a Jianghu martial artist who practiced qinggong to a certain stage would be able to display such control.

This greatly piqued Han Li’s curiosity.

Chapter 334: A Strange Change

“Poisoned? That’s impossible. I am quite careful and have a specialist responsible for testing my food and drink!” After a moment of terror, Sun Ergou revealed an appearance of unease.

Hearing this, Han Li was too lazy to explain any further. With a wave of his hand, a streak of azure light flashed and flew into Sun Ergou’s body.

“Young Master! This is... wh-... what’d you...” Sun Ergou hadn’t dared to dodge, but was still alarmed.

“This is True Spirit Technique, it’s capable of visualizing the poison within your body. Go ahead and take a look in a mirror!” Han Li sat on a chair and played it down.

When Sun Ergou heard this, his heart dropped. Then he hastily ran to the corner of the room with a dressing table.

He hastily scoured the dressing table for a small mirror and then looked into the mirror with great caution. What he saw left him dumbfounded. He saw that his entire face was covered in blackish-purple Qi. From a single glance, he could tell he was severely poisoned.

“Young Master, please save my life! This one has remained faithful to Young Master this entire time and possesses no trace of disloyalty.” Sun Ergou rushed over to Han Li with an expression of fear and knelt while imploring Han Li to save him.

At this moment, he was almost entirely convinced!

As Han Li was a cultivator, it was impossible he would waste so much effort to deceive someone like Sun Ergou. If Han Li had truly meant him harm, he could’ve killed him with a flick of a finger.

After having seen this display of loyalty, Han Li faintly smiled and calmly said, “Be at ease. Although the poison is quite hidden, it’s toxicity is weak. It won’t be able to kill you in a few days. There is no need to be so fussed over nothing!”

Although Sun Ergou had calmed down a bit, he continued his pitiful pleas, “Young Master possesses great power. Please give this one a method to dissolve the poison so that I, Sun Ergou, may continue to serve you faithfully! If Young Master does not trust me then I can swear an oath under poison. This one...” Although Sun Ergou was now a gang leader, we was still very much afraid of death. Without even waiting for Han Li to speak, he took the initiative to swear his own oaths — much to Han Li’s amusement.

‘Serve me faithfully? It seems more like he has been receiving benefits without giving anything in return!’ Han Li thought, not knowing whether to laugh or cry.

“This is a detoxification pill. After you take this, you’ll be fine but just make sure that your poisoning does not continue.” Han Li shook his head before tossing a blue medicine pill to Sun Ergou.

“Many thanks! Many thanks, Young Master!” Sun Ergou received the pill with great joy and repeatedly expressed his thanks. He then quickly climbed up from the floor and properly put away the pill.

“This poison doesn’t affect one so deeply after only one or two exposures. It should have taken at least several months for it to get to this point! I believe that you should be able to find the poisoner. Surely you can do that at least; isn’t that right, my dear Gang Leader Sun?” Han Li lightly chuckled and said half-jokingly.

“Young Master teases! However, as for who poisoned me, I do have a few suspects in mind.” Sun Ergou rubbed the back of his head with a smile.

As his life had been just saved by Han Li, he was naturally now even more respectful towards him.

“En! As a cultivator, I can’t be too involved in the affairs of you mortals. I’ll leave it to you! The reason why I came here was because I wanted to see Crooked Soul and take him away. Now that I have quite a bit of cultivation, I shouldn’t have any problem bringing him along. Do you have any complaints about this?” Han Li’s smiled disappeared as he said this with a deep voice.[1]

“Young Master wishes to take Sir Crooked Soul away? But Young Master, Sir Crooked Soul is no longer in the Fourth Level Gang.” When Sun Ergou heard Han Li’s tone, he incessantly complained in his heart, but he still had to summon the courage to reply.

“What do you mean? You lost him?” Han Li’s face darkened and the temperature in the room dropped several degrees, causing Sun Ergou tremble in fright.

“Young Master, please calm down! It wasn’t that I had lost him, but that Sir Crooked Soul had run off on his own. Although he is not in the city, he is not too far away, at a nearby mountain forest. I had sent a few people to follow after Sir Crooked Soul!” Sun Ergou explained at great speed, fearing that Han Li would act on his anger.

“He ran off on his own? What going on? Explain it clearly. If it isn’t as you say, then don’t blame me for coming back to punish you!” Although slight astonishment had flashed across Han Li’s face, he still managed to respond with a relaxed expression.

It was good enough that Sun Ergou knew about Crooked Soul’s whereabouts. But since Crooked Soul was only a walking corpse, Han Li found it hard to believe that he could have run away on his own.

Seeing that Han Li wasn’t angry, Sun Ergou felt relieved. Not daring to neglect him, he hastily explained, “Ever since Young Master had handed over Sir Crooked Soul to me, I have followed Young Master’s instructions to only use him as a last resort and to not allow others to see him.

“But an anomaly occurred six years ago with Sir Crooked Soul. That period of time was a crucial moment of expansion for my gang and we were against a mid level gang with a great amount of experts. I had Sir Crooked Soul help me deal with them. During that battle, Crooked Soul had displayed great might and won our gang a decisive victory. But a few days after the battle had concluded, a subordinate I tasked with watching Crooked Soul suddenly came and reported that he had actually started talking. I was extremely astonished and rushed over with the ‘Soul Guiding Bell’. Then...”

Sun Ergou stopped there and bitterly smiled.

“What happened? Don’t tell me that Crooked Soul attacked you while still in possession of the Soul Guiding Bell?”

Having heard that Crooked Soul could speak, he was greatly astonished. But having seen that Sun Ergou had deliberately kept him in suspense, Han Li unhappily rebuked him.

Frightened, Sun Ergou continued, “He didn’t attack me. But before I entered his room, Sir Crooked Soul seemed to know that I had arrived; he suddenly broke the wall and ran away as if he was flying. I was completely unable to chase after him!” As Sun Ergou said this, he revealed an expression of helplessness.

“He ran away?!” With raised eyebrows, Han Li’s mind seemed to have wandered off into thought.

“That’s right, Young Master! Although Sir Crooked Soul has done this for several years, for some reason, he is still lingering at the boundary of the forest. Although I’ve tried several times to find Crooked Soul and bring him back with the aid of my gang’s experts, he was always unwilling to see me. Whenever I approached him, he would immediately flee. I had a few experts block his path, but nobody proved to be Sir Crooked Soul’s opponent. Two of my gang’s experts have even died.” Sun Ergou said, perplexed.

“It isn’t a great mystery! It’s likely because of the Soul Guiding Compass that you carry! Although I don’t know why control over Crooked Soul was lost, it seems the restrictions I originally put on him were still effective.” Han Li coldly laughed before saying this with an indifferent expression.

“So it was like that!” Sun Ergou had appeared to be convinced.

It seemed that he had previously come to that conclusion as well.

“Tell me about Crooked Soul’s whereabouts. I will deal with him later. As it seems that this matter isn’t your doing, I’ll have to personally go to see what had happened. Since you no longer have a use for the Soul Guiding Bell, give it to me.” After a moment of thought, Han Li said this calmly.

“Yes, Young Master. My subordinates reported of Sir Crooked Soul’s whereabouts two days ago. He is currently in the west side of...” Sun Ergou respectfully gave directions to a place about a hundred kilometers outside of Jiayuan City. He then carefully took out the “Soul Guiding Bell” magic tool and offered it to Han Li with both hands.

Han Li nodded his head and examined the magic tool for a moment. He then placed it in his storage pouch, having found that it was in good condition.

“In addition to Crooked Soul, I came here because I also had a few questions to ask you about the Rainbow Sect. You must answer me honestly!” Han Li’s face suddenly grew stiff; his voice once more becoming cold.

Han Li’s change in tone had clearly stunned Gang Leader Sun. After a short pause, he repeatedly nodded his head like a baby chick pecking grain.

“What kind of person is the current Rainbow Sect Master? What family does he have? Have any outsiders recently appeared in the Li Estate and have any of them remained?” Han Li fired these questions off with a stiff expression.

Sun Ergou felt his heart tremble, but he answered without the slightest hesitation, “As for the Rainbow Sect Master, this one truly doesn’t understand what sort of person he is. This one had only previously seen him at a distance and I only understand that his martial arts are unfathomable. With regards to family, he has two sons and a daughter; all of whom are married. I’ve heard that his eldest son is presiding over at the Rainbow Sect’s previous headquarters. His second son has followed the Rainbow Sect Master to the Li Estate and is presiding over that. I’ve also heard...”

Sun Ergou gave a very comprehensive explanation. It was clear that he regularly put forth great effort into gathering intelligence on the Rainbow Sect.

As Han Li calmly listened, he unconsciously placed his hand on the table and started to tap; it appeared he was digesting the information.

When Sun Ergou saw Han Li stay silent for a moment, his heart stirred and he carefully asked, “Could it be because of that matter with the Mo Estate several years ago that you wish to act against the Rainbow Sect?”

Once Han Li heard this, his brow wrinkled as his face became gloomy.

“You speak too much! Don’t randomly ask about matters you have no right to know! Even more so, do not guess. You wouldn’t want to tragically become one of those poor souls who have lost their memories, right?”

Han Li’s ice-cold voice caused Sun Ergou’s expression to drop and he immediately begged for forgiveness.

Han Li snorted, letting the matter drop. One couldn’t afford to be polite when establishing authority.

[1]. In Chapter 63: True Appearance, it is revealed that Crooked Soul is the refined corpse of his deceased best friend. Finding this puppet too heavy to carry, he leaves it behind to Sun Ergou in Chapter 125: Plans.

[Back]

Chapter 337: A Concealed Expert, Crooked Soul

“As for tonight’s matters, I do not wish for Spirit Beast Mountain to know of them. You two should keep this to yourselves!” Han Li suddenly raised his head and coldly glanced at the Rainbow Sect Master and his son.

The old man’s heart trembled in fear and he remained silent with a humble appearance.

Han Li wordlessly stared at the Rainbow Sect Master for a moment. When he saw that the old man had broken out in a cold sweat, he revealed a smile and then his body blurred, disappearing without a trace.

While the old man was stunned, he felt a hand lightly pat his shoulder. His body immediately stiffened as he slowly turned his head.

Han Li was indifferently standing behind him.

“Does Sir Immortal have any commands? This old man will certainly follow them.” The Rainbow Sect Master said with an apprehensive smile.

“It’s nothing. I just wanted to give you a greeting.” Han Li replied with a calm expression.

“A greeting?”

The old man was startled, not fully understanding Han Li’s intentions. But something soon came to mind and he hastily inspected his body with worry. Fortunately, he didn’t find anything unusual and calmed down.

Han Li then released his Divine Wind Boat and appeared inside with a flash.

After giving a deep glance at the youth and the old man, Han Li coldly chuckled and flew off in a streak of white light.

The old man and his son were left completely baffled along with Mo Yuzhu.

……

As Han Li flew on his Divine Wind Boat, he unconsciously sneered.

Although the old man had said that he didn’t dare to tell Spirit Beast Mountain about him, Han Li saw something amiss from his expression.

Having seen this, Han Li naturally wouldn’t ignore a deep schemer who held hatred toward him, even if he was a mortal.

Therefore, when he had appeared behind him, he secretly took action and had a “Burrowing Worm” enter his body with a pat.

This insect was very strange. It was the size of a fine hair and was nearly invisible to the naked eye, only completely detectable through spiritual sense. So long as it entered the body, it would slowly crawl through one’s blood vessels and eventually reach the heart.

After one or two years, the infected party would start to experience heart pain and an inability to sleep soundly. The symptoms would grow increasingly severe over a span of several months until the heart pain surges, leading to death. It would appear no different than if he had died an ordinary death from heart problems. Even expert cultivators wouldn’t find anything wrong in the least unless they knew what to look for beforehand.

Since it would occur such a long time after Han Li had patted his shoulder, no association would be made to Han Li.

This unscrupulous and strange insect was something Han Li had acquired from the spoils of a Devil Dao cultivator. He initially had no idea what it was until he had someone else appraise it. Now knowing its purpose and usage, he had used it on the Rainbow Sect Master.

With this, he was able to fulfill his promise to Mo Fengwu without appearing evil in front of Mo Yuzhu. Han Li felt quite pleased with himself.

Han Li currently no longer cared if they informed Spirit Beast Mountain that Han Li had been there.

After all, he hadn’t harmed the father or the son in the slightest. Presumably, Spirit Beast Mountain wouldn’t pursue him over such a minor affair. As for the Rainbow Sect Master’s son, he seemed decent. Han Li hoped that Mo Yuzhu would have a happy life with him.

With that thought, he flew his Divine Wind Boat to the west of Jia Yuan City.

He wanted to hurry and resolve this matter of Crooked Soul’s peculiarity. Although he didn’t know what Crooked Soul was up to, he definitely couldn’t just leave him alone.

West of Jia Yuan City was a tall mountain range filled with dense forest. It was said that poisonous snakes and fierce beasts roamed in these parts. As such, people would rarely tread in that region. This was most likely the main reason why Crooked Soul ran there after the peculiarity had arisen.

Han Li silently observed the densely covered mountain range from the sky.

After a long while, he took out the “Soul Guiding Bell” from his storage pouch.

He gradually poured Spiritual Power into the bell as he grasped it in his palm. A short while later, the Soul Guiding Bell glowed with faint white light and floated in the air.

“Go.”

After he threw the small bell, he formed an incantation gesture with his other hand and softly spat out his command.

The Soul Guiding Bell trembled for a moment before releasing a clear ring. It then flew off at great speed.

Han Li faintly smiled and chased after it with his Divine Wind Boat.

By using Crooked Soul’s blood essence that the bell contained, he was able to easily use the bell to track down where Crooked Soul was located. Naturally, he couldn’t do this if the bell was too far away from Crooked Soul. If Crooked Soul was over five hundred kilometers away, Han Li would be powerless to act. But now that the bell had responded, Han Li grew happy, knowing that Crooked Soul was concealed nearby.

The small bell flew straight for about fifteen kilometers before suddenly descending. When Han Li saw this, he knew he had found his objective and immediately grabbed the small bell in midair. Then, he completely covered the small, glowing bell in a layer of azure light.

From Sun Ergou’s words, Han Li knew that Crooked Soul could now sense the Soul Guiding Bell. By concealing the bell’s aura, he could avoid having Crooked Soul flee.

He quietly descended on a small mountain’s peak and started to sweep his gaze in every direction.

Although it was already dark, Han Li was still able to vaguely see as he was a Foundation Establishment cultivator. As a result, he headed straight towards the direction in which the small bell had originally descended, into a large pile of stones on the mountaintop.

Han Li walked without the slightest sound as if he was a ghost. From Han Li’s measures, he had ultimately caught Crooked Soul completely unaware. Crooked Soul was sitting cross-legged on a huge rock in meditation as if he were refining Qi.

Hidden behind a rock, Han Li secretly watched Crooked Soul with complete amazement.

Han Li was able to feel Spiritual Qi within Crooked Soul’s body. His Spiritual Qi fluctuations indicated that he was at the fifth or sixth layer of Qi Refinement, leaving Han Li stunned.

Han Li had clearly remembered that Zhang Tie [1] was originally unable to cultivate the “Eternal Spring Arts” because he didn’t have spiritual roots.

‘Wait! Although Zhang Tie was unable to cultivate the Eternal Spring Arts, that didn’t mean that he didn’t possess any spiritual roots. It only meant that he didn’t have wood attribute spiritual roots. Could it be that Zhang Tie possessed spiritual roots of another attribute?’ Han Li thought, suddenly coming to a realization.

‘What were the odds! Doctor Mo was actually able to accept two disciples with spiritual roots when a person with spiritual roots couldn’t normally be found among ten thousand mortals.’

With incredulity, Han Li continued his thoughts, ‘It is truly unfortunate. Because he didn’t have similar attributed spiritual roots, we ended up with completely different fates. If I happened to not have wood attributed spiritual roots, then would I have ended up...” Han Li felt a trace of lingering fear in his heart.

“However, how did Crooked Soul acquire a foundation cultivation technique he could use? Could it be...?”

Han Li seemed to have thought of something and wrinkled his brow. His eyes flashed with malicious intent, but he continued to silently watch Crooked Soul cultivate.

After the time it took to eat a meal, Crooked Soul opened his eyes. He stood up and stretched his limbs.

His eyes displayed intelligence as if he truly possessed consciousness.

But when Han Li saw this, his face only appeared gloomier and his expression held a faint trace of maliciousness.

“Today’s progress wasn’t bad! It seems that in four months, I won’t have to be afraid of the magic tool that controls this body.”

As Crooked Soul revealed happiness, he heard an ice-cold voice from his side.

“It seems that your esteemed self is quite satisfied with that body!”

“Who is it?”

Crooked Soul’s expression turned cautious as he hastily looked in the direction of the voice.

At this moment, Han Li walked out from concealment with an icy expression.

“Who are you?”

“Yi! You’re a Foundation Establishment Cultivator!”

When Crooked Soul discovered that he was unable to see through the depth of Han Li’s cultivation, he couldn’t help but reveal fear.

“That’s what I wanted to know. Why did you occupy and steal that body? That is the body of my close friend, and I personally handed it over to my subordinate for safekeeping. You’ve occupied that body for so many years, so how about you give me an explanation?” Han Li calmly said.

“This body is yours?” Crooked Soul revealed doubt as his eyes continuously shifted about. It was clear that he had some sly plan in mind.

When Han Li saw this, he coldly sneered. He suddenly flipped his hand, revealing the Soul Guiding Bell.

“What are you doing?” When Crooked Soul saw Han Li move, he immediately jumped ten meters back like a frightened hare; he then stared at Han Li with a face of vigilance.

Although he had previously felt the existence of the Soul Guiding Bell, he did not know its specific form. He also didn’t know that the small bell was a magic tool that specialized in controlling his body. He had only believed that Han Li had taken out a magic tool to casually act against him.

[1]. Han Li’s friend and fellow disciple of Doctor Mo who was later refined into Crooked Soul.

[Back]

Chapter 339: Astonishment

“I am...”

“Your esteemed self had better avoid calling yourself a rogue cultivator. Otherwise, I’d feel inclined to distrust you!” Han Li expressionlessly interrupted him.

Crooked Soul bitterly smiled. It appeared that as he was still unresigned, he had thought to say as such.

As a result, after some slight hesitation, he dispiritedly said, “It is as Fellow Daoist suspects. This one has an unusual identity; he is not from the State of Yue...”

“You aren’t someone from our State of Yue?” Upon hearing this, Han Li’s face revealed a fraction of the shock he felt in his heart.

“I was actually a Controlling Spirit Sect cultivator from the State of Tiandou.” Crooked Soul slowly said.

“The Devil Dao Controlling Spirit Sect!”

Han Li couldn’t help but narrow his eyes and stare at him with a gaze as sharp as a sword.

“That is correct. I arrived at this place several years ago but I hadn’t expected that one of your country’s cultivators would ruin my mystic body and reduce me to this state.” As Crooked Soul spoke about the destruction of his body, he wore a helpless expression.

After a moment of thought, Han Li asked with raised eyebrows, “Your body was damaged six years ago?”

As Han Li’s voice was calm, Crooked Soul was unable to make out Han Li’s interest. He honestly replied, “That’s right!”

“After you took possession of this body, you hadn’t thought of returning?” Han Li calmly asked.

“This one had naturally wanted to do so. But it seems your esteemed self doesn’t understand much about our Devil Dao.” Crooked Soul’s face continued to appear helpless.

“What was the matter? Although I know a few things about the Devil Dao, they are only bits and pieces from rumors.” Han Li openly admitted.

“Our Devil Dao is particular about how strength is truth and how the weak are just prey for the strong. Only with strength would one be able to enjoy authority. Originally, my position at the Controlling Spirit Sect wasn’t low. I had a dainty, pretty Dao Companion and a few obedient disciples. But now that my cultivation has greatly diminished, those things would no longer be mine if I returned. My position would most likely be coveted by my fellow disciples and fall to a hidden scheme.” Crooked Soul explained with a cold smile.

After hearing this, Han Li wrinkled his brow and remained silent.

Crooked Soul continued, “This one’s cultivation was lowered to this stage because he took possession of this body. Thus, this one is confident that he will be able to restore his cultivation within forty years and will be able to openly return. What, did Daoist Friend believe that I wished to remain in this backwater place where even birds don’t go to shit?”

“From what you’ve said, you haven’t encountered any other cultivators while you hid nearby Jia Yuan city?

“None. Daoist Friend is the first cultivator from the State of Yue I’ve seen after taking possession of this body.” He said with a uneasy appearance.

“Then why is it that you tried to impersonate a Spirit Beast Mountain cultivator at the start?” Han Li closely continued with his interrogation.

“I believed that your esteemed self was a Seven Sects cultivator and didn’t want to put myself at a disadvantage.” Crooked Soul brightly assured.

Having heard that, Han Li suddenly smiled.

“Is that the truth?” Han Li amiably asked. However, his kind appearance caused Crooked Soul to feel a chill down his back.

“That’s right! Could it be that Fellow Daoist is unsatisfied with something?” He cautiously asked with an uneasy expression.

“I’ve previously heard people say that it is easiest to deceive others with words holding seven parts truth and three parts lies. I wonder, how much of what your esteemed self told me just now is true?” Han Li slowly said this as he stared at him.

“Hehe! Daoist Friend’s suspicions are far too strong. I am telling the truth.” Crooked Soul was clearly uneasy. But once he thought of the consequences of telling the truth, he could only boldly continue to hold his ground.

“How about I mention a few things first? Your Devil Dao has already invaded our State of Yue. As such, we are now enemies. Thus, I now feel disinclined from torturing you for any secrets. I’ll just rip out your soul and save myself some time.” Han Li sinisterly said with a calm expression.

Having recently suffered, Crooked Soul’s complexion turned pale.

“Invade your State of Yue? How is this possible? The timing is clearly off.” In an instant, his pale face revealed an expression of remorse.

Han Li felt shocked.

“You knew of this matter? It seems I’ve truly underestimated you. Regardless, even if your status in the Controlling Spirit Sect was great, you are currently only a Qi Refinement cultivator! Don’t blame me for being ruthless.” Han Li gradually narrowed his gaze and said with a menacing expression.

Han Li turned his hand, causing the “Soul Congregation Bowl” to appear once more. Its dense, cold Qi immediately filled the air.

But what happened next left Han Li stunned. “Crooked Soul” didn’t reveal any fear and stared at the alms bowl with a strange expression, causing Han Li to feel ill at ease.

Han Li couldn’t use the “Soul Refinement Technique”; he was only using it as a threat. If Crooked Soul truly intended to die, then Han Li could only watch on as he perished, taking his body with him. He did have a few soul extraction spells among the secret blood sacrificial techniques, but unfortunately, he hadn’t practiced them in the least.

Just as Han Li thought this, Crooked Soul let out a long sigh before saying, “I have a few secrets on me. Furthermore, it has much to do with the life and death of your Seven Sects. However, what will guarantee that you will spare me after I reveal them? You might just kill me and refine my soul afterwards!” When he said the words “Soul Refinement”, he couldn’t help but twitch.

Having heard Crooked Soul speak so solemnly, Han Li stroked his nose and put away the alms bowl once more.

“What guarantee do you want? So long as it is reasonable, I will consider it!” Han Li responded indifferently as if he didn’t consider the secrets to be of importance.

“Humph! I cannot trust a common oath. But to the best of my knowledge, those that cultivate the “Soul Refinement Technique” are able to swear forbidden oaths with their soul tools. If they were to break them, then their Soul Refinement technique will backlash and kill them.

“Alright, I agree!” Han Li agreed with the slightest hesitation, coldly laughing in his heart.

After that, Han Li took out the Soul Congregation Bowl and made a death-pledge in accordance to Crooked Soul’s words.

Seeing Han Li so easily and cleanly swear the oath, Crooked Soul grew suspicious and faintly felt that something was amiss.

“I swore your death-pledge. Don’t tell me that you have other conditions?” Han Li stonily interrupted Crooked Soul’s doubts, deliberately revealing discontent.

“Of course not. This one knows what happens to those who are greedy. However, before I divulge these secrets, Daoist Friend must first tell me about the current circumstances of our Devil Dao and your Seven Sects as I am unsure whether this information is outdated.” Crooked Soul was distracted for a moment before explaining with a big smile.

Han Li revealed a slight trace of hesitation before slowly describing the current circumstances of the Seven Sects and Devil Dao.

Crooked Soul attentively listened but once he heard of the great battle that was to take place in a month, his face revealed a slight sneer. Han Li, who had been paying close attention to his face, clearly saw this.

Once Han Li finished, Crooked Soul muttered to himself for a moment before starting.

What he said first left Han Li at a loss for words.

“Daoist Friend, if you are willing to hear me out, you have no need to hurry over to the Seven Sects’ border camp. It is very likely the Seven Sects and the cultivators of their allied countries will have already been defeated. If you go, then you will only be throwing your life away.” Crooked Soul said with a strange expression.

With an indifferent face, Han Li coldly stared at him, waiting for an explanation.

The Controlling Spirit Sect cultivator couldn’t help but be impressed with Han Li’s collected demeanor. Although he felt increasing trepidation toward Han Li, he still continued, “You probably don’t know it, but Spirit Beast Mountain was actually one of our own sects. They had never actually broken their secret relations with our Controlling Spirit Sect, and their recent rebellion was just a cover. If I’m not mistaken, this cover was prepared by the six sects in order to wait for the cultivators of the two allied countries, dealing with the three countries’ cultivators in a single move. Presumably, after the battle is over, our Devil Dao will reign over several countries.” These slowly narrated words secretly left Han Li in shock.

“Cover? Isn’t this too much? Spirit Beast Mountain took the initiative to reveal their relationship with your Controlling Spirit Sect. It would’ve been better if they had kept it hidden.” Han Li asked with an unsightly expression after recovering from his shock.

“Did Fellow Daoist truly believe that the other six sects didn’t know of Spirit Beast Mountain’s origins? Apart from Spirit Beast Mountain, there is another sect among your Seven Sects that was once a branch of the Devil Dao, the most powerful among the State of Yue, the Masked Moon Sect. The Masked Moon Sect once originated from the Harmonious Bond Sect. However, the Masked Moon Sect ambitiously planned to become independant and have truly broken their ties with the Harmonious Bond Sect several hundred years ago.” The words of the Controlling Spirit Sect cultivator continued to leave Han Li in shock.

Chapter 340: Trap

“Even so, many cultivators were killed in that attack, including two Core Formation cultivators. To take such losses just to conceal Spirit Beast Mountain is inconceivable!” Han Li wrinkled his brow, unwilling to be easily convinced.

“If no Core Formation cultivators died, then how would the other six sects have been convinced? Furthermore, are you really sure that those two Core Formation cultivators were genuine?” Crooked Soul sneered.

“You mean...” Han Li stared at Crooked Soul with surprise.

“To the best of my knowledge, our Devil Dao sects possesses two or three forbidden techniques that forcefully raises the cultivation of a Foundation Establishment cultivator to nearly the point of Core Formation. Naturally, there are great defects to these techniques, and they can basically only be used once on a cultivator; once used, death by ruptured meridians was inevitable and the duration of their flared cultivation was pitifully short. However, this would have been enough to trick the Seven Sects for one battle.”

Han Li grew silent and was mostly convinced.

With that in consideration, Spirit Beast Mountain could strike at an opportune moment during the confrontation between the Six Devilish Dao Sects and the Seven Sects along with their allies, and easily collapse the Seven Sects’ arranged formations. With broken formations, the Seven Sects and their allies would be defenseless, falling prey to the Devil Dao.

“Even if what you said was true, the time for the decisive battle has not yet arrived. If I were to make a report, wouldn’t I be able to turn the tide of the battle? Why would I want to run away?” After muttering to himself for a moment, Han Li asked with doubt.

“Do you really believe our Devil Dao will strike in accordance to the time that was agreed? According to our original plans, this announcement was to confuse our opponents and leave them vulnerable as they prepared. Although I don’t know the specifics, I reckon that within a few days, our Devil Dao would launch a surprise attack on the main camp. That should be the moment when the Seven Sects will be most relaxed and reinforcements still distant. Does Fellow Daoist truly believe that your information would arrive in time and that the upper echelons would even believe you?” Crooked Soul smirked, clearly relishing the disaster that was about to befall the Seven Sects.

Han Li’s calm expression finally broke, feeling worried in his heart.

If the Seven Sects were truly defeated, his coming days would not be easy. He would have to roam across foreign countries to avoid pursuit from the Devil Dao. His only other choice would be to repair the ancient transportation formation and start a new life of cultivation in a foreign land.

“Your esteemed self appears to fully understand the Devil Dao’s plans. It seems your status was truly high. There is no need to worry. I’m not interested in finding out your true identity. However, I must ask if you have any evidence for this. You can’t possibly expect me to be completely convinced with just words, yes?” Han Li solemnly asked after a moment of thought.

Han Li’s question stunned the Controlling Spirit cultivator for a moment.

“In a moment of desperation, I had already lost my body. Does Fellow Daoist truly believe there is any evidence that was left behind? If Fellow Daoist has some patience, he will only have to wait a few days to hear the results of the battle.” Crooked Soul bitterly smiled before answering as if it had nothing to do with him.

Han Li coldly smiled in response.

“Without a body, your soul somehow managed to escape. However, you’re still alive and were even able to recover your magic tools and other valuables; I’m sure you were able to recover such evidence as well.” Han Li coollyy said, striking at the heart of the matter and causing Crooked Soul’s bitter smile to freeze.

“Hehe! It seems I truly cannot conceal this from Fellow Daoist. Yes, I do possess a few secret letters between Spirit Beast Mountain and my own sect. In fact, I was in charge of relaying information in the State of Yue several years ago. But I wouldn’t have thought...” When Han Li exposed him, Crooked Soul revealed slight embarrassment.

Han Li inwardly sighed in response to his admission. This person was surprisingly crafty. It seems he’d have to be a bit more careful; he didn’t even know his age.

“Where did you put it?”

As Han Li bluntly asked this question, he started to sweep his gaze across Crooked Soul’s body.

“The jade slip letters are in my storage pouch. I placed it at a nearby cave. How about I bring Fellow Daoist there?” Crooked Soul appeared to be rather cooperative.

“You don’t have it on hand?” Han Li’s gaze flashed with doubt.

“As you know, this body is a reanimated corpse. Although it far exceeds ordinary men, it had lost a majority of its senses. Therefore, I fear that during an unknown moment of carelessness, I would lose my storage pouch. For that reason, I left it behind at my dwelling.” Crooked Soul explained this with difficulty, causing Han Li to feel something was amiss.

Han Li didn’t say anything and carefully searched his body, ending up empty handed. He then asked with an icy tone, “Where is the cave? I will go and find it!”

Seeing that Han Li was so very cautious, Crooked Soul could only gloomily tell Han Li its location.

Han Li nodded and turned to depart. But something suddenly came to mind, and he turned around to ask, “How did you enter that corpse? Although the body would be easier to possess as it doesn’t contain a soul, it still isn’t a cultivator’s body!”

Han Li was genuinely curious.

“I don’t know!”

His answer caused Han Li’s face to darken. But without waiting for Han Li to speak, Crooked Soul hastily explained, “I truly don’t know why. During that time, I dragged my heavily injured body to Jia Yuan City and was on the verge of death. I could only desperately eject my soul and search in every direction for a cultivator to possess. However, I was unable to find a cultivator anywhere nearby. Just when I was about to give up hope, I found this soulless corpse. In a moment of desperation, I attempted to enter its body. Against all my expectations, I was truly amazed that I had succeeded.”

The Controlling Spirit Sect cultivator appeared to be incredulous from this as well.

Han Li remained silent and stared at him for a moment. He suddenly walked toward Crooked Soul and slapped two additional Soul Lock talismans on his body before vanishing into the darkness.

Crooked Soul was left behind with a bitter expression. But a short while later, Han Li returned with a strange glare in his eyes.

…

Han Li was able to easily find the cave using the directions given. It didn’t appear to be very large.

With a wave of his hand, a moonlight stone flew out of his storage pouch. Hovering above his head, the moonlight stone illuminated his surroundings.

Then, he looked into the dark cave and pondered for a moment before taking out his white scale shield and tortoise shell. With the two magic tools protecting his front, he carefully walked inside.

Like Han Li expected, the cave was not large. After walking for about twenty-five meters, he saw a cave wall blocking his path, the presumable end of the cave.

Han Li turned his sharp gaze and found nothing strange. He then lowered his head and looked at the ground.

According to what Crooked Soul said, the storage pouch should be buried underneath a bluestone and should be easy to find.

As expected, about six meters away, he found a meter tall pitch-black chunk of what appeared to be stone.

Without thinking much further, he took several steps forward and closely examined it under the moonlight stone’s gentle light.

“Xi!” Han Li exhaled in surprise.

Stone it was not. It was clearly a large pile of remains, bones with traces of rotting flesh that released the faint smell of blood.

After recovering from his astonishment, he discovered that the bones were from fierce predators such as tigers and leopards and had traces of teeth marks as if something had been biting them.

Having seen this, Han Li sunk into thought before inwardly shouting, ‘Not good!’ He hastily turned to leave the cave.

However, it was already too late. A black shadow scuttled out of some unknown place and fiercely knocked against Han Li’s white scale shield.

Suddenly, he was thrown off with intense force and fiercely slammed into the cave wall. Although he was shielded, the pain nearly caused him to pass out.

“What is this monster?” Han Li thought this with furious alarm through the severe pain.

But without waiting for Han Li to fall from the cave wall, the shadow pounced toward him once more.

Han Li reacted in fear, hurriedly placing both his defensive magic tools in front of him.

Dāng. A clear ring surprised Han Li.

This time, the impact didn’t carry a great force. Bang. However, the white scale shield was evenly split into two pieces and had fallen onto the floor.

Han Li nearly bit his tongue from terror.

Inconceivable! That monster was actually able to split his white scale shield in two!

Chapter 345: A Small Old Man and Bell Tolls

After looking through the items in the storage pouch, Han Li bluntly moved all of the items into his own storage pouch before slicing the original storage pouch into pieces.

Although this storage pouch was clearly much better than his own, Han Li didn’t dare to use it as he wasn’t sure if the bag possessed any hidden traces.

Han Li then rested for another day before he felt that it was about time to leave. With Crooked Soul in tow, he flew toward Yellow Maple Valley instead of the Seven Sects Camp.

Han Li reckoned that if anything bad occurred at the Seven Sects Camp, the sects would be the first to receive this information. Therefore, he first headed to the sect in order to hear if there was any news. If nothing was out of the ordinary, then he would quickly convene at the Seven Sects Camp.

After flying for six days, he had uneventfully arrived at the Tai Yue Mountain Range.

Han Li didn’t notify anyone. Instead, he first secretly returned to his own Immortal’s cave first.

Once he entered the cave and closed off his formation from the outside, Han Li felt much more at ease. After all, he was in the safety of his own territory.

Han Li immediately rushed to the secret room containing his spirit well spring.

He found two fist-sized spiders floating in the spirit well spring, having already hatched from their eggs. Although they weren’t large, one could tell that they were beyond ordinary from their sparkling and translucent bodies.

Upon seeing Han Li, the small spiders blurred, immediately shooting toward him. Han Li was surprised at first, but something immediately came to mind, and he didn’t avoid them.

As a result, the two spiders steadily landed on Han Li’s shoulders and mischievously crawled over Han Li’s body.

Han Li faintly smiled. It seems the soul controlling restriction that used his blood essence had an effect. The two spiders already saw him as their parent and thus had shown such affection.

Delighted, Han Li picked up a spider off of his body and carefully observed it with curiosity.

Although spiders generally gave people feelings of great disgust and hate, this spider had a shining, pure-white body. It was extremely beautiful, giving people the notion of wanting to pet it in admiration.

But what surprised Han Li the most was that the small spider already had the Spiritual Qi of a fourth layer Qi Condensation cultivator. It was already a genuine low grade one demonic beast. It appeared it had great potential!

With regards to the white spider’s ranking on the list, it was listed as the “Bloodjade Spider” at about rank one hundred. Although it was not as fearsome as the “Golden-Back Demon Mantis”, it was a rare breed.

Han Li played around with the two small spiders for a moment before placing them inside a leather bag. Since he didn’t know when he would be able to return, he naturally wanted to carry them with him so that he could properly train them.

Afterwards, Han Li went to his own bedroom and took out a small chest from underneath his bed.

The box contained storage pouches filled with all kinds of talismans. Han Li casually took two of them. Since he had nearly used all of the talismans on hand, he had to replenish them.

Having finished his affairs, Han Li left Crooked Soul in his Immortal’s cave and confidently flew straight toward Yellow Maple Valley.

Perhaps it was because a majority of the people had already hurried off to the Seven Sects’ Camp, Han Li only came across a few separated Qi Condensation disciples. He casually stopped one and made an inquiry about the circumstances of the valley. No news had arrived about misfortune falling upon the Seven Sects, much to Han Li’s relief.

But since this had only come from a Qi Condensation disciple, Han Li couldn’t let this matter drop. After a moment of consideration, he headed straight toward the Hundred Medicine Garden. As a mid Foundation Establishment cultivator, that small old man should have some reliable information.

A short moment later, Han Li had appeared above the Hundred Medicine Garden, but he was blocked by the white mist formation spell.

He had long returned its command medallion to the small old man and could no longer enter the Hundred Medicine Garden as he pleased.

Although Han Li had already witnessed the power of the Five Elements Reversal Formation, the small old man’s simple illusion formation was still able to obstruct Han Li. Instead of entering by force, Han Li sent a sound transmission talisman instead; after speaking into it, it turned into a streak of fire, flying into the white mist.

Not long after, the white mist below him blew away, allowing him a path in.

When Han Li saw this, he chuckled and gently descended.

When he arrived at the center of the Hundred Medicine Garden, he found two people waiting for him.

“Senior Martial Brother Ma, it’s been a while!” Han Li grinned at a small old man as he said this.

“Humph! Even without seeing each other, you still went and found trouble for me!” The small old man, the master of the Hundred Medicine Garden, didn’t greet him with a smile and rolled his eyes instead.

“Hehe! Could it be that such an adorable disciple like Young Lady Xiao is not to your satisfaction?” Han Li continued to grin at him completely without concern.

With a slightly red face, the young woman saluted Han Li and greeted him with gratitude, “Xiao Cui’er pays her respects to Martial Uncle Han. Many thanks for Martial Uncle’s great kindness!”

This young girl was the granddaughter of that Xiao grandparent-grandchild pair.

When the small old man heard this, he revealed an unsightly expression. But when he wanted to say something, Han Li quickly interrupted him. “Senior Martial Brother Ma, the reason why I came here is because I have a few important matters to discuss with you. It concerns something significant!” Han Li suddenly said with a solemn expression.

Having seen Han Li’s solemn expression, the small old man wrinkled his brow. An instant later, he instructed Xiao Cui’er, “Guard the garden’s entrance. I have a few matters to discuss with your Martial Uncle Han!”

“Yes, Master!” The young woman respectfully replied and silently walked to the garden’s entrance.

Xiao Cui’er’s obedient action was clearly to the small old man’s satisfaction. He had even revealed a trace of a fond expression.

When Han Li saw this, he inwardly laughed. This Senior Martial Brother Ma said that he gave him trouble, but he was inwardly fond of Xiao Cui’er. Even so, he was still trying so hard to save face in spite of this!

The small old man brought Han Li into his guest room. After they both sat down, he insipidly asked, “Junior Martial Brother, shouldn’t you be at the border camp? How do you still have time to come here for questions? Let’s hear what’s so important that you had to come here!”

Senior Martial Brother Ma wore an indifferent expression.

“... It’s a long story!” Han Li sighed and bitterly smiled.

Because Han Li had been friends with the small old man for so many years, he knew that although the old man’s words were caustic, he had a truly good character. Thus, he had told him about his encounter with the Controlling Spirit Sect cultivator. Naturally, Han Li glossed over the finer details of the fight and focused on the possibility that Spirit Beast Mountain was still working with the Devil Dao.

After hearing Han Li out, the small old man’s expression became stiff.

A long while later, he eventually asked Han Li with a strange expression, “Junior Martial Brother Han! You exterminated the soul of a Core Formation cultivator? And Spirit Beast Mountain is still an agent of the Devil Dao?”

He was in complete disbelief as if he had listened to a tall tale.

Han Li’s face became bitter in response.

It was no wonder why the old man was like this. No one could be convinced in such a short amount of time.

Han Li tensely wrinkled his brow and replied, “I don’t know how reliable this information is. That’s why I returned to the sect first to see if there was any news from the border camp. If nothing had happened, I would be able to go there with an easy heart.” Han Li didn’t conceal anything from the small old man, fully revealing his great desire to preserve his own life.

“There is nothing. We’ve only received requests to transport large quantities of spirit stones and other supplies. No negative news had arrived. It has all been very ordinary.” The small old man said with a stern expression.

Han Li lightly sighed and stroked his nose, muttering, “It seems I was completely made a fool of by him! I want to curse that cultivator out to vent my gloominess. Or maybe I should be celebrating that nothing bad had happened to the main camp instead?”

Dāng. Dāng. Just as he finished speaking, the sound of a huge bell continuously tolled from the official hall.

The small old man and Han Li couldn’t help but look at each other in dismay.

The bell tolls continued for the time it would take to finish a cup of tea before stopping.

The small old man had an extremely unsightly expression and took a deep breath. He spoke with a deep voice, “No less than eighty-one tolls. It seems your information is most likely true. The circumstances are far from great!”

“Let’s go and see what happened. It might not have anything to do with my information.” Han Li calmly said after a moment of silence.

“Humph! It’d be a miracle if it were not! If it’s not a major defeat at the frontlines, what else would cause the Dragonwaking Bell to toll eighty-one times, representing a extermination level crisis of our sect?” The small old man bitterly smiled.

Chapter 347: Evacuation

When they arrived at the rear hall, the old man was standing with his hands held behind his back.

Seeing that the many cultivators had arrived, he said with a calm expression, “Those of you that I had just chosen have good aptitude or have practiced exceptional cultivation arts. As such, you are the spark that will ignite our sect’s revival. Therefore, I will give you all half a day to immediately return and retrieve your items. Afterwards, Martial Nephew Huang will lead you on your journey.”

Everyone was shocked. Someone then asked in bewilderment, “Venerable Ancestor, don’t we still have two more days before the Devil Dao breach our defensive line? Why the hurry?”

“Humph! While it will take two days to break through our defensive line, do you believe that they will allow those left behind to slip away? They will send men past the defensive line to attack the distant sects, most likely with the objective to obstruct our escape rather than extermination. For this reason, we will sacrifice those outside in order to buy time for you to retreat. But if you dare to leak this matter during the time you are to retrieve your items, our retreat will be met with great chaos, and I will have to personally dispose of the sect.” The ancestor’s voice was extremely callous, causing the hearts of those present to tremble.

“Yes, Venerable Ancestor.”

……

Naturally, Han Li and the others didn’t dare to object. They all respectfully agreed and went out to retrieve their items.

On their way back, Han Li and the small old man parted with much on their minds.

Because Han Li’s Immortal’s cave was too far away, he had to fly at full speed on his Divine Wind Boat.

Han Li’s heart was in turmoil.

According to what Ancestor Ling Hu said, Han Li would no longer have to worry about his well-being. If they were to move to another country, he would be regarded as valuable due to the fact that manpower was lacking.

But at the same time, they would have to conquer territory in a new country in order to establish Yellow Maple Valley. As one of the remaining Foundation Establishment cultivators, Han Li would be preoccupied with miscellaneous affairs. He would no longer have much time remaining to cultivate!

Presumably, when this matter had been settled and the six sects have reestablished themselves, he would’ve already come across an opportunity to advance to the Core Formation stage. However, Han Li was unwilling to deal with these troublesome affairs for such a long period of time.

But as Han Li entertained the idea of making his escape, he had no idea whether or not he was still being observed by that old eccentric’s spiritual sense. He didn’t know if his actions could still be observed at this distance. If this were the case, he would be certain to meet a tragic end if he deserted.

Han Li felt great regret. Had he known that the situation had deteriorated to this degree, he definitely would’ve fled the country instead of returning!

Without any other option, Han Li could only return to his Immortal’s cave.

Upon entering his Immortal’s cave, he first headed to his bedroom and took all the talisman-filled storage pouches from underneath his bed. He then went to his storage room and put away his remaining rare medicine ingredients.

Lastly, he went to the secret room that held the spirit well spring and completely destroyed it, concealing the spirit well spring.

Since he was currently unable to transport this item, Han Li didn’t want those from the Devil Dao to make use of it.

Having finished all that, Han Li inspected his residence thoroughly once more. Feeling that he hadn’t overlooked anything, he called Crooked Soul out of the cave before carefully removing and putting away the formation flags and plates of the first set of the “Five Phases Reversal Formation”.

After the formation spell disappeared, he looked at the large entrance of his Immortal’s cave. With an intense gaze, he suddenly released two streaks of black light and smashed the mountaintop, thoroughly concealing his immortal’s cave.

Subsequently, he released the Divine Wind Boat and brought Crooked Soul on board. After flying a circle around his former home, he finally flew off.

By the time Han Li returned to the Official Hall, most of the others had already arrived. Leaving Crooked Soul outside, he entered the hall by himself.

But what surprised him was that apart from tens of Foundation Establishment cultivators, several hundred Qi Condensation Disciples were also gathered outside the hall.

‘Could it be that they will evacuate together with us?’ Han Li thought doubtfully.

His eyes suddenly brightened upon seeing the small old man and Xiao Cui’er. They were quietly talking to each other with grim expressions.

Having seen this, Han Li walked over without hesitation.

“Martial Uncle Han!” Xiao Cui’er respectfully greeted Han Li when she saw him approach.

Han Li nodded to her with a smile and then turned toward the small old man, whispering, “What’s going on? Are these Qi Condensation disciples travelling with us?”

Han Li spoke in a soft voice to avoid attracting the others’ attention.

“That’s right!”

“To avoid being easily abandoned, these disciples either possessed exceptional aptitude or distinguished status. My own disciple also has exceptional aptitude!” The small old man spoke indifferently. But when he mentioned Xiao Cui’er, he revealed a trace of pride; Han Li found this somewhat humorous.

A short while later, Ancestor Ling Hu and a valiant middle-aged man appeared.

“I’ve just received information that traces of Devil Dao cultivators have been spotted nearby. We must all immediately set off. Obey Martial Nephew Huang’s orders from now on! I will gather the remaining sect members to draw the enemy.” Ancestor Ling Hu spoke with a solemn expression.

Han Li and the others were shocked by what they heard. The Devil Dao were truly swift!

The valiant middle-aged man who stood by his side followed up, coldly saying, “As time is pressing, I will keep it short. In this evacuation, I only have one demand. You must all listen to my orders. Those that disobey will be regarded as traitors. We will now depart!”

This person was truly quick and decisive! With those brief statements, he respectfully saluted the old man before taking the lead to leave the hall.

After a moment of astonishment, everyone rushed after him like a swarm of bees.

As a result, the grand crowd of several hundred cultivators took to the skies and hurriedly flew toward the northeast.

……

Over half a day later, the group had arrived at the Tai Yue Mountain Range. At that point, they slightly increased their speed.

Standing on the Divine Wind Boat, Han Li flew near the front of the group. When the small old man saw that Han Li’s Divine Wind Boat could carry more, he dragged Xiao Cui’er into the boat with him without a trace of politeness. Han Li could only bitterly laugh in response and said nothing more.

Xiao Cui’er was a bit interested in Crooked Soul who stood behind Han Li and stared at him with wide eyes. Naturally, the young girl was able to somewhat see through Crooked Soul. After asking a few questions, she no longer pressed the issue.

After travelling over fifty kilometers through the Tai Yue Mountain Range, a streak of white light suddenly shot toward the group from behind. In the blink of an eye, it travelled past the group and into the hand of Martial Uncle Huang. It was a sparkling short sword with a jade slip tied to it.

The middle-aged man’s face darkened and he waved his hand, stopping the group.

After taking the jade slip off, he casually flung the short sword away. Immediately after, it transformed back into a streak of white light and flew back toward its original location.

Martial Uncle Huang then probed the jade slip with his spiritual sense. A moment later, his face became very unsightly, and he immediately lowered his head in deep contemplation. It was obvious that a troublesome matter had occurred.

“The circumstances have changed. All Foundation Establishment cultivators step forward. I must assign you another duty.” The middle-aged man turned around and said this with a dark expression.

These words left Han Li and company stunned. But after they looked at each other, Xiao Cui’er cleverly jumped off the Divine Wind Boat, and they obediently flew forward.

“Martial Uncle, what happened?” Many had witnessed the middle-aged man receiving a message from the flying sword.

“Venerable Ancestor sent us a message. The Devil Dao is about to arrive. It seems like they knew of our plan and separated into two groups. One group moved to surround Yellow Maple Valley, while the other group chased after us. In order to protect our continued retreat, I require a squad to follow me and draw them away. As I block them, those who remain will follow those that I assign and continue their escape from the State of Yue.” Martial Uncle Huang said in an ice-cold tone.

Their hearts trembled upon hearing his words.

They weren’t fools. Being assigned to block the Devil Dao would most likely result in death!

Although a majority of them evaded his gaze, Martial Uncle Huang started pointing without restraint. In a single breath, he had picked over twenty Foundation Establishment cultivators.

While the small old man managed to escape calamity, Han Li was unfortunately among those chosen!

Those that were chosen became deathly pale, but they didn’t dare to utter any words of refusal.

With a wave of an arm, Martial Uncle Huang sent the others to continue their journey, leaving Han Li and company behind.

“We are pressed for time! I know that you all don’t think very favorably of this assignment, but I don’t need to you stake your all to meet the enemy. I only request that you mount an ambush and draw their attention away from our retreating forces.” The middle-aged man said with a relaxed tone. He then took out about twenty green jade slips.

“Memorize the map inside the jade slip and then destroy it! If you are later separated, you will be able to regroup again in accordance to the map.” Martial Uncle Huang waved his hand and streaks of green light shot toward the twenty-plus cultivators and floated in front of them.

Having heard Martial Uncle Huang’s words, the others’ complexion improved visibly. Since they didn’t have to rigidly block the Devil Dao, their chances of survival were much higher. As a result, they all grabbed the jade slips and started to memorize the map contained within.

Han Li only skimmed through the jade slip in passing and didn’t take it to heart.

After all, this assignment to remain behind and block the Devil Dao was a rare opportunity to escape. Han Li was unwilling to stay with Yellow Maple Valley to the very end for a later opportunity to reach Core Formation.

Chapter 348: Heavenfire Technique

After seeing that everyone had crushed their jade slips, Martial Uncle Huang revealed an expression of satisfaction.

His hands then flashed with yellow light, and a small foot-long banner appeared in his hand. The banner was white and glowed with a yellow radiance, rendering its embroidery difficult to discern.

“I will use the Cloud-Wind Banner to mask the traces of your presence. When the enemy arrives, launch your ambush when they are most vulnerable.”

Martial Uncle Huang then lightly shook the small flag in his hands, releasing countless strands of milky-white vapor from his flag. In the blink of an eye, a huge, hundred-meter-wide cloud had appeared, concealing Han Li and company within.

Han Li and the other Foundation Establishment cultivators were pleasantly surprised by the sudden concealment! This cloud was exceptionally thick, but for some unknown reason, their vision wasn’t obstructed in the least. It would serve as exceptionally good cover!

Martial Uncle Huang continued his casting, causing the cloud to further expand. Soon after, they could no longer see anything outside of the cloud.

Han Li was left speechless!

Although his magic tool “Azurefire Miasma” could also turn into a thick cloud, it was incomparable to the Cloud-Wind Banner. Not only was the scope of his Azurefire Miasma smaller, he could only use it on himself; anyone else within it would be poisoned.

With that thought, Han Li couldn’t help but glance at Martial Uncle Huang.

He was sitting down cross-legged with his eyes shut in the cloud. Two Foundation Establishment cultivators were attentively standing behind him. It seemed that they were his bodyguards.

Han Li stared blankly for a moment. But soon after, he came to the realization that Martial Uncle Huang was using his spiritual sense to scout for enemies. As a Core Formation cultivator’s spiritual sense was great and could detect movements within a radius of a hundred kilometers, he should be capable of detecting them.

Having seen this, Han Li sat on his Divine Wind Boat and rested. The upcoming fight would be incredibly dangerous. Crooked Soul remained motionless behind him, appearing steadfast.

After two hours, Martial Uncle Huang spoke, “The enemy has arrived. We’re about a kilometer away from them. We need to intercept their advance.” He then took off without another word, bringing the cloud with him.

Everyone within the cloud naturally didn’t dare to leave its cover and hurriedly followed after Martial Uncle Huang on their magic tools.

Han Li wrinkled his brow and took out his huge silver sword as he flew, giving it to Crooked Soul. Although he didn’t know how useful it would be, it was still better to try to increase one’s fighting capabilities.

“We are here. The enemy will soon arrive. Everyone, prepare yourselves!” Martial Uncle Huang commanded. After a short moment, the cloud had arrived in the enemy’s path.

Suddenly, everyone’s magic tools started shining, and they began to apply defensive magic techniques to their bodies. Sparkles of light flashed from within the cloud.

Han Li took out two azure-red spheres and lightly bumped them together. With a muffled thump, a concentrated azure-red mist was released from the two spheres, quickly enveloping Han Li. In the blink of an eye, a huge, twenty-meter-wide azure-red cloud completely concealed Han Li.

Han Li had unexpectedly used the Azurefire Miasma to form a cloud as a defense while still within Martial Uncle Huang’s cloud. The nearby cultivators were stunned, not understanding Han Li’s intentions.

Han Li didn’t pay attention to his fellow sect members. He grabbed his tortoise shell with one hand and held an common blue throwing knife in the other hand instead of taking out his Black Dragon Claws.

Han Li clearly understood what he was doing. In his mind, the more low-profile the magic tool, the better. Only then would he avoid any troublesome attention during the raid and easily make his escape.

Everyone waited attentively, and in the blink of an eye, ten minutes had passed. However, not a single enemy was found.

A majority of the waiting cultivators grew anxious and impatient. They couldn’t help but look at Martial Uncle Huang with doubt.

The valiant Martial Uncle Huang now also appeared doubtful, but after a moment of thought, he unhurriedly said, “Everyone, do not worry. I will launch a search with my spiritual sense.”

As he sat down, a deafening series of booms suddenly sounded out from the sky before he could even start. The sounds increased in intensity and occurrence until they appeared to be coming from all directions.

Alarmed by the sudden noise, the cultivators quickly turned their heads to the sky. What they saw left their faces pale.

The sky had turned red at an unknown time, and all of the clouds had turned into fiery-red ash clouds as if they were made of boiling lava. The huge rumbling sounds came from bursting pockets of lava within the clouds.

“What’s going on?!” Someone to the side of Han Li shouted in horror.

“Everyone, be careful! This is the intermediate high-grade “Heavenfire” magic technique. Lava will begin dripping from above, with each drop equivalent to a Foundation Establishment cultivator’s strike! If you do not block it, you will turn into ashes.” As Senior Uncle Huang said this, his face became extremely unsightly.

It was clear that the ambushers had now become the ambushed.

“Then let's quickly escape! I have no intention of trying to block this!” Someone said with panic. He was prepared to fly off immediately.

“It is already too late! The magic technique is complete, and we are now trapped within it. Everyone, gather together and form a defensive barrier!”Martial Uncle Huang’s eyes flashed with coldness as he gave his commands with fierce resolution.

Having heard his orders, the others suddenly understood the situation and hastily acted together. With a flash of blue light, they erected a huge light barrier.

In nearly the same instant that the barrier was formed, the intermediate high-grade magic technique started to wreak devastation from the sky. It struck down upon Han Li and company, but the barrier they had just erected managed to easily repel the attacks.

However, that was only the beginning of the rain of lava. Although the majority of the attacks missed, a significant amount of damage had been inflicted upon the light barrier, causing it to spark with red and blue light.

Initially, the group felt that they had energy to spare, but the lava soon began dropping at an increased rate and in larger quantities. In turn, the group’s spiritual power expenditure also quickly increased. At this rate, they wouldn’t be able to last for long.

The barrier of blue light gradually weakened from the assault.

Fortunately, this formidable magic technique ended as quickly as it began. Just as the barrier was on the verge of collapse, the Heavenfire Technique reached its end, and the clouds of lava disappeared without a trace, causing the Yellow Maple Valley cultivators to feel relieved.

However, their happy expressions immediately froze a moment later.

At some point during the attack, they had been silently surrounded by nearly a hundred cultivators. From their attire, they appeared to be from the Devil Dao. They were all looking down at the Yellow Maple Valley cultivators with a trace of ridicule.

The Yellow Maple Valley cultivators were both furious and frightened! However, the surrounding cultivators were only Foundation Establishment disciples. Not a single Core Formation cultivator was amongst them, causing the Yellow Maple Valley cultivators to sigh in relief. Although they had consumed much of their magic power, they still had a Core Formation cultivator among them. There should be no need to be afraid.

“How did you know we were here? My Cloud-Wind Banner should’ve concealed us from your spiritual sense!” Martial Uncle Huang asked with a sunken expression.

“I can answer that!” A slurred, coquettish voice came from above, causing Martial Uncle Huang’s heart to tremble in fear. He hastily looked toward the sky and saw a man and woman floating down from above.

The man had a head full of white hair and was shriveled to the bone, appearing as if the slightest breeze could knock him over. The woman was seductively attractive with a slender waist and generous bottom. Every one of her movements tugged at the heart.

Han Li silently cursed. The two in the air were actually Core Formation cultivators. Their appearance brought greater trouble.

“Fair Rouge and Skeleton?” Upon seeing the two, Martial Uncle Huang’s pupils shrank.

Without waiting for their reply, he suddenly waved his Cloud-Wind banner and caused the white mist to completely disappear, revealing Han Li and company. While facing such powerful enemies, he naturally couldn’t afford to look after Han Li and his other martial nephews.

“Heehee, I truly didn’t expect that Fellow Daoist would recognize this couple! This isn’t fair! You recognized us husband and wife, but we are rather unfamiliar with Fellow Daoist. However, I have heard of an ice-cold fellow from Yellow Maple Valley that had a very interesting magic treasure called the Cloud-Wind Banner. Could your esteemed self be him?” The seductive woman chuckled as if she didn’t possess the slightest hostility.

But upon seeing the woman’s delicate, charming smile, Martial Uncle Huang’s expression only grew colder. He continued to stare at her in silence.

The woman faintly smiled in response to his silence, before suddenly shouting, “How utterly boring. Kill them!”

“Alright. Since Junior Martial Sister wants his life, I will naturally obey!” The shriveled ‘Skeleton’ chuckled and sinisterly said.

At that moment, Han Li and company heard their Martial Uncle’s voice transmission in their ears, “Once I act, immediately break through their enclosure. Run away as far as you can.”

Martial Uncle Huang’s voice was completely devoid of emotion.

Chapter 350: Instant Kill

Han Li calmly looked at the two without speaking a word. However, he clearly understood that these two most likely had something to do with Qi Yunxiao’s residence being destroyed.

In response to Han Li’s silence, the youth couldn’t help but ask, “Who is your esteemed self, and what is your relationship with that fellow named Qi?”

Upon hearing this, Han Li merely gave the youth a cold glance before ignoring him and turning his gaze back to the old man. It was obvious that with regard to cultivation, the old man was the one who was truly in charge.

When the youth saw Han Li disregard him, he was furious. Although he knew that Han Li was a Foundation Establishment cultivator, his clan was one of the most prestigious clans in the State of Yuanwu. He had never been treated like this before.

Furthermore, due to the matter regarding Qi Yunxiao, he was already filled with anger. Thus, he clenched his teeth and wanted to release his magic tools. But just as he was about to move his arm, the old man grabbed onto it, stopping him.

“Not yet! We still don’t know who this person is. We must find that out first before we take further action!” The old man stated with a calm expression.

The youth then glanced somewhat suspiciously at Crooked Soul, who stood behind Han Li. Crooked Soul didn’t have the aura of a living person, yet he could feel magic power fluctuations from his body. He felt that it was inconceivable.

When Han Li heard this, his eyes narrowed. The old man was a mid Foundation Establishment cultivator yet he spoke as if he were not to be trifled with, causing Han Li to grow slightly apprehensive.

“Were you the ones who destroyed this place?” Han Li asked with poise.

“What relation does Fellow Daoist have with Qi Yunxiao? Are you from the Qi Clan?” The old man responded to Han Li’s question with his own.

Han Li slightly wrinkled his brow. It seemed the other party wouldn’t honestly answer him as he only exchanged one question for another.

“Seems like we both don’t wish to answer one another. Wouldn’t it be better to exchange answers with each other? That way we can waste less of each other’s time.” Han Li asked with raised eyebrows.

The old man was surprised for a moment. But after pondering for a moment, he agreed.

“Since I was the one who proposed this, how about you ask first?” Han Li said insipidly.

“Is your esteemed self a member of the Qi Clan?” The old man immediately asked without a trace of politeness.

In turn, Han Li responded without the slightest of hesitation: “I am not!”

Having heard Han Li’s resolute reply, both the old man and the youth were surprised and revealed an expression of doubt.

“Is Qi Yunxiao currently dead or alive?” Han Li unhurriedly asked.

“He’s still alive!” The old man hesitated for a moment before answering.

The words “still alive”, immediately put Han Li’s heart at ease.

“What relationship does your esteemed self have with Qi Yunxiao?” The old man cautiously asked.

“I have a business deal with him,” Han Li coldly responded.

“A business deal?” Surprise flashed through the old man’s eyes.

“Where is Qi Yunxiao currently?” Although Han Li asked this casually, he was feeling quite worried.

“I cannot tell you this!” The old man instantly rejected.

“Then I will change the question. Why did you attack Qi Yunxiao?” Han Li immediately asked another question without batting an eye at his refusal.

“He killed members of our Fu Clan. Why shouldn’t we kill him?” The youth to the side quickly answered with a sneer.

The old man wrinkled his brow, revealing a trace of annoyance, but he didn’t say anything more.

“Fu Clan!” When Han Li heard this, he was instantly reminded of those Qi Condensation cultivators he had killed while saving Xin Ruyin; he now felt a great desire to kill.[1]

“So it was like that! However, there are only two of you here. If the Qi Clan were to come here with a formidable character, how would you be able to match them?” Han Li casually asked this while appearing indifferent.

“How could any foreign cultivator sent by the Qi Clan oppose the two of us from the Fu Clan? Could it be that we are not enough?” The youth proudly answered Han Li’s inquiry.

“So, you two are here alone?” Han Li suddenly asked with a deep voice.

“Why are you asking this?” The youth was thinking of how to respond with an angry expression, but the old man at his side suddenly asked this with suspicion.

However, it was already too late. Han Li suddenly raised his arms and shot two streaks of black light toward the youth. Afterwards, he patted his storage pouch, releasing over ten streaks of white light. In the blink of an eye, those lights transformed into puppet beasts and puppet soldiers.

Once those puppets appeared, they immediately released a mad barrage of light beams and light arrows.

When the old man saw this, he felt aghast. His body instantly blurred and appeared beside the youth, summoning a copper coin magic tool in front of him. In an instant, it grew to the size of a table and blocked the incoming attacks.

A series of explosions could be heard as numerous beams of light struck the copper coin. Each strike pushed the old man further and further back, much to his dismay.

But in the next moment, the youth next to him let out a miserable shriek, causing the old man to hastily turn his head in dread. But as he turned his head, his neck suddenly felt cold and everything went dark.

After the old man’s headless body fell to the ground, Han Li was the only one remaining in the air with a faintly shining thread tied to the ring finger of his right hand.

Just a moment ago, Han Li took advantage of the massive, eye-catching assault to conceal his movements. By using the Smoke Shifting Steps, he was able to travel over sixty meters away from his Divine Wind Boat in a few breaths, arriving behind the two. Then, with a wave of his string, he was able to easily behead them.

Han Li had found this battle to be as easy as dusting off his clothes!

Han Li found it quite humorous. In a battle between Foundation Establishment cultivators, elemental defensive barriers basically weren’t used because they were unable to block the attacks of top grade magic techniques. They required too much time to activate, and they were far too expensive. Thus, most people used defensive magic tools to protect themselves instead of defensive light barriers that they felt were useless.

That kind of thinking had given Han Li many openings to take advantage of. This was especially apparent when Han Li originally fought the Devil Dao cultivators at the border as a majority of his kills had died in this manner.

Now that he thought about it, this particular killing technique was quite similar to that of the Black Fiend School’s Blood Servant, Ice Demon. It was as fast as lightning; by the time they hear the thunder, it was already too late. Unfortunately, this technique could only be used on the ground. Otherwise, Han Li would have no one to fear among Foundation Establishment cultivators.

Han Li lightly shook his head, feeling a great sense of lamentation in his heart!

He walked in front of the headless corpses and collected their storage pouches. After he inspected them with his spiritual sense, he felt some disappointment.

Although they possessed three top grade magic tools, they were of common quality. Han Li did not have much use for them. On the other hand, that copper coin was a rarely seen defensive magic tool.

With that in mind, Han Li restored it to its original size and had it fly into his hand. After happily admiring it for a moment, he flung two small fireballs toward the headless corpses and turned them into ashes. Back in the boat with Crooked Soul, Han Li circled through the vicinity once before taking to the skies.

This time, he would go to that small mountain with Xin Ruyin’s residence. He hoped her home was well hidden enough that it hadn’t encountered any mishaps.

Six hours later, Han Li arrived at the nameless mountain of Xin Ruyin’s residence.

When Han Li saw that the fog above the mountain was intact and the same as before, he felt overjoyed.

After musing for short while, Han Li didn’t dare to fly down. Instead, he flew halfway up the mountain before taking out a sound transmission talisman. He then softly whispered a few words into it before throwing it out.

The sound transmission talisman turned into a fiery streak of light and flew towards the mountain, suddenly disappearing from sight. Soon after, a large portion of the fog rose and completely enveloped him.

Han Li stood still as he saw a scene bloom before him, leaving him surrounded by gargantuan trees over three hundred meters tall. He couldn’t help but feel shocked, feeling like an ant among the huge trees.

Still, he knew that once Xin Ruyin received the sound transmission talisman, she should be quick to come meet him.

As expected, the huge tree illusions turned into thick fog a short moment later. Then the fog parted and revealed a three meter wide passageway.

The passage was remarkably long. After traveling for over two hundred meters, he was finally able to faintly see its opening and couldn’t help but grow excited.

But when he was about twenty meters away from the exit, he suddenly heard a hoarse woman’s voice: “Senior Han, who is that person behind you? You shouldn’t be bringing strangers to this place.”

[1]. Xin Ruyin is Qi Yunxiao's unrequited love and master of formation spells. Introduced in Chapter 277: Xin Ruyin.

[Back]

Chapter 352: Promise

Han Li didn’t immediately refuse or agree. Instead, he tightly wrinkled his brow and lowered his head in silence, weighing the potential gains and losses.

Truth be told, Han Li was unwilling to agree.

As of current, Han Li held little interest in spell formation and tool refinement techniques. Only after he successfully reached Core Formation would he have the time to research such things. In addition, he was unwilling to provoke a huge cultivator clan for no reason, not to mention that he didn’t have the ability to do so.

“I understand that this request is overreaching, but Ruyin truly doesn’t have any other way.” Xin Ruyin gave a bleak smile with a pale complexion.

“Elder Brother Qi’s death by the Fu Clan was because of the incident that I brought about. If I do not avenge my husband, then I wouldn’t have the face to see him after I die; I would prefer to go to hell!” Xin Ruyin softly whispered with a pleading tone.

When Han Li heard her say ‘die’, he couldn’t help but raise his eyebrows as he suddenly thought of something. He suddenly raised his head, taking a careful look at Xin Ruyin’s complexion and leaving Xin Ruyin stunned in response.

“There is something amiss with your complexion. Let me see your veins.” Han Li spoke in an irrefutable tone, greatly surprising Xin Ruyin.

A queer glint flashed from her eyes. After a moment of hesitation, she obediently handed Han Li her flawless wrist.

Han Li impolitely brought two fingers to her wrist and poured a strand of Spiritual Qi into her body.

A long while later, Han Li’s expression became unsightly.

“Are you aware that your blood vessels have completely withered away? If this is not addressed, you will die within two years!” Han Li coldly said after withdrawing his hand.

Xin Ruyin faintly smiled in response to Han Li’s assertion.

“Of course I know this. How could I not know about my own body? My constitution is of the Dragon’s Cry, a male body wrongly born as female. If someone with this constitution were to forcefully cultivate, their meridians would gradually wither away along with their lifespan. For me to have lived this long was by mere luck. Originally, I had hoped to find an ancient formula to cure this illness. However, I failed, merely wasting the many spiritual medicines that Elder Brother Qi had searched for in vain!” Xin Ruyin revealed an expression of self-mockery.

“Young Madam!” Xin Ruyin’s maid couldn’t help but shout out with sadness from behind her.

“It’s nothing, Xiao Mei! I am only going to see Elder Brother Qi a bit sooner. This is exactly what I desire!” Xin Ruyin unexpectedly consoled her maid with a peaceful expression.

Han Li’s expression grew soft and for some unknown reason, he truly felt pity toward her. But unfortunately, Han Li couldn’t do anything about Xin Ruyin’s strange illness and could only watch on as her life and beauty withered away.

“Since Senior Han now knows of this matter, he should understand why I have acted in this manner. Although Senior is currently only a Foundation Establishment cultivator, you are the sole person familiar with Elder Brother Qi and me that has a chance of avenging him. I don’t require Senior to swear an oath. I only want a promise, so that I may pass away with ease.” Xin Ruyin returned to her previously calm demeanor and nonchalantly mentioned the matter of vengeance again.

Han Li stroked his nose with all his strength, finding himself in a rather difficult position. But after a moment of hard thought, he suddenly asked, “What about those from Fellow Daoist Qi’s clan?”

“Humph, the Qi Clan? They are merely a common clan within the State of Yuanwu. How could they dare to offend the Fu Clan? Besides, Elder Brother Qi was only an external branch disciple driven out from the sect. They couldn’t be less concerned! As for me, I’ve learned everything from a nameless formation spell grandmaster. He was a rogue cultivator that had long since passed away.” Xin Ruyin understood what Han Li meant and explained her and Qi Yunxiao’s background to Han Li in a soft voice.

Han Li’s mind grew quiet. He had truly thought that this woman had an alternative.

“Fine, I can give Young Lady Xin this promise! However, I will only act when I possess the ability to do so. If such an opportunity does not appear in my lifetime, will you regret it?” After pondering for a long while, Han Li took a deep breath and spoke in a heavy voice.

“That will be enough! So long as you can give me hope, it will do. Let me thank Senior Han in advance!” Xin Ruyin couldn’t help but widely smile in response, suddenly appearing daintily beautiful.

Han Li was stunned as he took in her beauty. But soon after, he shook his head and bluntly swiped his sleeve across the table, causing to two jade boxes to disappear without a trace into his storage pouch.

“Since you require another month to restore the transportation formation, then I will have to trouble Young Lady Xin in a month’s time. I will now be taking my leave!” Han Li spoke unhurriedly as he stood up. With this gap of time available, he had quite a few matters to attend to.

“This one pays Senior her respects!” Xin Ruyin said respectfully without further urging Han Li to stay.

As a result, Han Li flew to the Heavenly Star Sect’s market city with Crooked Soul in tow.

After a day, Han Li arrived in the vicinity of the market city. After he took out a cloak from his storage pouch and covered his face, he entered the market city with a swagger, bringing Crooked Soul along with him.

As Han Li walked through the streets of the market city, he was astonished to find so many cultivators trading and bustling about.

There were several times as many cultivators compared to the last time he came here. In addition to the hurried atmosphere, there were also a few rarely seen Foundation Establishment cultivators within the city.

After pondering for a moment, Han Li’s eyes flashed with thoughtfulness. But soon after, he tossed the matter to the back of his mind and went straight toward that magic tool store that helped him craft his magic tools on his previous trip. He had a few materials that could be refined into useful magic tools, thereby increasing his own strength.

That magic tool store still looked exactly the same as before. Even its arrogant signboard was completely the same.

Han Li entered the store with a faint smile.

The circumstances within the store caused Han Li’s brow to slightly furrow.

The tiny store actually had six people standing and sitting around. When they saw Han Li enter, they couldn’t help but glance at him.

When Han Li saw them, he swept his cold gaze past them without a trace of politeness. In response, they immediately lowered their heads. As Qi Condensation cultivators, they naturally wouldn’t dare to offend Han Li, a “Senior” Foundation Establishment cultivator.

But a man with a fiendish appearance sitting in a chair looked at Han Li without the slightest hint of fear. Although he was only in early Foundation Establishment, he didn’t turn his gaze away.

Han Li didn’t pay him any mind and walked over to the two store employees that were chatting.

“Is Store Owner Xu here?” Han Li calmly asked the burly man called “Dahei”.

“Senior, who...” The burly man revealed an expression of doubt.

Han Li sighed and took out the Black Dragon Claws, revealing them to him. He was assisting at the side as this magic tool was created. There was no way he wouldn’t have recognized it.

“So it turned out to be Senior! This one will call Master out.” The burly man’s eyes brightened, recognizing the Black Dragon Claws as Han Li had expected. He immediately apologized with a wide grin and hastily ran to the back courtyard.

Seeing that Han Li was the store owner’s acquaintance, the others couldn’t help but look at each other in shock. However, nobody dared to untactfully bother Han Li.

Not long after, the fully white-haired shop owner welcomed Han Li with a beaming smile. On his last trip, Han Li left him with a significant amount of rare materials. It was only natural for the old man to give him such a warm welcome.

“This small old man is honored to have Senior come to my shop once more! Does Senior wish to refine more magic tools?” After exchanging a few pleasantries, Old Man Xu impatiently asked with a face full of anticipation.

Han Li faintly smiled and deliberately swept his gaze past the other cultivators in the room.

“How foolish of me!” Shop Owner Xu exclaimed, immediately understanding what Han Li had meant. He then invited Han Li to the rear courtyard and excitedly led the way.

The others didn’t dare to say anything, except for the large, fiendish man who snorted with dissatisfaction. He was greatly angered at how differently he was treated compared to Han Li, as he was also a Foundation Establishment cultivator who had even sought out this Tool Refinement Store.

In response to the large man’s snort, Han Li shot an ice-cold glance at him.

Han Li had killed no small number of cultivators and unconsciously carried a murderous aura as a result. That single glance immediately caused the large man to feel as if his entire body had turned to ice, and he couldn’t help but reveal an expression of terror.

Having seen the large man’s expression had changed, Han Li didn’t pay him any further attention and brought Crooked Soul along with him to the rear courtyard.

At that moment, Dahei cleverly stepped forward and apologized to the others, casually giving them an excuse in an attempt to placate their discontent.

“Did Senior bring back more materials?” When Han Li and Crooked Soul entered the rear courtyard, Shop Owner Xu glanced at Crooked Soul with slight surprise before impatiently asking Han Li.

Chapter 363: Transfer

Not long after that, Han Li walked out of the tree hollow and flew off.

Han Li was even more cautious this time around. During his entire journey, he used his spiritual sense to its greatest extent. Upon hearing even the wind rustling the grass, he would immediately go into hiding. After all, it would be extremely dangerous to negligently run into a cultivator with his current cultivation.

Thus with paranoid levels of carefulness, Han Li eventually arrived back at his underground cave after taking up nearly twice the time he had been away. Only after he entered his Five Elements Reversal Formation did he truly let out a breath of relief.

As for Crooked Soul, he was still obediently sitting at the side of the formation. When Han Li saw that Crooked Soul had remained in the exact same posture that he had left him in, he couldn’t help but smile.

Han Li knew that restoring his cultivation wasn’t a matter requiring merely three or four years. As such, he didn’t meditate or take any pills to cultivate. Instead, he spent the following days wholeheartedly focused on restoring the ancient transportation formation.

Under his current circumstances, travelling to a country far away was much too dangerous. He could only hope that he would be able to use the ancient transportation formation after restoring it.

Although Han Li’s cultivation had greatly declined, it did not obstruct his restoration work. After a sleepless week, he had completely finished its restoration.

Han Li, a normally cool-headed person, felt his heart stir as he looked at the completed ancient transportation formation.

He was at the most crucial step with regards to failure or success. He had to test whether another transportation formation was safely connected to his. If the other end of the transportation formation was damaged or if it no longer existed, then it would naturally be of no use. He could only bury his thoughts of using the transportation formation and find another path forward.

With that in mind, Han Li calmly placed down low-grade spirit stones one after another on the edge of the transportation formation.

When he finished placing the last spirit stones, Han Li hastily took several steps back and couldn’t help but look on with bated breath.

This ancient formation that was created countless years ago suddenly hummed and flashed with yellow radiance before quickly fading away into darkness.

Han Li’s heart dropped! Could it be that the ancient transportation formation on the other end was disabled? This would mean that everything he had done was a complete waste!

Han Li couldn’t help but reveal complete disappointment. But still, he was unresigned. He began walking in circles around the transportation formation with hands behind his back while occasionally muttering to himself.

He suddenly stopped and tightly creased his brow as if he had thought of something. He then crouched down and picked up the low-grade spirit stone at the center of the formation.

Han Li took a close look at it and let out a breath of cold air. The spirit stone was spent and no longer held any trace of Spiritual Qi.

Han Li revealed a thoughtful expression before suddenly brightening up. Without the slightest hesitation, he took out several sparkling mid-grade spirit stones and exchanged them with the low-grade spirit stones he had placed down before.

If he had guessed correctly, the formation didn’t activate because low-grade spirit stones provided an insufficient amount of Spiritual Qi.

After placing down the final spirit stone, the transportation formation immediately started to emit a muffled hum before erupting with huge spiritual ripples. A blinding yellow light shot out from the center of the formation spell and shot outside the cave. The Five Elements Reversal Formation was unable to block it in the slightest.

When Han Li saw this, he was stunned. But something immediately came to mind, and his face turned deathly pale.

At nearly the same time, he suddenly heard huge rumbling sounds from outside the cave. Although he was protected by the huge formation, Han Li still felt the earth-quaking vibrations.

Han Li’s expression grew tense, and he hastily beckoned Crooked Soul as he walked toward the transportation formation.

He couldn’t help but hesitate. He truly had no idea where the transportation formation would take him. He had originally planned to verify what kind of place was at the other end. After confirming the absence of danger, he would then decide whether or not he should remain there. But now that the ancient transportation formation was exposed, this would be a trip of no return.

While Han Li was hesitating, he heard a frightening boom from above and looked up in fright.

He saw that the cave roof had been ripped away by some unknown magic tool and blinding sunlight shot through, clearly illuminating what was occurring in the cave. A large group of Devil Dao cultivators hovered above the now-exposed cave. They all revealed astonishment once they saw Han Li and the ancient transportation formation shining with yellow light.

“You again?” A furious yell came from the crowd of Devil Dao cultivators. Three people flew out.

The one in the middle wore a silver mask, the Ghost Spirit Sect’s Young Master Wang Chan. Two eccentrics stood beside him: a shriveled, white-haired old man and a young child with red lips and white teeth -- the Li Brothers who previously appeared at Yan Ling Castle.[1]

“Ancient Transportation Formation!” When the Li Brothers saw the origin of yellow radiance, they couldn’t help but look at each other and shout out in pleasant surprise.

Wang Chan stared blankly for a moment. He then asked ecstatically, “Did you see correctly? Is it really an Ancient Transportation Formation?” Wang Chan’s voice trembled slightly. He clearly understood what an intact ancient transportation formation signified for one’s sect.

The shriveled Li Brother chuckled. Just as he thought of saying something, his expression suddenly grew stricken, “Not good! That brat is about to use it. Quickly, stop him!” As he said this, he shot a streak of black light straight toward Han Li.

He knew that once the transportation formation was activated, there would be a moment of delay before it could be used. That delay was more than enough for him to kill any junior several times over.

But just as his magic treasure flew into the cave, a brilliant light erupted, and a rainbow barrier blocked the streak of black light.

The old man was surprised for a moment but immediately recovered. With a sinister expression, he yelled, “Everyone, attack! This brat has laid down a formation spell. We must break through it as quickly as possible or else it will be too late!”

Upon hearing the order from their sect elder, the Devil Dao cultivators promptly released their magic tools as if they had woken up from a dream. Even Wang Chan and the childlike Li Brother struck down upon the spell formation.

Han Li’s Five Elements Reversal Formation was merely a simplified version of the grand formation. Under the attacks of two Core Formation cultivators and a crowd of Foundation Establishment cultivators, the rainbow light barrier immediately distorted and appeared as if it were about to collapse.

At that moment, Han Li had already brought Crooked Soul with him to the center of the formation. With a command medallion in hand and tightly shut eyes, he muttered under his breath, completely ignoring the attacks of the Devil Dao cultivators.

“A Greater Displacement Medallion! That brat actually has such a magic tool?” The old man snarled in a fluster upon clearly seeing the command medallion in Han Li’s hand. He suddenly linked his hands together and a huge amount of black light threads surged, shooting down at the light barrier below.

The formation released several cries before finally reaching its limit and the rainbow light barrier exploded!

Without the strange rainbow light to protect him, the overbearing wave of attacks was about to engulf Han Li.

But at that very moment, Han Li opened his eyes and spouted out one word with an icy tone, “Transfer!”

The yellow light suddenly surged. Within the yellow radiance, Han Li and Crooked Soul disappeared without a trace. The wave of attacks had completely missed their mark.

The Devil Dao cultivators in the sky were left dumbstruck.

The complexions of Wang Chan and the Li Brothers were ashen. Since they didn’t have a Greater Displacement Medallion, they were unable to chase after Han Li.

A moment later, the transportation formation’s yellow light suddenly faded away. Upon seeing this, Wang Chan and his guards grew incomparably furious.

Naturally, they knew that Han Li, the one who had just used this formation, had destroyed the other end. Even if they found a Greater Displacement Medallion, they would be unable to use the formation.

Wang Chan, with bitter resentment still fresh in his heart, was unwilling to give up. Using his status as the sect’s Young Master, he sent for several cultivators to guard the formation day and night for the mere purpose of preventing Han Li from escaping should he repair the formation and return. If that time came, he would make certain to capture Han Li alive and properly repay him for the great kindness of repeatly obstructing his plans.

But shortly afterwards, the Devil Dao would begin the next step of their expansion, and the Ghost Spirit Sect’s Young Master would start to oversee campaigns in other areas. As a result, this matter was quickly dropped to the back of his mind.

As for the cultivation world of the Heavenly South Region, it would remain in turmoil for a long time to come.

In the next two years, an alliance would be formed by the remaining countries to resist the powers of the Devil Dao and Righteous Dao Alliance, known as the “Heavenly Dao Alliance”; this created yet another superpower within the Heavenly South Region.

The three superpowers had near equal strength and campaigned against one another. After a short amount of time, it seemed that they had reached a stalemate.

As for the Six Sects, they eventually arrived at the Nine Nations Union. They contended with the local sects for natural resources such as spirit veins and spirit stone mines, managing to establish a new foothold. Naturally, if the Moulan Tribe’s Spell Soldiers were to invade the nine countries, the six sects would dispatch men to combat them. They no longer possessed the same leisure they had back at the State of Yue.

As a result, many Foundation Establishment cultivators and Core Formation experts perished in battle against the Spell Soldiers. Han Li’s former master, Li Huayuan, was one such example, dying in an intense battle that took place over ten years later.

But in contrast, a new generation of Six Sect cultivators quickly matured. Many Core Formation cultivators eventually rose from the ranks of their Foundation Establishment cultivators...

[1]. The Li Brothers were first introduced in Chapter 254: Yan Clan Ancestor. They are Core Formation cultivators and the Ghost Spirit Sect Young Master's personal bodyguards.

[Back]